<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>INTRO on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/</link>
    <description>Recent content in INTRO on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 11:48:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Regex for Old macOS Models</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/finding-non-macos14-compatible-macs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/finding-non-macos14-compatible-macs/</guid>
      <description>Identifying macOS 10.14 minimum requirements At work, we are a small team serving a large gorup of clients. Because of that, automation is very importnat. It is impossible to get to each client directly, and we constantly have our plates full with other projects, walk-ins and general maintanance.
One project that was recently brought up was detecting and replacing old company-owned Macs that are out of warranty and cannot be upgraded to Apple&amp;rsquo;s newest macOS, which at the time of this writing is macOS Mojavi (10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From LastPass to KeePass</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/lastpass-to-keepass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/lastpass-to-keepass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using LastPass for the last 5 years and been happy with it. I recommended it to friends, family, and co-workers. I tried to sell it through its convenience: once set up, LastPass auto-fills user and password fields, and can even log you into a website directly. LastPass also creates complicated passwords automatically and is available on every major browser, iPhones and Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it seems like even LastPass&amp;rsquo;s time has come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Removing Company Software</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/remove_company_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/remove_company_software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When someone asks what we install on their personal devices (BYOD laptops), I usually give them the abridged version. People rarely care about details. Every now and then though, someone is a bit concerned and asks for more information. Stuff like why do we need software that tells us details about their hardware, how do we use it, and of course, if we can view their personal data. My answer to that last question is &amp;ldquo;we can if we want to.&amp;rdquo; It bothers me this question comes only from so few individuals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFPS Secure Token Active Directory Problems</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/macos-secure-token-trouble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/macos-secure-token-trouble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most chances are, you won&amp;rsquo;t even hear about Secure Token unless you happen to manage Macs for your company. Secure Token seems to be only an issue with Active Directory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hub</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/raspberry_pi_org_hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/raspberry_pi_org_hub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having a consisted, stable server for my org files has been on my mind for a while. I bought a Raspberry PI (RP) to serve as a file server to be used as a &amp;ldquo;hub&amp;rdquo; that will always be on and host these files. This is a description of the setup of what I&amp;rsquo;ve done to make this work. I hope you&amp;rsquo;d find this useful! Feel free to contact me with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Wisdom</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/desktopwisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/techden/desktopwisdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I asked my coworkers the following question:
&amp;ldquo;What is the one truth, in a sentence, you&amp;rsquo;ve learned from being in a help desk position&amp;rdquo;? Here are the answers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>