<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>photography on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/photography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in photography on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/photography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TAONAW&#39;s First Photography Video</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200326/</link>
      <pubDate>27270-03-03</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200326/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are currently three unfinished drafts in TAONAW&amp;rsquo;s main org file&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It seems as if the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portal:Coronavirus%5Fdisease%5F2019&#34;&gt;pandemic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social%5Fdistancing&#34;&gt;social-distancing&lt;/a&gt; dried out my ideas and ability to express myself. On Tuesday I took a walk into the park and captured some flowers and birds with my camera. As it turned out, the walk outdoors recharged my batteries. I came back home and sat down to finally record my first video about photography. Here are the details about how I did it and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TAONAW seeks to use free technologies for content, and broadcasting video is another suck example. I was surprised at how easy it was to set up an account and upload the video to &lt;a href=&#34;https://video.autizmo.xyz&#34;&gt;https://video.autizmo.xyz&lt;/a&gt;, an instant of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PeerTube&#34;&gt;PeerTube&lt;/a&gt;. While YouTube and Instagram are unavoidable to reach photography enthusiasts, I&amp;rsquo;m going to use them only as secondary sources&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve created a channel for &lt;a href=&#34;https://video.autizmo.xyz/video-channels/taonaw/videos&#34;&gt;TAONAW&lt;/a&gt; where I plan to keep uploading photograph-related content. There are additional options and information to add to the channel which I need to revisit. I also need to follow up with a YouTube channel, which will work Like with my content on &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@Josh%5FRollins&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;, presenting older and selective content. Since I&amp;rsquo;m not bothered by making a profit out of the videos, much of YouTube&amp;rsquo;s settings do not make a difference to me and I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave them at default. It&amp;rsquo;s a headache next to the simplicity on PeerTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create the video, I used my &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sony%5F%25CE%25B16000&#34;&gt;Sony a6000&lt;/a&gt;, the camera I&amp;rsquo;ve been using to take my photos since last October, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005KP473Q/ref=ppx%5Fyo%5Fdt%5Fb%5Fsearch%5Fasin%5Ftitle?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34;&gt;AmazonBasics 60-Inch Tripod&lt;/a&gt; which I purchased two months ago. Copying the video to &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191208/&#34;&gt;Hedwig&lt;/a&gt;, my desktop computer, is a breeze thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gwenview&#34;&gt;Gwenview&lt;/a&gt; which comes with KDE. I Then edited the .mts video file with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenShot&#34;&gt;OpenShot&lt;/a&gt;, cutting ambulances&amp;rsquo; sirens (I live next to a hospital)  and added comments in text. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FFmpeg&#34;&gt;FFmpeg&lt;/a&gt; has been a tool of choice for a couple of years, and I used it here to compress and brighten up the video since I underestimated how dark my room is for the camera (learning from mistakes is the only way to learn).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://video.autizmo.xyz/videos/watch/2ecdc35c-ad1d-4bcd-8d92-3df21a117136&#34;&gt;resulting video&lt;/a&gt; is not as bad as I feared, but of course, there&amp;rsquo;s much more to learn. The challenges I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered were not technical: the biggest one turned out to be finding a spot that doesn&amp;rsquo;t show the mess in my room; I ended up arranging my photos on my wall. Another was finding what to say: not &lt;em&gt;lack&lt;/em&gt; of what to say, but how to say it, how to keep to the point. It is very different than writing a blog post and editing it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear comments, suggestions and general questions about the video and the topic itself.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;video.autizmo.xyz/videos/embed/2ecdc35c-ad1d-4bcd-8d92-3df21a117136&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re curious about how my blog is constructed and written with Emacs, look at the About section or read &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/drafting-a-post/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always like to link to Wikipedia articles when possible, but I find myself at awe at the richness of information happening right now when the members of this dedicated community build a whole subsite inside Wikipedia just about COVID-19. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet, please take a look, even if just to see the list of resources and links at the bottom of these articles. So much free and available information. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started my photography journey with Instargram, where I still make connections and followers, but going forward I&amp;rsquo;m planning on giving &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixelfed.social/&#34;&gt;Pixelfed&lt;/a&gt; the main stage. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The joy of Taking Photos</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200201/</link>
      <pubDate>4040-02-02</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200201/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying taking photos since October and decided to start recording videos, expanding the way I publish content. As it turns out, recording, editing, and storing videos is not as simple as I thought. The outcome has been holding back on discussing one of my biggest passions these days. I want to change that today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/my-new-sonya6000/&#34;&gt;discussed my camera&lt;/a&gt; before my trip earlier this year. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve learned more about photography enjoyed seeing my skill improving. Here&amp;rsquo;s one of the first photos I took to demonstrate this:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200201_1.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above image is an experiment in trying to focus on an object with a 16mm lens. I was trying to see if I can get the blurry effect with the stock lenses, and I succeeded, though I basically almost had to have the fruits in the picture touch the lens to get it. The composition in this image was done a few weeks later (it&amp;rsquo;s all about cropping).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the elements of photography as an art form is seeing things that are not really there. It requires creativity I admire in other photos. My own take:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200201_2.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figure of the hand in this photo was almost missed when I was focusing on the water drops after the rain. It captured the mood of the day perfectly: gloom and melancholy. It was taken much more recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often go to a park nearby to relax and enjoy a bit of nature in the midst of the busy city. Animals are a constant sight, and as I improved the flow in my movements and became somewhat less clumsy, I stopped scaring the little ones off. First, there were squirrels:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200201_3.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, as I became more still, birds stopped flying away as I took my time changing my lenses:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200201_4.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both the above cases, I took plenty of photos and selected these two. I find that squirrels are fairly easy to snap. They&amp;rsquo;re not really afraid of humans and can actually be &lt;a href=&#34;https://gothamist.com/news/nyc-park-visitors-warned-about-hangry-squirrels-out-for-blood&#34;&gt;quite intimidating&lt;/a&gt;. Birds, on the other hand, are a different story. They are everywhere, and you have to be perfectly still for a while for them to come closer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot in photography that is both different and similar to the work I do every day. In a way, it&amp;rsquo;s highly technical with much to learn about lighting and composition elements. In another way, it takes me out to explore, often to long walks of several hours, alone with nature and with my thoughts. I have to take my time and slow down on these walks to take good photos and I appreciate many things from different angles as I re-evaluate them in a different light, quite literally. The technical and the art mix in a way that fits well into my current lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The images you see here are all on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/jrss12/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, which is why they have such a bad quality. I do have the larger, high quality versions with me of course and recently started printing some of them to keep around my home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of you may scuff about Instagram. Why use Facebook&amp;rsquo;s commercial platform on a site that stands for free software? The answer is reach, discovery.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixelfed.social/&#34;&gt;Other options&lt;/a&gt; exist, but they are nowhere close with their use-base and have a limitation on how many images can be stored. I do hope to find a better solution as I take more photos and grow in skill and content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re a regular reader of this site!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new Camera Instead of Pixel4</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/my-new-sonya6000/</link>
      <pubDate>8080-11-11</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/my-new-sonya6000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Google was about to officially announce the new Pixel4, I was excited about getting a new phone with an improved camera and enhanced night vision. However, not even a week later, I ended up with a digital camera instead. A few weeks later with my camera, I am happy with my purchase and the new things it brought into my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the important lessons you learn working in IT is not to jump the gun. You always want to stay a generation behind with full maturity and support. When it was time to trade my current Pixel2 for the new Pixel4, my urge to get a new one already took a hit from the cost. The more I waited the more problem surfaced like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/10/google-says-a-fix-for-pixel-4-face-unlock-is-months-away/&#34;&gt;face Unlock issue&lt;/a&gt;, or the not-exactly 90ghz display thing. The list of &amp;ldquo;mehs&amp;rdquo; with the Pixel4 doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem &lt;a href=&#34;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/11/google-pixel-4-review-overpriced-uncompetitive-and-out-of-touch/&#34;&gt;to show signs of slowing down&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holding back on the Pixel4 transformed from excitement to &amp;ldquo;wait, why do I want to give them nearly a grand for?&amp;rdquo; I was &lt;em&gt;pushing&lt;/em&gt; myself toward the Pixel4 despite everything I&amp;rsquo;ve heard, and the reason for that was the camera. I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying my growing photographs collection and the bit of artistic escape I got in my otherwise fully-tech-related life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if all I want is a better camera and to take better photos&amp;hellip; Why not just get a good dedicated camera without an $800 phone attached to it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within minutes I was already watching a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9XDQUpLKpaI&#34;&gt;YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt; about the four different types for digital cameras (by the way, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCjYxkqv3N2p1WwjKvbZykvg&#34;&gt;Dave McKeegan&lt;/a&gt; has a bunch of very well-made explanatory videos about photography). Hours turned to days as I swallowed everything I could from YouTube and photography websites. When I felt I got an idea of what would work best for me (a generic-purpose mirrorless camera) I posted on Reddit and settled on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dpreview.com/search/?query=sony%20a6000&amp;amp;product=sony%5Fa6000&#34;&gt;Sony a6000&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20191128.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My decision was based on a couple of factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted a cheap camera, yet still capable of taking good photos and one that would allow me to continue to learning. Likewise, I wanted a popular camera with a lot of support and tutorials available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted a light compact camera that will be easy to carry around and fit in my backpack so I can easily take it anywhere. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to worry about carrying a heavy bag which will demotivate me from carrying my camera and taking photos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was interested in capturing videos as well, mostly for my vid journals and possibly videos for broadcasting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The a6000 answered all the above. Five years on the market, it is still widely sold, but old enough to be cheaper than its newer replacements (the a6300 and the a6500). It&amp;rsquo;s small and light, easy to cary, and most of all, it teaches me a lot about photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I was about to leave on a vacation to the Bay Area in California, I had a limited number of days ahead of me. To make things more complicated, I friend from work suggested to bring over his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dpreview.com/products/canon/slrs/canon%5Feos7d&#34;&gt;Cannon 7D&lt;/a&gt;. He was considering selling it to me since my sudden enthusiasm in photography surfaced and suggested I take it for a spin, so I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 10-year-old Cannon camera&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; came with a full-size backpack full of lenses of professional-grade which I got to play with over the weekend. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I was doing exactly and I had limited time to try all the goodies, so after a weekend with it I decided to give it back to him and stick to the basics with the a6000. I&amp;rsquo;m happy I did. The Cannon 7D&amp;rsquo;s plathora of professional lenses were way over my budget and my budding skills. The next weekend I was already in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bhphotovideo.com/&#34;&gt;B&amp;amp;H&lt;/a&gt;, and a couple of hours later, I got my a600 with a starter kit and an additional 55-210mm lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three weeks later, I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report I managed to carry the camera with me to work every day. I take photo-walk lunches whenever possible and snapshots of different things I find walking: dogs in dog parks, birdhouses, trees and color-changing leaves, co-workers, myself talking excitedly about photography (an interesting side-affect: I got myself familiar with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openshot.org/&#34;&gt;OpenShot&lt;/a&gt; again as an interesting side-quest). I used to take walks on weekends, but now I do so with the camera and it makes me examine each object from different angles and situations that I didn&amp;rsquo;t do before. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to do something more artistic with my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One difference between cameras and smartphones that I learned early on: there&amp;rsquo;s no huge difference between a 2 year old, a 5 year old and even a 10 year old cameras. I&amp;rsquo;m sure for professional photographers there are some important factors to consider, but at the same time I have a feeling that folks who have been taking photos for years know how to get great photos from old and new cameras. With a phone, you&amp;rsquo;re expect to buy a new one every 2 or 3 years, with cameras, it&amp;rsquo;s more about investing in what you already have. :EXPORT_HUGO_SECTION: Help Desk Head Desk :EXPORT_FILE_NAME: my-new-sonya6000 :EXPORT_HUGO_PUBLISHDATE: 2019-11-08: &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
