<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Help Desk Head Desks on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Help Desk Head Desks on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Submenus in org-mode Capture</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/sub-menus-in-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/sub-menus-in-org/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-in-files/&#34;&gt;In my last post&lt;/a&gt;, I discussed how I (finally) found out that I can use entire org files as capture templates. This is a basic feature that works out of the box, but the org-mode manual doesn&amp;rsquo;t give it enough exposure in my opinion. Turns out it &lt;a href=&#34;https://irreal.org/blog/?p=8161&#34;&gt;wasn&amp;rsquo;t just me&lt;/a&gt; either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was expanding my checklists and learning more &amp;ldquo;trivial&amp;rdquo; org-capture features, I discovered more useful things, but ran out of time to write about them. It&amp;rsquo;s now time to get back to more &amp;ldquo;basics&amp;rdquo; of org-capture again for some helpful tips.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Org-capture in Files</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-in-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-in-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty busy org-mode-ly speaking. There is a lot to say, and as I was writing my post, more ideas occurred to me that behooved me to stop writing and experiment more, which lead to more interesting results, which meant I ran out of time to write about the results. When I finally returned to my post this morning, I realized there&amp;rsquo;s so much to explain, I can&amp;rsquo;t include it all in one go. Here you go, part one of my latest adventure in org-mode: org-capture from org files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Updates: June</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/quick-updates-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/quick-updates-june/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though I don&amp;rsquo;t have any means of tracking how many readers I have on this blog, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel a little bit responsible for my audience. This is an attempt to see how a quick &amp;ldquo;here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s up&amp;rdquo; post while the blog is otherwise idle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, a few quick updates about what&amp;rsquo;s coming up:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Emacs and Chutzpah</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/of-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Says &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jamierubin.net/2019/06/13/writing-in-the-digital-age-an-introduction/#comments&#34;&gt;Jamie T. Rubin&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;As a writer, I naturally want to spend my time writing. More and more I see tools getting in the way of writing. If that wasn’t the case, why do so many tools now add a “focus” or “distraction-free” mode? What choices can I make to simplify my writing ecosystem?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My answer to that, considering the theme of this blog and how I&amp;rsquo;m writing it,  is obvious. But the question is going deeper than that, and so should be the answer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orgzly: An Interview</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/orgzly-neven-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/orgzly-neven-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orgzly.com/&#34;&gt;Orgzly&lt;/a&gt; several times on this blog, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t dedicated a full post to it yet until now. Instead of describing my workflow again or just praising Orgzly&amp;rsquo;s usefulness in a repeated manner, I thought it would be interesting to reach out to its creator and ask a couple of questions instead. To my delight, he was happy to reply! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to present my first interview on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Tools for the job: Flameshot</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/best-tools-flameshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/best-tools-flameshot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every now and then I discover (or re-discover) a tool in Linux that does exactly what I need it to do. Some examples include ffmpeg, to shrink down my self-recorded webcam journal session while increasing the volume; abcde, to rip a classical music CD to flac and find its exact title and name; youtube-dl, which downloads any video online I need along with aria to speed these downloads, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to praise a new excellent tool, this time for screenshots: &lt;a href=&#34;https://flameshot.js.org/#/&#34;&gt;Flameshot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Manjaro</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching-to-manjaro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching-to-manjaro/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux as my daily driver for the last three years. I work with Windows on a daily basis and I support Mac issues all the time, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I will ever go back to using either one for my personal data. As a matter of fact, it&amp;rsquo;s Linux which made an appearance at work: without my VM and Org-mode, I would probably be drowning under hips of emails, meeting invites, support tickets, and the constant in-person walk-ins into our work environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Managing Email in Emacs is not for me</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/mu4e-not-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/mu4e-not-for-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had &lt;a href=&#34;https://irreal.org/blog/?p=8004&#34;&gt;irreal&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/bfsck6/mu4e%5Ffor%5Fdummies/&#34;&gt;mu4e for dummies&lt;/a&gt; on my todo list for a week before I decided to give it up. At first, I thought it was because setting the time and following through the guide was too much of a &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; in my head to tackle, so I broke it down. Then, as I looked at the individual components, I realized it&amp;rsquo;s more complicated then technicalities alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everenote - Behind the Scenes</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/everenote-behind-the-scenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/everenote-behind-the-scenes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years back, I was an avid user of Evernote. That was a period of information &amp;ldquo;innocence&amp;rdquo; for me, before I knew much about Linux and switched careers to IT. Back then, Evernote was an amazing discovery. It was the first serious digital (and, to be honest, analog as well) system I built. I remember many nights where I drifted off to sleep thinking about how to tag and achieve my information in it. To this day I have plenty of memories stored away in its achieve files &amp;ndash; though they have been since downloaded and converted from the App&amp;rsquo;s native format.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Gcal Failed</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/why-gcal-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/why-gcal-failed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently tried &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/myuhe/org-gcal.el&#34;&gt;Org-Gcal&lt;/a&gt; a second time just to turn it off again. I was following the (now slightly outdated) &lt;a href=&#34;https://cestlaz.github.io/posts/using-emacs-26-gcal/&#34;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://cestlaz.github.io/&#34;&gt;Mike Zamansky&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; blog and managed to get it working this time, but I found the end result messy and cumbersome. This is mostly because of how I use org and my agenda to quickly get a view of what I need, not really a reflection on the tool itself. It made me understand how different the methodology of Google calendar and Org-mode are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading my Audio Game</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/upgrading-audio-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/upgrading-audio-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few months of research, I finally upgraded my Audio system on my PC. As it turns out, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as expensive as I feared. The renewed interest in music took me in rewarding directions of sound exploration I did not anticipate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elite Dangerous: Beginning</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/elite-dangerous-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/elite-dangerous-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;17:42. Almost time to go home. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to hold on a bit longer, to tell myself I should around more before I buy it. Elite is complex, with a steep learning and no real objectives in sight. I was worried it&amp;rsquo;ll be more work after work. So of course, I bought it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Password Managers Hacks</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/password-manager-hacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/password-manager-hacking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;News that surfaced last week report of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.securityevaluators.com/casestudies/password-manager-hacking/&#34;&gt;security flaw&lt;/a&gt; that exists in the most popular password managers out there like LastPass, KeePass, and 1Password among others. Does this mean people should stop using them? No. Will people use this news as yet another excuse not to use password managers? Sure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Regex for Old macOS Models</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/finding-non-macos14-compatible-macs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/finding-non-macos14-compatible-macs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At work, we are a small team serving a very large gorup of clients. Because of that, automation is very importnat. It is impossible to get to each client directly, and we constantly have our plates full with other projects, walk-ins and general maintanance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One project that was recently brought up was detecting and replacing old company-owned Macs that are out of warranty and cannot be upgraded to Apple&amp;rsquo;s newest macOS, which at the time of this writing is &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/macos-mojave/id1398502828&#34;&gt;macOS Mojavi (10.14)&lt;/a&gt;. the idea is to locate these machines and retire them. To do such projects, we use system managment tool, KACE. KACE used to belong to Dell, and is still mostly used for Windows machines (it is most usefuls on Dells, obviously) but in this line of work it&amp;rsquo;s many times using the tools you already have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From LastPass to KeePass</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/lastpass-to-keepass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/lastpass-to-keepass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using LastPass for the last 5 years and been happy with it. I recommended it to friends, family, and co-workers. I tried to sell it through its convenience: once set up, LastPass auto-fills user and password fields, and can even log you into a website directly. LastPass also creates complicated passwords automatically and is available on every major browser, iPhones and Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it seems like even LastPass&amp;rsquo;s time has come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Org Capture Templates - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-template-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-template-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took a long unplanned break from writing about my Templates because of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/blogging/css-updates-1/&#34;&gt;CSS changes&lt;/a&gt; I worked on and the complications with Magit. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say these are now behind me, and that I gained another grain of confidence using Magit and knowing git, but this is a post for yet another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the last two templates are rather short, I&amp;rsquo;m putting them both here together. Here we go:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Updates</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/css-updates-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/css-updates-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About some CSS Updates&amp;hellip; and why I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted in the last two weeks or so. (Changes are now complete!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Subnautica and Fear</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/subnautica-and-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/subnautica-and-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/subnautica_jrss.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple is a Hardware Second Company</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/apple-hardware-second/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/apple-hardware-second/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to look hard to find the holes in this Emperor&amp;rsquo;s clothes. Apple has been heading downhill for a couple of years, but it&amp;rsquo;s only recently that the public at large started to take notice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Write Posts for my Blog</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/drafting-a-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/drafting-a-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though it doesn&amp;rsquo;t show on this blog (yet), I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging since I got into college, more than a decade ago. Blogging is an activity that combines a couple of passions for me: writing, technology. and visual creativity. My process hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed much over the years, and the tools I taught myself to use help me maintaining my routine. This is a quick explanation of its main components.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Write Posts for my Blog</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/drafting_a_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/drafting_a_post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though it doesn&amp;rsquo;t show on this blog (yet), I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging since I got into college, more than a decade ago. Blogging is an activity that combines a couple of passions for me: writing, technology. and visual creativity. My process hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed much over the years, and the tools I taught myself to use help me maintaining my routine. This is a quick explanation of its main components.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Removing Company Software</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/remove-company-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/remove-company-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When someone asks what we install on their personal devices (BYOD laptops), I usually give them the abridged version. People rarely care about details. Every now and then though, someone is a bit concerned and asks for more information. Stuff like why do we need software that tells us details about their hardware, how do we use it, and of course, if we can view their personal data. My answer to that last question is &amp;ldquo;we can if we want to.&amp;rdquo; It bothers me this question comes only from so few individuals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Removing Company Software</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/remove_company_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/remove_company_software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When someone asks what we install on their personal devices (BYOD laptops), I usually give them the abridged version. People rarely care about details. Every now and then though, someone is a bit concerned and asks for more information. Stuff like why do we need software that tells us details about their hardware, how do we use it, and of course, if we can view their personal data. My answer to that last question is &amp;ldquo;we can if we want to.&amp;rdquo; It bothers me this question comes only from so few individuals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Hugo - Full Time</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PayPal informed me that the host of my WordPress blog is charging me for another $80 or so for the next year. The very next day, tumblr &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/231885248-Sensitive-content&#34;&gt;decided to shoot itself in the head&lt;/a&gt; (rather than the leg, if you ask me). It was good to be reminded to not trust cloud services for creative content - like my blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Hugo - Full Time</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching_2_hugo_ft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching_2_hugo_ft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PayPal informed me that the host of my WordPress blog is charging me for another $80 or so for the next year. The very next day, tumblr &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/231885248-Sensitive-content&#34;&gt;decided to shoot itself in the head&lt;/a&gt; (rather than the leg, if you ask me). It was good to be reminded to not trust cloud services for creative content - like my blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFPS Secure Token Active Directory Problems</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/macos-secure-token-trouble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/macos-secure-token-trouble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most chances are, you won&amp;rsquo;t even hear about Secure Token unless you happen to manage Macs for your company. Secure Token seems to be only an issue with Active Directory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFPS Secure Token Active Directory Problems</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/macos-secure-token-trouble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/macos-secure-token-trouble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most chances are, you won&amp;rsquo;t even hear about Secure Token unless you happen to manage Macs for your company. Secure Token seems to be only an issue with Active Directory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hub</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/raspberry-pi-org-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/raspberry-pi-org-hub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having a consisted, stable server for my org files has been on my mind for a while. I bought a Raspberry PI (RP) to serve as a file server to be used as a &amp;ldquo;hub&amp;rdquo; that will always be on and host these files. This is a description of the setup of what I&amp;rsquo;ve done to make this work. I hope you&amp;rsquo;d find this useful! Feel free to contact me with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hub</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/raspberry_pi_org_hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/raspberry_pi_org_hub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having a consisted, stable server for my org files has been on my mind for a while. I bought a Raspberry PI (RP) to serve as a file server to be used as a &amp;ldquo;hub&amp;rdquo; that will always be on and host these files. This is a description of the setup of what I&amp;rsquo;ve done to make this work. I hope you&amp;rsquo;d find this useful! Feel free to contact me with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Wisdom</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/desktopwisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/desktopwisdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I asked my coworkers the following question:
 &amp;ldquo;What is the one truth, in a sentence, you&amp;rsquo;ve learned from being in a help desk position&amp;rdquo;? Here are the answers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Wisdom</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/desktop-wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/desktop-wisdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I asked my coworkers the following question:
 &amp;ldquo;What is the one truth, in a sentence, you&amp;rsquo;ve learned from being in a help desk position&amp;rdquo;? Here are the answers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolvement of Video Journal &amp; Org</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/video-journal-evolved/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/video-journal-evolved/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over time, my videos definitely got smaller. This is because I got used to Org in different areas of recording my thoughts. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://jarss.github.io/TAONAW/blog/org-update/&#34;&gt;discussed these&lt;/a&gt; couple of times before: tasks, task notes, and journal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Windows</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/emacs-windows-managment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/emacs-windows-managment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In his 5th Emacs podcast, &lt;a href=&#34;https://emacscast.org/episode%5F5/&#34;&gt;Rakhim&lt;/a&gt; discusses the difficulties of windows management in Emacs. I agree with him. Emacs&amp;rsquo; Windows are a pain. It was probably one of the longest pet peeves I had with the program, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until this podcast that I realized that I&amp;rsquo;m much better off than I used to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - what takes so long?</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/hugo-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/hugo-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve bseen following me online for the last month or so (especially on reddit) you&amp;rsquo;d know I&amp;rsquo;ve been engaged in shifting away from WordPress and into the world &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - what takes so long?</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/hugo-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/hugo-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve bseen following me online for the last month or so (especially on reddit) you&amp;rsquo;d know I&amp;rsquo;ve been engaged in shifting away from WordPress and into the world &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agenda, and the Benfit of Having Multiple Files</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/agenda-multiple-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/agenda-multiple-files/</guid>
      <description>I used to write all my tasks, personal and work, into one tasks.org file.
On Sunday night, this was good. I had 5 tasks on my list, and I was ready to start my work week. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t take long (two days actually) for tasks.org to become monster.org. It didn&amp;rsquo;t happen because of the number of tasks, which I kept (more or less) under control. It happened because of the size of the projects I was working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libre and Clothes</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/libre-and-clothes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/libre-and-clothes/</guid>
      <description>When I write, I live in Emacs (with the awesome Solorized theme) inside Org-Mode.
With time, I found that Org has already made me more effienet writer and note taker. I write notes in every meeting now, rather it&amp;rsquo;s my &amp;ldquo;turn&amp;rdquo; or not. I write notes as I work, about every solution and every problem I&amp;rsquo;m facing. I write first thing in the morning, usually about org-related thoughts I had as I wake up, over a cup of Sumatra cofee (little almond milk, one pack of sugar).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>