<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hugo on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hugo on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Updates: 2019-10</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/blog-updates-2/</link>
      <pubDate>12120-10-10</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/blog-updates-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been fairly active with the website this month, but most of the changes are behind the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tags-to-topics&#34;&gt;Tags to Topics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;tags&amp;rdquo; title changed to &amp;ldquo;Popular Topics&amp;rdquo;. This list now displays any topics that have been featured at least 3 times on TAONAW from the highest to lowest. A new &amp;ldquo;All Topics&amp;rdquo; link at the bottom leads to the tag page (which I need to change to &amp;ldquo;topics&amp;rdquo; now - work in progress) to view all the other topics, sorted by latest addition. I am planning to add an introduction the page later on, inspired a bit by &lt;a href=&#34;https://karl-voit.at/&#34;&gt;Karl Voit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Sections&amp;rdquo; portion of the sidebar &lt;del&gt;will be&lt;/del&gt;  was eliminated. More personal posts are now tagged as &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/life/&#34;&gt;life&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;. As a preparation to go sections-less, the tags were cleaned and condensed to reflect broader topics. Popular topics that emerge will receive their own  tags as they become more popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmetics&#34;&gt;Cosmetics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sidebar &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jarss/TAONAW/blob/master/static/css/hyde.css&#34;&gt;is now 14rem wide&lt;/a&gt; to contain the &amp;ldquo;Popular Topics&amp;rdquo; heading without a break. This caused the words &amp;ldquo;Art Of&amp;rdquo; in the red title at the sidebar to come together, something I &lt;del&gt;intend to&lt;/del&gt; changed. I learned that it&amp;rsquo;s probably smarted to increase the spaces between words in the title using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3schools.com/cssref/pr%5Ftext%5Fword-spacing.asp&#34;&gt;word-spacing&lt;/a&gt; CSS property instead of changing the width of the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post titles have a new font, &lt;a href=&#34;https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Montserrat&#34;&gt;Montserrat&lt;/a&gt;. If you don&amp;rsquo;t see this font, please let me know. This change was implemented previously, but later deleted by mistake in the CSS file. This is a Google Font that is enabled for free using the head_fonts.html in Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colors for the tags under the titles and the &amp;ldquo;Read More&amp;rdquo; links on the main page were changed to the same red as the Title&amp;rsquo;s red. Other links in the posts and remain the same&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixing-the-homepage&#34;&gt;Fixing the Homepage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My homepage, which displays a list of summaries of posts, broke after a recent Hugo update. That was because of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/news/0.58.0-relnotes/&#34;&gt;specific Hugo change in version .58&lt;/a&gt;.  This was fixed after a day of diving into Hugo, something I should probably do more often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;trimming-down-the-fat&#34;&gt;Trimming Down the fat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, there are a lot of unused files inside the builds of this website. For example, when I changed my tagging and got rid of the old tags, it turned out the old tags still have HTML files inside the site. The original theme I used to build this site is still stored intact inside the theme folders, &lt;del&gt;and I don&amp;rsquo;t really need it&lt;/del&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. There are other examples, probably one of the known side effects of having a static website that builds HTML webpages for everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearing the old files is tricky, and I ended up deleting files I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I need until I tried to publish the site again. Not a big problem since everything is backed up many times over, but something I can live without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;netifly-coming-soon&#34;&gt;Netifly - Coming Soon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Kaushal Modi, my Hugo mentor &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.technology/@kaushalmodi/102949264377765642&#34;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt;, the answer to all these annoyances is Netifly. I knew about this service previously, but this time because of a specific issue&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I had with git, I learned that Netifly bypasses the entire build Hugo creates. That is, it reads the md files directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the md files are created on the fly for me thanks to ox-hugo, it&amp;rsquo;s almost as if I have a dynamic website. I would still need to push the changes to github, but Netifly would take care of everything from there. No more old dead HTML files or forgetting to build my website before pushing to github - something I do more often than I&amp;rsquo;d like to, for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting a website to build on Netifly is pretty easy, but I&amp;rsquo;ll need to change the DNS records to point to Netifly&amp;rsquo;s servers instead of github. That&amp;rsquo;s not a hard thing to do, but there&amp;rsquo;s a chance something would break and my website will be down, and I&amp;rsquo;m running out of time as I&amp;rsquo;m writing this. I will wait on Netifly a bit longer, but this is a change that is pretty sure to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-section&#34;&gt;About Section&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve added an &lt;a href=&#34;http://joshrollinswrites.com/about/&#34;&gt;about section&lt;/a&gt; to the blog. Creating a section that uses the posts&amp;rsquo; template was a learning experience since Hugo&amp;rsquo;s default is to treat all sections&amp;rsquo; main pages (index.html pages) as a &amp;ldquo;list&amp;rdquo; template. To resolve this, I needed to use &lt;code&gt;layout: &amp;quot;single&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/front-matter/&#34;&gt;front-matter&lt;/a&gt; for the index page. In ox-hugo, this is done by adding a ~ &lt;code&gt;:EXPORT_HUGO_LAYOUT: single&lt;/code&gt; property under the header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure how to fit the link to the about section in the sidebar. For now, it&amp;rsquo;s just a linked from my name in the site&amp;rsquo;s description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was harder than it should have been&amp;hellip; these links are nested inside a class which is also nested inside a class. The right syntax in CSS is &lt;code&gt;[parent-class] [child-class] [html-tag]&lt;/code&gt; with spacing being important: three spaces, no more. However, because my CSS was messy, the rules I&amp;rsquo;ve added were re-defined again later in the CSS file; I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware I called the same elements in two different places. As it turns out, cleaning your code (CSS, bash, or whatever) is important - and so as adding comments. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I tried to publish the site to Netifly (see below) it turned out I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; need the original theme of the site. I am unsure why at this point, since all the essential files I use are stored outside of the theme&amp;rsquo;s folder. I believe this has to do with the site&amp;rsquo;s theme setting which specifies the theme&amp;rsquo;s name, which probably points to that folder. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I included the word &amp;ldquo;hugo&amp;rdquo; in my git ignore file. This was because I used to store a hugo binary in the site&amp;rsquo;s root folder, because a newer version was not available on Linux Mint, at the time. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Hugo - Full Time</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>5050-12-12</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PayPal informed me that the host of my WordPress blog is charging me for another $80 or so for the next year. The very next day, tumblr &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/231885248-Sensitive-content&#34;&gt;decided to shoot itself in the head&lt;/a&gt; (rather than the leg, if you ask me). It was good to be reminded to not trust cloud services for creative content - like my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-issues-with-my-host&#34;&gt;The Issues With my Host&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current host sucks. My WordPress blog continuously goes offline, so much so that I had to mute the alerts I got because they overwhelmed my inbox. My connection issues never got resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another major issue with that website was the lack of https (this is not my host fault, actually, it&amp;rsquo;s just yet another thing you need to buy) and the constant spam I got on the website. People would go to my link and find a totally different website trying to sell them something. That issue was not resolved either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were other technical issues, from WordPress not functioning right due to database corruptions (the host had an automatic set up process), to my domain not being resolved correctly. In the past, such issues would die out in the first month or two when I switch to a new host &amp;ndash; but not this time. This time, as soon as I got the notification of renewal from PayPal, I immediately asked for cancellation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-work-to-be-done&#34;&gt;More Work to be Done&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more work to do on this website. I am still not happy with it, and I believe my WordPress blog overall looked better still. But it is up to me to make this place better with my own set of growing skills. CSS, ox-Hugo, Go, and of course, the quality (and quantity) what I write matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also not entirely happy with the blog hosted on GitHub, which is now owned by Microsoft. It&amp;rsquo;s no difference than Tumblr being bought out by Yahoo. I need to move to an actual host with a more liberal point of view about sexual content. Unfortunately, in this world of ours, this means I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a host that is OK with Pornography. They have to include everything in one blanket statement so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to sort out in courts, in case someone gets offended. But I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go down that hole right now, there&amp;rsquo;s a whole lot of it, more than enough, on the internet right now with people freaking out about Tumblr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s the solution&amp;hellip;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe AWS (Amazon hosting service) might be it for now. I find it hard to believe they&amp;rsquo;d bother chasing me if I mention a sexual encounter or show a picture of a breast. Still, even AWS is not a safe haven. Hmmm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - what takes so long?</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/hugo-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>4040-10-10</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/hugo-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve bseen following me online for the last month or so (especially on reddit) you&amp;rsquo;d know I&amp;rsquo;ve been engaged in shifting away from WordPress and into the world &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d imagine the people of in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/&#34;&gt;r/emacs&lt;/a&gt; would raise an eyebrow at the term &amp;ldquo;world of Hugo.&amp;rdquo; After all, Hugo is a relatively simple program, not a deep rabbit-hole like Emacs. Yet, it&amp;rsquo;s Hugo that got me overwhelemed, not so much Emacs. What? Really?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, it has to do with background and expectations. As a non-programmer (as in, someone who never wrote anything a bit more complicated then a few lines of shell script) Emacs was a mountain. Standing at the bottom, I gazed at the cloud shrowing its peek and told myself &amp;ldquo;well, you gotta take a first step somewhere&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; so I did. For me, that was Org-mode. As a matter of fact, at the time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know much about Emacs and how deep it can get. All I knew was that Org was cool, and I&amp;rsquo;m interested in learning more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple of months, I got a bit more comfortable with Emacs and my level of doing things with it. I am still miles away from the top, and I&amp;rsquo;m fine with that. I got Emacs to do most of what I want it to do for me at this point, which is writing these posts, my journal entries, and of course my agenda and tasks both at work and at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo, on the other hand, was meant to replace WordPress. As a person who used WordPress on and off a couple of years, I expected more or less the same thing. You know, going to my webiste online somewhere, log in with a username and password, navigate the GUI and post stuff, add plugins&amp;hellip; As such, I didn&amp;rsquo;t care for a change that much. WordPress was working more or less OK, so why change to something similar and learn things all over again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get frequent alerts that my website is down from my webhost, but I got used to shrug these off. I got it as a cheap deal, and for about $6 a month or so hosting, what do you expect? People in the Emacs reddit mentioned they see more spam from my site&amp;rsquo;s URL instead of my posts, but again, with 1 person complaining out of 10 or so, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a big deal. After all, SSL and https is for professional website that can afford it, and I am just an amatuer-ish blogger. Perhaps the biggest hurdle was Github: I knew people who use Hugo usually use Github to publish their blog, but they were all programmers. Me, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about Github or git. That was for coders, people who write scripts for a living. This is not me. I am not a porgrammer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what changed that perspective. Perhaps it was a random tutorial I saw about Git which made me realize it&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; crazy complicated. Perhaps it was the fact that someone advised me not to link to my website again if I don&amp;rsquo;t have https. Maybe it was just my inner geek, itching for a change, and WordPress was getting too familiar and too boring. Whatever it was, I took the bait, and I started doing all of it at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I watched some Lynda videos about git and read a few posts. Then, I learned more about Hugo. After that, it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/&#34;&gt;ox-hugo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lsquo;s turn (because I gotta write my posts from inside Emacs), and then it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://magit.vc/&#34;&gt;Magit&lt;/a&gt; (because I gotta use git from inside Emacs). I think I went through everything in a matter of about a month. I learned too much too fast. But that&amp;rsquo;s how I roll. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I do that to myself, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how it makes sense to go from &amp;ldquo;git is for coders&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;ALL THE THINGS,&amp;rdquo; but I do anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this attitude has terrible consequences. You learn everything on a very shallow level, which means the first tiny bump in the road sends you launching out of control. You get frustrated and you try again, just to hit another bump. Turns out, if I &lt;em&gt;learn everything&lt;/em&gt; I also expect to &lt;em&gt;know everything&lt;/em&gt; out of myself, which is of course nonsense. But not everything is futile. Knowing the big picture in advance is not a bad idea. Learning a couple of things at once make you realize how they work together, and helps you develop a mindset that is more skilled at solving specific problems. Later, when you go look at the official documents, certain things already make sense to you even though you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen them before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be it as it may, it&amp;rsquo;s not easy. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend this method to anyone. it&amp;rsquo;s doing damage control instead of learning. However, manuals never made sese to me. In the rare occessions where I do have the patience to read through the introduction, I&amp;rsquo;d forget what I wanted to do (or how to do it) by the time I get the real stuff. Besides, manuals are usually written by the people who made the program; as such, they are written from the inside, for insiders. Certain terms and syntax make aboslutely no sense to newcomers, who find that they struggle with basic terms that the veterans spit out as if they were born into it. Indeed, if there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that I kept running into when learning Emacs is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to bother with its documentation. As helpful as it is, and as much as everyone loves to say all the help you ever want is C-h v (or a or whatever) away, it was not true for me. It is much, much easier to Google something up and find a blog post (or a YouTube video) that explains it to you in plain English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m much further ahead than where I was when I started my Hugo ordeal. I have sucessfully launched a couple of testing websites on and off Github. I have whined, complained, and whined again to anyone who would listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here we are with Hugo. I use git, and well, the site is on Github. This post was written with ox-hugo. I used Magit, but because there are so many issues I&amp;rsquo;m running into, I decided to make a decision not to use it for at least another month. It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to hold myself back, for sure. On one hand, since I&amp;rsquo;ve done WordPress for so long, I&amp;rsquo;m aching to go back to my old website where I don&amp;rsquo;t have problems learning how to create a new static page (that doesn&amp;rsquo;t show on the front page of this blog), or how exactly images work with these posts, or how can I automate the long process of saving a post and updating my Hugo website compared to the simple &amp;ldquo;click to publish&amp;rdquo;  in WordPress. I&amp;rsquo;m sure some of you are aching to tell me just how to do some of these things. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and speaking of helpful people: a big thank you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kaushalmodi&#34;&gt;Kaushal Modi&lt;/a&gt;, who kept answering my endless questions, who was there through my frustration, anywhere I went. This guy is passionate and compassionate about what he does.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
