<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tools on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tools on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Tools for the job: Duplicati</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200212/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I&#39;ve kept postponing since &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191208/&#34;&gt;switching to Linux on my desktop&lt;/a&gt; has been my backup system. I wrote a script on my raspberry pi to create an encrypted tar achieves of my org files twice a day transfer them over to Hedwig (my desktop), which will then find their way into an online backup provider. Now that I switched to Linux, that system stopped working, and I&#39;ve kept postponing the critical need for an online backup too long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools in Windows</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/windows-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/windows-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.tube/videos/watch/697084c3-6e9b-435c-b5e2-7647a9d9c30f&#34;&gt;first public video&lt;/a&gt; introduced me to new challanges I didn&#39;t face until now. Case in point: displaying milliseconds in VLC. I looked online in various places for a solution with my tools of choice, VLC player and ffmpeg. Workarounds do exist, but not nearly as simple as what exists for me in Windows. This happened to me before. As I was starting to get stuck, I realized that sometimes it&#39;s ok not to wrack my head over every single hurdle. This is a reminder for myself, and hopefully save you some time to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orgzly: An Interview</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/orgzly-neven-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/orgzly-neven-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orgzly.com/&#34;&gt;Orgzly&lt;/a&gt; several times on this blog, but I haven&#39;t dedicated a full post to it yet until now. Instead of describing my workflow again or just praising Orgzly&#39;s usefulness in a repeated manner, I thought it would be interesting to reach out to its creator and ask a couple of questions instead. To my delight, he was happy to reply! I&#39;m happy to present my first interview on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Tools for the job: Flameshot</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/best-tools-flameshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/best-tools-flameshot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every now and then I discover (or re-discover) a tool in Linux that does exactly what I need it to do. Some examples include ffmpeg, to shrink down my self-recorded webcam journal session while increasing the volume; abcde, to rip a classical music CD to flac and find its exact title and name; youtube-dl, which downloads any video online I need along with aria to speed these downloads, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I want to praise a new excellent tool, this time for screenshots: &lt;a href=&#34;https://flameshot.js.org/#/&#34;&gt;Flameshot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everenote - Behind the Scenes</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/everenote-behind-the-scenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/everenote-behind-the-scenes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years back, I was an avid user of Evernote. That was a period of information &amp;ldquo;innocence&amp;rdquo; for me, before I knew much about Linux and switched careers to IT. Back then, Evernote was an amazing discovery. It was the first serious digital (and, to be honest, analog as well) system I built. I remember many nights where I drifted off to sleep thinking about how to tag and achieve my information in it. To this day I have plenty of memories stored away in its achieve files &amp;ndash; though they have been since downloaded and converted from the App&#39;s native format.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>