<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tools on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tools on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Elfeed to View Videos</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200611/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200611/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things that makes Emacs stand out is its modes (or &amp;ldquo;plug ins,&amp;rdquo; for those who haven&amp;rsquo;t used Emacs before). The nature of Emacs being open source means that every mode is born out of a need. Nothing is &amp;ldquo;fluff.&amp;rdquo; Every good mode has a good reason to exist. The more people who have the same need, the more customized and refined the mode becomes. Indeed, some of these modes are more supirior than complete softwre packages, which often costs money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk about Elfeed, one of these tools. Elfeed is better than any other RSS feed readers I&amp;rsquo;ve seen. The gif below will show you why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/elfed-view-vids.gif&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-so-good-about-elfeed&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s so Good about Elfeed?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of you who are familiar with Emacs and/or Elfeed would probably want to skip this section entirely and go below to my specific tweak. However, if you&amp;rsquo;re thinking of using Elfeed and wonder what&amp;rsquo;s so good about a mere RSS reader, read on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, A quick explination for those of you who&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with Elfeed or Emacs. What you see is a sum of three things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I open a Window with my RSS feeds, and filter specfically for YouTube channels that were updated in the last week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once I locate the feed I want to watch, I browse down to it and hit &amp;ldquo;v&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A local media player opens and shows me my feed completely free from any YouTube ads or other attention-grabbers I&amp;rsquo;d find using a full browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wait, are we still talking about an &lt;em&gt;RSS&lt;/em&gt; feed? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this means we&amp;rsquo;re discussing a geeky way of reading &lt;em&gt;text&lt;/em&gt; articles from blogs and such?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s exactly where my earlier point comes in. Elfeed is not an &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; an RSS feed reader, No. It&amp;rsquo;s an answer to a specific need, or a solution to a problem that exists. What is the problem then? To &lt;a href=&#34;https://nullprogram.com/blog/2013/06/13/&#34;&gt;quote its creator&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unlike many other feed readers, Elfeed is oriented around entries — the Atom term for articles — rather than feeds. It cares less about where entries came from and more about listing relevant entries for reading.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the issue Elfeed&amp;rsquo;s trying to fix, I suggest reading some of &lt;a href=&#34;https://irreal.org/blog/?s=elfeed&#34;&gt;Irreal&amp;rsquo;s articles about it&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://noonker.github.io/posts/2020-04-22-elfeed/&#34;&gt;the post that inspired me to give it a try again&lt;/a&gt;. I had the pleasure of talking to the author of that blog, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/noonker&#34;&gt;Noonker&lt;/a&gt;, directly. He had this to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I consider many modern websites to be abusive and manipulative. They&amp;rsquo;re engineered in such a way to maximize ad dollars by keeping you engaged. They&amp;rsquo;re not designed for people. I really try to minimize my time on these sites and elfeed does a lot to keep me a separated from the manipulative aspects of these sites.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly what Elfeed is good for. This, I&amp;rsquo;d argue, is also what Elfeed excels at doing better than any other RSS feeder out there. That&amp;rsquo;s because it&amp;rsquo;s inside my productivity environment already (Emacs). Its filters, customized to give me the exact update I need, are a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html%5Fnode/emacs/Bookmarks.html&#34;&gt;bookmark&lt;/a&gt; away in Emacs (&lt;code&gt;C-x C-r l&lt;/code&gt;) away. These means that the updates I care about are only 5 keystrokes away, burned into memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Case in point: during these times of COVID19, I used Elfeed to watch Governor Cuomo&amp;rsquo;s (I live in NYC) video feeds without opening my browser and without going to YouTube. Not only Elfeed helped me staying away from YouTube&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Oh! Watch this also!&amp;rdquo; algorithms and ads, it also made sure this brifing was on my daily news dose, along with the NYC section of the New York Times and new org-mode posts on Reddit&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-specific-youtube-viewing-fucntion&#34;&gt;The Specific YouTube Viewing Fucntion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noonker generesouly provides his YouTube download function in the post (&lt;a href=&#34;https://noonker.github.io/posts/2020-04-22-elfeed/&#34;&gt;here it is again&lt;/a&gt;). I took the function and manipulated it, after watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://cestlaz.github.io/post/using-emacs-72-customizing-elfeed/&#34;&gt;Mike Zamansky&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; helpful &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/G1NGNR40lB4&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nil&#34; data-lang=&#34;nil&#34;&gt;(require &#39;elfeed)

(defun elfeed-v-mpv (url)
  &amp;quot;Watch a video from URL in MPV&amp;quot;
  (async-shell-command (format &amp;quot;mpv %s&amp;quot; url)))

(defun elfeed-view-mpv (&amp;amp;optional use-generic-p)
  &amp;quot;Youtube-feed link&amp;quot;
  (interactive &amp;quot;P&amp;quot;)
  (let ((entries (elfeed-search-selected)))
    (cl-loop for entry in entries
	     do (elfeed-untag entry &#39;unread)
	     when (elfeed-entry-link entry)
	     do (elfeed-v-mpv it))
    (mapc #&#39;elfeed-search-update-entry entries)
    (unless (use-region-p) (forward-line))))

(define-key elfeed-search-mode-map (kbd &amp;quot;v&amp;quot;) &#39;elfeed-view-mpv)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was just comfortable enough to manipulate the code a bit after doing some reading on Elisp, but I can&amp;rsquo;t quite explain it fully yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that there are two functions at play: one that grabs the URL from the feed and store it into a symbol (Elisp spin on what would be a variable in other languages. Well, kind of). It also assigns the shortcut key &amp;ldquo;v&amp;rdquo; to view videos, which will work only in Elfeed (so v is free to be used for something else elsewhere).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand better the why and hows, I suggest viewing the video mentioned as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important part for this function to me is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mpv-player/mpv&#34;&gt;MPV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, which immidetly beats ,VLC in minimalizim. I used Plasma&amp;rsquo;s powerful Window manager to have MPV run without a window frame at all, giving it a quick &amp;ldquo;just the vid please, thanks&amp;rdquo; interface which further enhanches what I wanted to get from the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s more to Elfeed&amp;rsquo;s RSS reading philosophy here. Finding relevant RSS feeds is not as simple as going to a big media site and copy down their main RSS feed. This means I&amp;rsquo;d get every single article, which takes me away from staying on point. RSS feed hunting, as it turns out, is an art form in itself. Not all major website support it fully, and it can be challenging to find (or create) what you need. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a week of using MPV, I uninstalled VNC. VNC is OK, but once you try MPV, you stay with it. It is lean and doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the bloatness of VNC, which can do &lt;em&gt;so many things&lt;/em&gt; that I just don&amp;rsquo;t need it to do. It works without controls (they come up as you hover over the screen) and encourages you to use keyboard keys to skip, control the volume, etc. It probably deserves a post on its own. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Software</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200428/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200428/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What do Emacs, SSH, FTP, IRC and ffmpeg have in common?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; programs&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that stood the test of time and are still in active usage today. Yes, ffmpeg is maybe not as &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; as Emacs, with its base back in the 1970, and you could argue IRC is barely used next to the giants of social media today, but that doesn’t mean they&amp;rsquo;re not usable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, not only usable, but often better off than modern software that gravitates more and more toward the cloud. My argument here is not that these old tools should replace the existing popular gaints of today and tomororw. Actually, the fact that they &lt;em&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt;, the fact that they are &amp;ldquo;frozen&amp;rdquo; in time and only work for geeks, is a big part of the benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet%5FRelay%5FChat&#34;&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, or internet relay chat. Using IRC requires some know-how of commands like &lt;code&gt;/join&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;/nick&lt;/code&gt; and even &lt;code&gt;/whois&lt;/code&gt; that today&amp;rsquo;s users would know nothing about. Modern application such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.com/help/articles/201259356-Use-built-in-slash-commands&#34;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; and the like have similar commands, but these are artificial like plastic plants: a head nod to the past with often the same functionality a mouse click can achieve in GUI. Most users without technical background won&amp;rsquo;t even know these. IRC does not have a CEO behind it; it does not have a single software which is at the mercy of patches and version numbers; it does not have to abide to the whims of its shareholders and change its TOS every couple of months to another confusing legal document no one reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could pick up a Linux administration book from 2007, and most of it will still be true today. Administrators, or those who think like admins, tend to prefer the proven and stable, not the new-and-flashy. The level of granular control, the options, the out-of-the box availability, the lack of storage space that is required, and of course the no payment associated, add to the stability and familiarity to a package that is hard to defeat. I could use 3 different Linux distros, a Mac and a Windows PC, and I will still trust ffmpeg to work on my video compression and editing more than I would any Adobe product. It&amp;rsquo;s just that there are far better solutions that I found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could argue it&amp;rsquo;s all a matter of taste, and I&amp;rsquo;d say sure, everything is. I find comfort in the terminal, in typing in commands which show me what I&amp;rsquo;m about to do, and how. I know that I could type in the same command 5 years from now, even 50, and expect the same thing to happen - if the machine these programs reside in is alive. In turn, this attitude pushes me to learn more of how things work. At first, a regular user might not understand why I spend 2 hours learning how to script something that takes them 3 clicks to accomplish; but later, when the GUI clicking needs to be repeated for 50 or a 100 items, or when they need a new setup which comes with a new workflow, they&amp;rsquo;d understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;: Technically, IRC, ssh and ftp are procols, not software; but the idea I&amp;rsquo;m driving at is age, stability and usage. ffmpeg is a collection of software and Emacs &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a software (in a way, perhaps a collection of packages in itself as well), and the same point can be applied to both of these as well. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Tools for the job: Duplicati</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200212/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve kept postponing since &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191208/&#34;&gt;switching to Linux on my desktop&lt;/a&gt; has been my backup system. I wrote a script on my raspberry pi to create an encrypted tar achieves of my org files twice a day transfer them over to Hedwig (my desktop), which will then find their way into an online backup provider. Now that I switched to Linux, that system stopped working, and I&amp;rsquo;ve kept postponing the critical need for an online backup too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a happy &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.backblaze.com/&#34;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; customer for about half a year, and I used their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.backblaze.com/cloud-backup.html&#34;&gt;full computer backup plan&lt;/a&gt; on Windows for a flat fee of $60 a year. With Linux though, this plan was no longer an option. It seemed Backblaze was telling me &amp;ldquo;hey man, now that you&amp;rsquo;re using Linux full time, it&amp;rsquo;s time to wear the big boy&amp;rsquo;s hat and stop using our training wheels. Get serious, or go back to Windows.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backblaze&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/cloud-storage.html&#34;&gt;B2 Backup&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most affordable (if not &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; most affordable) deals I&amp;rsquo;ve found. I had to create a script that would most likely run with &lt;a href=&#34;http://duplicity.nongnu.org/&#34;&gt;Duplicity&lt;/a&gt;, a trusted Linux tool that&amp;rsquo;s been around for a while. After a massive project at work finally ended, I had the time to sit down and try to make it work. I started running into issues though: it seemed like authentication with B2 was rejected due to some known issue, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find too much information about fixing it. What I did found though, as I was looking through various help documentations, is a lesser-known FOSS tool: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duplicati.com/&#34;&gt;Duplicati&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can tell by the game of words here that Duplicity and Duplicati are related: &amp;ldquo;The Duplicati project was inspired by Duplicity and had similar functionality until 2008,&amp;rdquo; its team says in the manual, and the philosophy is the same: a free encryption-supported tool for backups. It&amp;rsquo;s not directly available in official depositories (maybe in rolling releases?) due to its beta status, but it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duplicati.com/download&#34;&gt;easy enough to download for Debian-based distros&lt;/a&gt; (this is another example of why &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200108/&#34;&gt;switching to Kubuntu&lt;/a&gt; was a good idea for me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duplicity&amp;rsquo;s GUI is easy enough to understand, almost to the point that their &lt;a href=&#34;https://duplicati.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;&gt;manual&lt;/a&gt; or excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duplicati.com/articles/Getting-Started/&#34;&gt;getting started guide&lt;/a&gt; are not needed. As it turns out, connection settings for Backblaze&amp;rsquo;s B2 backups come built-in, as well as many other options like Amazon&amp;rsquo;s S3 or box.com. As a matter of fact, the GUI was so simple and intuitive I quickly created different backups for that required different intervals:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200212_1.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these created, I was looking a my backups differently. No longer one large archive of all my system files, photos, media and org files, but a separate, &lt;em&gt;purposeful&lt;/em&gt; and specific jobs for different kind of needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200201/&#34;&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt; do not need to be backed-up every day. That&amp;rsquo;s because I take new photos perhaps once a week (sometimes less unfortunately). My org files are the opposite case: I work with them daily both at work and at home, and the differences are large enough for two daily backups: midday while I&amp;rsquo;m at work, making progress on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200123/&#34;&gt;various projects&lt;/a&gt;, and one late at night, after I&amp;rsquo;ve recorded my day in the journal and additional events on the agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duplicati also comes with &lt;a href=&#34;https://duplicati.readthedocs.io/en/latest/04-using-duplicati-from-the-command-line/&#34;&gt;command-line options&lt;/a&gt; which can be used to automate similar process on different machines (I can upload my photos from my desktop, and then duplicate the process for a similar backup on my raspberry pi, for example) or to save in case you need it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s too early to tell, but Duplicati&amp;rsquo; approach to backups with its ability to work with b2 out of the box is making the long-trusted &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bit-team/backintime&#34;&gt;back-in-time&lt;/a&gt; obsolete: there&amp;rsquo;s no need to backup to my external with one program and upload to b2 with another; duplicati is perfectly fine backing up what I need to my external as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backblaze is an excellent service/tool in itself. For &amp;ldquo;regular&amp;rdquo; home users, they have a simple desktop tool (Mac or Windows) that backs up everything important on the computer (main hard drive and system files) by default, but easy enough to work with if you want to be more granular about your approach, including password-protected encryption. They are aggressively affordable, even more so than Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Glacier. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools in Windows</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/windows-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/windows-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.tube/videos/watch/697084c3-6e9b-435c-b5e2-7647a9d9c30f&#34;&gt;first public video&lt;/a&gt; introduced me to new challanges I didn&amp;rsquo;t face until now. Case in point: displaying milliseconds in VLC. I looked online in various places for a solution with my tools of choice, VLC player and ffmpeg. Workarounds do exist, but not nearly as simple as what exists for me in Windows. This happened to me before. As I was starting to get stuck, I realized that sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s ok not to wrack my head over every single hurdle. This is a reminder for myself, and hopefully save you some time to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;millseconds-why&#34;&gt;Millseconds? Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While going over my video and deciding on parts to cut out (you guys don&amp;rsquo;t need to see me reading from my notes and going &amp;ldquo;uhhh, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;) it became clear that the cuts are sharp and unpolished. I start to say something, and then the video cuts to me looking at a different direction starting a new sentence. It&amp;rsquo;s jarring and makes me cringe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FFMPEG allows sepcifying which sagments you want to isolate down to the millisecond to prevent this from happening. Figuring out the point of cutting percisely on that level though proved to be too hard in VLC. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I can tune VLC to move frame by frame and somehow display the exact timestamp I&amp;rsquo;m on, but after a day and a half of looking into different solutions and two extensions, I gave up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;windows-and-mpc-hc&#34;&gt;Windows and MPC-HC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mpc-hc.org/&#34;&gt;Media Player Classic: Home Cinema&lt;/a&gt; is exactly what I needed. I remembered it from my pre-linux days, when I used it to watch different exotic video codecs that would not play on any other player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a lightweight tool that doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much else (as far as I know) besides playing videos and, if you right-click on the timestamp and choose &amp;ldquo;high precision&amp;rdquo;. Bang. A day and a half of looking into complicated solutions resolved in a single rightclick. The fact that I sometimes record and always edit my videos on my Windows desktop (which is my much stronger gaming-oriented machine) helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortuantely, WPC-HC is &lt;a href=&#34;https://mpc-hc.org/2017/07/16/1.7.13-released-and-farewell/&#34;&gt;discontinued&lt;/a&gt;. After all, who needs such a niche product when you have something as rubust and full-featured like VLC&amp;hellip;? So while it runs great for now, I probably need to keep my eyes open for a replacement (any recommendtations are warmly welcome).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-for-everything-else-linux-is-awesome-dot-dot-dot-right&#34;&gt;But for Everything Else, Linux is Awesome&amp;hellip; Right?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part, yes. But there are a few exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another good tool without a Linux alternative that jumps to mind is &lt;a href=&#34;https://getgreenshot.org/&#34;&gt;Greenshot&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, I blogged about &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/best-tools-flameshot/&#34;&gt;Flameshot&lt;/a&gt; before, but I since stopped using it due to an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lupoDharkael/flameshot/issues/563#issuecomment-526918408&#34;&gt;annoying locale issue&lt;/a&gt; deep in my Manajro&amp;rsquo;s configuration. It&amp;rsquo;s replacement, &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.kde.org/p/1156408/&#34;&gt;Ksnip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, is not as good. While I can forgive flameshot&amp;rsquo;s lack of features in favor of lightness and elegance, ksnip is way &amp;ldquo;bulkier&amp;rdquo; but lacks many good features compared to greenshot and a good amount of polish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m at the graphics department: another great tool in Windows is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getpaint.net/index.html&#34;&gt;paint.net&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a light photo-editing tool which walks the thin line of &amp;ldquo;photoshop light&amp;rdquo; like no other app I&amp;rsquo;ve used. There&amp;rsquo;s GIMP of course, but I never use it. It comes with its own learning curve and plethora of features I almost never need beyond my Android&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.niksoftware.snapseed&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Snapspeed&lt;/a&gt; (here are two &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixelfed.social/p/JR121/74693748268863488&#34;&gt;recent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixelfed.social/p/JR121/82812393729691648&#34;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll skip the loaded issue of gaming on Linux, since the fact that I have a Windows desktop built mostly for that speaks for itself, and continue into other forms of entertainment: hosting my movies, music, and Ebooks. Linux does have the top hand when it comes to running a good server, but installing PLEX and managing file permissions for a NTFS hard drive shared with Windows is an experience I&amp;rsquo;m willing to pass on. When I eventually graduate to a NAS, it will probably be Linux based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this mostly leaves us with Windows for entertainment and video editing, Linux for productivity and work&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Sounds about right to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about you? Do you use different systems side by side like this, or are you the laptop warrior kind? Maybe a Windows guru? A mac-all-the-way person?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems like this &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.kde.org/Incubator/Projects/Ksnip#Status&#34;&gt;project has been killed&lt;/a&gt; in favor of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DamirPorobic/KImageAnnotator&#34;&gt;KimageAnnonator&lt;/a&gt;, which looks exactly the same to me. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, since I use Backblaze to backup my files, my Windows machine is also my dedicated &amp;ldquo;backup server-client&amp;rdquo; as well. However it&amp;rsquo;s my Raspberry Pi that does the automation and uploads a compressed backup file every night without fail. You can&amp;rsquo;t beat Linux when it comes to automations of &amp;ldquo;set up and forget&amp;rdquo; like these. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orgzly: An Interview</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/orgzly-neven-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/orgzly-neven-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orgzly.com/&#34;&gt;Orgzly&lt;/a&gt; several times on this blog, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t dedicated a full post to it yet until now. Instead of describing my workflow again or just praising Orgzly&amp;rsquo;s usefulness in a repeated manner, I thought it would be interesting to reach out to its creator and ask a couple of questions instead. To my delight, he was happy to reply! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to present my first interview on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, for those of you who are not familiar with Orgzly, a quick intro. Those of you who are, just skip the next paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Org-mode, as awesome as it is, has one glaring problem which keeps many users from using it all day: it&amp;rsquo;s inability to be mobile. Org-mode is built into Emacs, which in turn is built into Linux (or, with some alternations, into macOS). This means you can&amp;rsquo;t take Org-mode with you on the go. For Android, Org-mode&amp;rsquo;s official tool was &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/matburt/mobileorg-android&#34;&gt;MobileOrg&lt;/a&gt;, which is no longer active. While workarounds exist, it&amp;rsquo;s probably safe to say the only Android tool worth your time out there is Orgzly. As I mentioned several times before, it was actually Orgzly that got me into Org-mode and then into Emacs. I use Orgzly every day, all day. It is easily the main reason why Org-mode is even an option for me at work: it is what allows me to access my agenda and todo&amp;rsquo;s with all their details on my running-around routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this out of the way, let&amp;rsquo;s turn to the creator of Orgzly: Neven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neven prefers not to talk too much about himself but agreed to tell us he&amp;rsquo;s a software engineer working for a company in the US. His experience comes mostly from working with Java. Below, my questions in italic, his answers in the texts under.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Orgzly seem to answer a very specific niche: Android Org-mode users on the go. Are these the people you&amp;rsquo;re trying to reach?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was born from the need to have org files on my Android phone. MobileOrg was the only app available I could find, but I had a hard time setting it up and getting used to it. Initially, I started writing a web app, in Rails. But too many little things bothered me, it felt hackish and clunky. So eventually, I started playing with Android. I never wrote anything for it before, but since I use it, it seemed like the best alternative. Orgzly literally grew from the &amp;ldquo;hello, world&amp;rdquo; app, while I was learning to program for Android. So my first goal was to have an easy-to-use Android app for org files, yet powerful enough to be able to do the majority of work in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having Org-mode users as the app&amp;rsquo;s early adopters was very useful, as they know what they want and how they want it. It was also a motivator for me. But I had non-Org-mode users in mind right from the start. Even with huge competition in the field of task apps, I thought it would be useful for the quality of Orgzly to make it tempting for those users as well and see what suggestions they&amp;rsquo;d have on improving it. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get stuck writing for the very specific type of mostly tech-savvy users and end up with a hard-to-use app. Orgzly was made to support more formats to store the notebooks in - not just org files - from day one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As an Org-mode user, how does Orgzly help you with your personal workflow?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got a job years ago, I needed a way to track all the projects and the little tasks I was working on. I never had a real need for that before, so I started using a simple spreadsheet (I used OpenOffice, which was popular at the time).  Occasionally I gave random software or productivity apps a go, looking to improve my system. Eventually I tried Org-mode (after about a year or so) and never looked back. At the time I was a Vim user, but because Org-mode became such an important part of my workflow, I eventually switched to Emacs. It was way more convenient for me, as I became a heavy Org-mode user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays I use Org-mode for pretty much everything: Orgzly-related work, day job-related projects, and personal tasks. Anything from new Orgzly repository type support to buying fruits at the store, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can we expand on that? We Org-mode folk love hearing about other people&amp;rsquo;s methods and hacks&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t do anything too crazy. I used to store the majority of my tasks in three big org files (Orgzly.org, work.org, and personal.org) with different states, tags and properties. Search speed became an issue for me in Org-mode, mainly when filtering by planning times and properties, so now I have two files per area: one for active tasks and one for some day/maybe (a la GTD) stuff. I also have a separate Inbox.org file (again taken from GTD, the method I&amp;rsquo;m trying to follow as much as I can in Org-mode). This seems to be working particularly well with a mobile app such as Orgzly, since you don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend too much time thinking where and how to store some idea or a task when you&amp;rsquo;re on the go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What do you hope Org-mode users get out of Orgzly? What about the non-Org users you mentioned?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Org-mode users, my goal is that they feel as comfortable and efficient in Orgzly as much as they do in Org-mode. This is obviously a huge goal and the app has still a long way to go for that to happen, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s a useful goal to have since it helps to improve the quality of the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for Non-Org-mode users, they should be able to use the app easily, without the underlying format of notebooks or any Org-mode-specific features getting in their way. They shouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to know what Org-mode even is, but if they learn about it through Orgzly, great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What makes Orgzly different than the other task and productivity apps out there then?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the number of apps out there, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty hard to stand out. Having notebooks in plain text and being able to sync them anywhere would be the main advantage I guess. Syncing is currently done through Orgzly&amp;rsquo;s Directory repository, and Dropbox is still the only way to do that directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you get any help developing the app? How much work and time do you put into it? Orgzly doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any ads or any other form of contribution, is that something you are looking into?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to work on Orgzly as much as I can, but I don&amp;rsquo;t do it nearly as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like to. It&amp;rsquo;s not always easy to find the time between my day job and personal projects. There are periods when I have a lot of free time to work on Orgzly, and there are times when I can barely get on top of my emails. Contribution on GitHub is great, especially small and tested pull requests which I can just merge immediately. There have been some larger projects done too. For example, there is a Git repository support currently in progress which I&amp;rsquo;m barely involved in, which is great. As for Orgzly monetization, my plan is to implement in-app purchases for the version in Google Play. (&lt;em&gt;note: Orgzly is available in Google Play store and in the free &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.f-droid.org/&#34;&gt;F-Droid store&lt;/a&gt; - J.R.&lt;/em&gt;) I never considered adding ads (I do not like seeing them in apps). I considered accepting donations, but I prefer trying to have a long-term steady income instead, eventually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neven, thank you so much for agreeing to do this FAQ. Please keep up the excellent work!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you!
-Neven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-couple-of-concluding-remarks&#34;&gt;A Couple of Concluding Remarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a few additional thoughts to share after heading from Neven:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, It was intriguing to hear the Neven&amp;rsquo;s opinion about non-tech and non-Org users. In a way, he looks up to them as inspiration: the more they can use the app, the better the app is. This makes me think about the Org-mode and Emacs manual. It is very detailed, very informative, yet in the beginning it served me as a last resort only. That&amp;rsquo;s because it feels the Emacs was written from the &amp;ldquo;inside&amp;rdquo; by people who understand programming and Linux. Because of that I often couldn&amp;rsquo;t find what I was looking for and ended up Googling basic questions. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to ask. Today, when I have a better understanding of what I need, I can use the manual more often. But Orgzly was not created this way. I started using Orgzly before I started using Emacs, and one of the reasons for that was because it made sense from the start. The manual was intuitive, made sense, and &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt;. I think Neven is on to something very important here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, I find that a couple of hacks really help me work around Orgzly&amp;rsquo;s limitation. It is, after all, just an &amp;ldquo;Org-mode&amp;rdquo; light. It might be useful to highlight some of these here again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neven said that in a mobile app, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to think much about what information you capture and where to put it. This is something I very much agree with. I have Orgzly&amp;rsquo;s agenda widget on my screen for my tasks for the day, which a quick tap away from projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on at any given moment (since I go back to my office to refile and organized between tasks). The widget has a plus sign at the corner which quickly launches a new note in my default &amp;ldquo;inbox&amp;rdquo; org file. When I create a note, I often don&amp;rsquo;t type. Instead, I tap the microphone on my Android&amp;rsquo;s keyboard and dictate what I need. Even if the translation is 100%, it&amp;rsquo;s close enough that I know what I wanted to say when I&amp;rsquo;m in front of a computer. This is so quick it&amp;rsquo;s often &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; than using org-capture. When the note saves, it is automatically scheduled as a todo item on my agenda to the same day (an option in Orgzly) so that it&amp;rsquo;s in front of my face on the agenda and I can refile and schedule it as needed and don&amp;rsquo;t forget about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second thing is &lt;a href=&#34;https://syncthing.net/&#34;&gt;Syncthing&lt;/a&gt;. Neven mentioned Dropbox, which works fine, but for the more privacy and space-aware folks out there, Syncthing is a godsend. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/raspberry%5Fpi%5Forg%5Fhub/&#34;&gt;wrote about it in length before&lt;/a&gt;, so I won&amp;rsquo;t get into my system here. If Orgzly is what allows me to work with Org-mode everywhere, Syncthing is the glue that makes it possible. An update on my phone from the field will show up in a second on my VM at work and my Linux box at home, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Tools for the job: Flameshot</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/best-tools-flameshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/best-tools-flameshot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every now and then I discover (or re-discover) a tool in Linux that does exactly what I need it to do. Some examples include ffmpeg, to shrink down my self-recorded webcam journal session while increasing the volume; abcde, to rip a classical music CD to flac and find its exact title and name; youtube-dl, which downloads any video online I need along with aria to speed these downloads, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I want to praise a new excellent tool, this time for screenshots: &lt;a href=&#34;https://flameshot.js.org/#/&#34;&gt;Flameshot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/2019-05-25.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flameshot is walking the thin line between being a heavy future-rich screen capture tool with all kinds of features (think  and the minimal screen-capture one that usually comes bundled with your distro. I think it manages to be &amp;ldquo;just enough&amp;rdquo; to do exactly what it needs to do. Nothing more, nothing less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was easy enough to tie Flameshot to my print-screen button. When summoned, the entire screen becomes dark, and a little message asks me to drag my selection with the mouse. The resulting window, which you can see in the picture above, is a frame that can be adjusted by dragging its sides to crop exactly what you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you stretch the frame, the different tools buttons re-arrange themselves depending on the frame&amp;rsquo;s size. It&amp;rsquo;s a really nice feature which makes the whole application feel smooth and responsive. The wider the frame is, the more tools on the bottom. If the frame is really small, the tools will wrap all around the frame, creating a second row, as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flameshot comes with all the basic tools you need from an annotation application: arrows, lines, and now (finally) a text tool, which needs to first be activated from the tools configuration menu: (&lt;code&gt;$ flameshot config&lt;/code&gt;). There&amp;rsquo;s also a text-blur and upload to Imgur tool. Flameshot is minimal: there&amp;rsquo;s no eraser button, for example, because it&amp;rsquo;s not needed. You can only undo and re-do. The color palette is basic, without a large color wheel. You can&amp;rsquo;t rotate and flip images; it trusts you to use a more &amp;ldquo;heavy guns&amp;rdquo; editing tool for that, reminding you it&amp;rsquo;s there only for a screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an elegant tool, with an intuitive UI: right-click to choose a color; scroll to make the lines wider or thinner. When you choose the upload to Imgur button, for example, it automatically does that in the background and opens a window for you to either save, copy the freshly-created link to the clipboard or delete the image from the site, which opens another tab in your browser for that. This is the kind of application that makes you feel proud using it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everenote - Behind the Scenes</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/everenote-behind-the-scenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/everenote-behind-the-scenes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years back, I was an avid user of Evernote. That was a period of information &amp;ldquo;innocence&amp;rdquo; for me, before I knew much about Linux and switched careers to IT. Back then, Evernote was an amazing discovery. It was the first serious digital (and, to be honest, analog as well) system I built. I remember many nights where I drifted off to sleep thinking about how to tag and achieve my information in it. To this day I have plenty of memories stored away in its achieve files &amp;ndash; though they have been since downloaded and converted from the App&amp;rsquo;s native format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, YouTube&amp;rsquo;s algorithm picked up &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5rNUpXYCcrA&#34;&gt;a video from Evernote&lt;/a&gt; and threw it my way as a suggestion. It&amp;rsquo;s a short introduction to a promised upcoming series from Evernote, called Behind the Scenes. Introduced directly by Evernote&amp;rsquo;s current CEO, Ian Small, this seems to be an honest attempt to &amp;ldquo;take us behind the scenes&amp;hellip; and show us what [Evernote] is working on.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evernote is a for-profit company with a product that is very different than org-mode. While I have no desire or need to switch from org in the near future, it would be interesting to see what kind of challenges the makers of a popular note-taking app come up with. Who knows, perhaps I could learn a thing or two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
