<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>games on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in games on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Elite Dangerous: Beginning</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/elite-dangerous-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/elite-dangerous-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;17:42. Almost time to go home. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to hold on a bit longer, to tell myself I should around more before I buy it. Elite is complex, with a steep learning and no real objectives in sight. I was worried it&amp;rsquo;ll be more work after work. So of course, I bought it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I heard about Elite was on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/990638636763840513&#34;&gt;Twitter, from one of the famed infosec folks I follow&lt;/a&gt;. Then I heard about a bunch of players on an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcgamer.com/over-8000-elite-dangerous-pilots-are-embarking-on-an-incredible-18-week-journey/&#34;&gt;epic journey to the other side of the galaxy&lt;/a&gt;, especially when I realized this was a gamer-community driven event. This was also around the time I started watching Twitch streams more often, looking for a game that is more than just another hack and slash. Eventually, a few weeks ago, I started watching [Elite streamers](&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/directory/game/Elite:&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/directory/game/Elite:&lt;/a&gt; Dangerous).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no idea how beautiful the game was. I didn&amp;rsquo;t prepare myself to watch streamers for long periods (something I didn&amp;rsquo;t know before), glued to the screen and asking questions. And then I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/thepavehawker/videos&#34;&gt;Pave&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pave is a real-world USAF veteran who now makes a living streaming Elite 8 hours a night, &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; night. I know, because I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching him for a week, glued to the screen until my head started bobbing up and down and then up again as sleep took over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with his mug of Joe, a classic story-teller voice, and patience tougher than nails, Pave explained everything I asked him to the littlest detail. No question was too dumb or too long. Everything was explained. The more he explained, the more I learned just how vast and &lt;em&gt;complex&lt;/em&gt; Elite is. Go ahead and try him: just ask him what joystick he uses, and why he mispronounces its name, or what (in his opinion) are the best controls to play the game. Pave has been playing the game since 2015, and it shows. Watching him maneuvering around a space station looking for the landing pad or zigzagging his way in a dogfight, the guy has skills that kept me coming back for more every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a game creates streamers like Pave, you know something must be right about it. When a game has been in existence (in one shape or another) since 1984, you know you&amp;rsquo;re looking at a true classic. And when players form a group that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2019/02/18/elite-dangerous-rescue-mission-commander-deluvian/&#34;&gt;goes on epic journeys to save other players&lt;/a&gt;, you know you got a game that brings the best out in people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you know. I thought it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hurt to try it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Subnautica and Fear</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/subnautica-and-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/subnautica-and-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/subnautica_jrss.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it was time to build a base on my second attempt at &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subnautica&#34;&gt;Subnautica&lt;/a&gt;, I picked a location near the &lt;a href=&#34;http://subnautica.wikia.com/wiki/Blood%5FKelp%5FZone&#34;&gt;Blood Kelp Zone&lt;/a&gt;. Its cliff walls spread in front of me into the endless blue, and deep down I could see the pale &lt;a href=&#34;http://subnautica.wikia.com/wiki/Bloodvine&#34;&gt;bloodvines&lt;/a&gt; reaching up toward me like the claws of a forgotten demon. As if by cue, scary dramatic music started playing, and my PDA&amp;rsquo;s AI announced that the zone &amp;ldquo;matches 7 of the 9 preconditions for stimulating terror in humans.&amp;rdquo; I was thankful the game creators didn&amp;rsquo;t include the two other ones, whatever these may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I chose this location for my home was because of fear. Subnautica is a game about fear, and it was teaching me to face it one step at a time. The first time I played, the game had the element of surprise. I remember my first &lt;a href=&#34;http://subnautica.wikia.com/wiki/Reaper%5FLeviathan&#34;&gt;reaper&lt;/a&gt;: it came out of nowhere and grabbed my &lt;a href=&#34;http://subnautica.wikia.com/wiki/Seamoth&#34;&gt;Seamoth&lt;/a&gt; like a plaything. I  yelped, slammed the Alt+F4 keys, and stomped out of my room white like the hallway wall I was leaning against, mumbling &amp;ldquo;oh my god&amp;rdquo; over and over. Now I know better. I know where they are, I can see them in the distance, and&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m still scared. But I go ahead anyway. The fear is not pushing me away; it&amp;rsquo;s teaching me to be prepared. The only thing that&amp;rsquo;s really scary is fear itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the base is furnished complete with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://subnautica.wikia.com/wiki/Moonpool&#34;&gt;Moonpool&lt;/a&gt; for my Seamoth which I call &amp;ldquo;Discovery.&amp;rdquo; It is powered by a nuclear reactor I built from fractions retrieved from brave explorations. A single glass corridor connects my living area to a bubble-like observatory room which hovers directly over the dark abyss. There&amp;rsquo;s a chair in the middle of that observatory, so I can sit and read my PDA&amp;rsquo;s contents while staring fear in the face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve found something at the bottom of the abyss. &amp;ldquo;Something that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be there.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a dark, green-hellish looking place with bones of creatures the size of an apartment building. Each day I explore further. Each day I push further and the game never fails to scare me. Winning these small battles against myself bit by bit becomes addictive. I look back at what scared me before and I know I&amp;rsquo;ve conquered it. I know that now if one of these monsters chooses to attack my base, I will fight it. The base hanging over the cliff that once terrorized me is now my home, transformed into my new comfort zone. I know every fold in the ground, every floaters-covered rock, every hole to the mushroom cave. You can&amp;rsquo;t be scared of what you know. Subnautica is an excellent teacher of this lesson.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
