<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Orgmode on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/orgmode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Orgmode on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/orgmode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Org Capture Templates - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/emacsorg/org-capture-template-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/emacsorg/org-capture-template-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took a long unplanned break from writing about my Templates because of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/blogging/css-updates-1/&#34;&gt;CSS changes&lt;/a&gt; I worked on and the complications with Magit. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say these are now behind me, and that I gained another grain of confidence using Magit and knowing git, but this is a post for yet another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the last two templates are rather short, I&amp;rsquo;m putting them both here together. Here we go:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Org Capture Templates - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/emacsorg/org-capture-template-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/emacsorg/org-capture-template-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was happy to see part one of this series generated interest on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/orgmode/comments/agxe8n/my%5Forgmode%5Ftemplates%5Fpart%5Fone%5Fany%5Finterest%5Fin%5Fmore/&#34;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;. One of the things I love about Org-mode (and Emacs) is this passion among its user and the thirst to learn more from each other. I believe one of the major reasons for that is Org-mode&amp;rsquo;s complexity: there are so many options, it &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be personalized by its users&amp;rsquo; needs. Org-mode is esaily the most personal tool I&amp;rsquo;ve used in a while. Every time I read something Org-mode related somewhere else it&amp;rsquo;s as if I&amp;rsquo;m invited over for a discussion over a cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Org Capture Templates - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/emacsorg/org-capture-template-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/emacsorg/org-capture-template-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.social/@emsenn&#34;&gt;emsenn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.social/@emsenn/101387457090836368&#34;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; Org-mode users for their day-to-day capture templates in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.technology&#34;&gt;technology Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; (which you should join and follow if you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet). I was happy to reply and figured it would be intesting to dig into my capture templates. I started writing this post explaining all of my templates, but then realized I&amp;rsquo;m starting to edit out details because the post is getting too long. So instead, I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain each template at a time. Hopefully you find this interesting!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Org Update</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/emacsorg/org-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/emacsorg/org-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I blogged about my Org activities. Overall, not a lot has changed from my latest setup. Setting up a new site on GitHub with Hugo kept me fairly busy, away from hacking away at Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>