<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>orgmode on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/orgmode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in orgmode on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/orgmode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Submenus in org-mode Capture</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/sub-menus-in-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/sub-menus-in-org/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-in-files/&#34;&gt;In my last post&lt;/a&gt;, I discussed how I (finally) found out that I can use entire org files as capture templates. This is a basic feature that works out of the box, but the org-mode manual doesn&amp;rsquo;t give it enough exposure in my opinion. Turns out it &lt;a href=&#34;https://irreal.org/blog/?p=8161&#34;&gt;wasn&amp;rsquo;t just me&lt;/a&gt; either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was expanding my checklists and learning more &amp;ldquo;trivial&amp;rdquo; org-capture features, I discovered more useful things, but ran out of time to write about them. It&amp;rsquo;s now time to get back to more &amp;ldquo;basics&amp;rdquo; of org-capture again for some helpful tips.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Org-capture in Files</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-in-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-in-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty busy org-mode-ly speaking. There is a lot to say, and as I was writing my post, more ideas occurred to me that behooved me to stop writing and experiment more, which lead to more interesting results, which meant I ran out of time to write about the results. When I finally returned to my post this morning, I realized there&amp;rsquo;s so much to explain, I can&amp;rsquo;t include it all in one go. Here you go, part one of my latest adventure in org-mode: org-capture from org files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Updates: June</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/quick-updates-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/quick-updates-june/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though I don&amp;rsquo;t have any means of tracking how many readers I have on this blog, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel a little bit responsible for my audience. This is an attempt to see how a quick &amp;ldquo;here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s up&amp;rdquo; post while the blog is otherwise idle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, a few quick updates about what&amp;rsquo;s coming up:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orgzly: An Interview</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/orgzly-neven-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/orgzly-neven-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orgzly.com/&#34;&gt;Orgzly&lt;/a&gt; several times on this blog, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t dedicated a full post to it yet until now. Instead of describing my workflow again or just praising Orgzly&amp;rsquo;s usefulness in a repeated manner, I thought it would be interesting to reach out to its creator and ask a couple of questions instead. To my delight, he was happy to reply! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to present my first interview on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Gcal Failed</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/why-gcal-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/why-gcal-failed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently tried &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/myuhe/org-gcal.el&#34;&gt;Org-Gcal&lt;/a&gt; a second time just to turn it off again. I was following the (now slightly outdated) &lt;a href=&#34;https://cestlaz.github.io/posts/using-emacs-26-gcal/&#34;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://cestlaz.github.io/&#34;&gt;Mike Zamansky&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; blog and managed to get it working this time, but I found the end result messy and cumbersome. This is mostly because of how I use org and my agenda to quickly get a view of what I need, not really a reflection on the tool itself. It made me understand how different the methodology of Google calendar and Org-mode are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agenda, and the Benfit of Having Multiple Files</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/agenda-multiple-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/agenda-multiple-files/</guid>
      <description>I used to write all my tasks, personal and work, into one tasks.org file.
On Sunday night, this was good. I had 5 tasks on my list, and I was ready to start my work week. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t take long (two days actually) for tasks.org to become monster.org. It didn&amp;rsquo;t happen because of the number of tasks, which I kept (more or less) under control. It happened because of the size of the projects I was working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libre and Clothes</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/libre-and-clothes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/libre-and-clothes/</guid>
      <description>When I write, I live in Emacs (with the awesome Solorized theme) inside Org-Mode.
With time, I found that Org has already made me more effienet writer and note taker. I write notes in every meeting now, rather it&amp;rsquo;s my &amp;ldquo;turn&amp;rdquo; or not. I write notes as I work, about every solution and every problem I&amp;rsquo;m facing. I write first thing in the morning, usually about org-related thoughts I had as I wake up, over a cup of Sumatra cofee (little almond milk, one pack of sugar).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>