<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Wisdom</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/desktopwisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/desktopwisdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I asked my coworkers the following question:
&amp;ldquo;What is the one truth, in a sentence, you&amp;rsquo;ve learned from being in a help desk position&amp;rdquo;? Here are the answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris (age:25, years in the job:3)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;There are a lot, and I mean a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt;, stupid people in the world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick (age:28, years in the job:10)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;You got to have a lot of patience&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave (age:63, years in the job:30)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re only as good as the last person you&amp;rsquo;ve helped&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myself (years in the job:3)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;If it was really to &amp;lsquo;just work&amp;rsquo;, we&amp;rsquo;d be out of a job&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at the nature of the job and the experience each one of us had, these facts make a lot of sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris is the youngest, very bright, and after money. He&amp;rsquo;s tired of users forgetting to check the power cable or not knowing how to reset their computers before calling. Nick is a chill guy who never seems to get upset. He is used to the boss demanding things and he exercises every day, which definitely help to take out aggravations. Dave has seen it all in this job and been through a couple of management changes. His other favorite sentence is &amp;ldquo;tomorrow is another day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolvement of Video Journal &amp; Org</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/video_journal_evolved/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/video_journal_evolved/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over time, my videos definitely got smaller. This is because I got used to Org in different areas of recording my thoughts. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://jarss.github.io/TAONAW/blog/org-update/&#34;&gt;discussed these&lt;/a&gt; couple of times before: tasks, task notes, and journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My tasks do rarely contain sub-tasks anymore. This is odd because sub-tasking was one of the reasons that got me into Org-mode initially. Over time I found that I rather leave notes to myself about where I left off and what needs to be done instead of using actual tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Task notes are usually brief (one paragraph with 3 to 5 lines) and are always timestamped with most recent on top. This quickly lets me know where I stopped a task and why. Interestingly, I use it also to indicate general mundane errands, like grocery shopping. In such cases, I can also include a checklist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journal is a different story. This is where I let myself spill the beans. I took a long break from using a journal because I felt there&amp;rsquo;s so much recording done on a keyboard, and I wanted a quicker way to record my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But recording my thoughts was inconvenient. I had to take a break from my workflow, record a video, name it, compress it, and save it. It required that I&amp;rsquo;ll find a quiet corner - nearly impossible to do during my day - to record for a few minutes. So out of necessity, I started to include more text in my task notes. Eventually, I felt they become too long, too personal, and just too heavy. I needed a separation and going back to my journal felt natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that typing is just slow enough to make me process what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking. I can edit what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to say, which means I can rethink of a better way of describing it. To prevent myself from going on and on, I journal on specific events only, never an entire day. My capture template takes the link of my event and makes it the title, and then continue to discuss only that event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I noticed something interesting: with time, my rambling on videos was reduced from going on an on for an hour plus or so (and multiple videos) to shorter segments. Here&amp;rsquo;s a visual:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/videojournalevolved_1.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above: over time, my clips become shorter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, last weekend, I reached the conclusion that my written journal is just &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; at keeping track of my experiences. Since I re-created the way I save my achieve files now, it also means the links from the journal org file to the org and the events is never broken: I just have to make sure to refile an event from my &amp;ldquo;oh snap&amp;rdquo; thought-dump org into the current week org file, and I&amp;rsquo;m good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still record a short &amp;ldquo;weekly summary&amp;rdquo; on weekends, and now I find I&amp;rsquo;m actually looking forward to it. These are now 10-20 minutes long videos in which I briefly go through my agenda and logged events and explain what happened while my memories of this week are still fresh. I then give the week a &amp;ldquo;theme&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works as a way for me to remember what happened far in the future if I want to reflect on my experiences but not looking for something specific, or not sure what it is. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good way to reflect on the major events of the week after I had a weekend to slow down and process. It works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Relationships and Money</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/of_people_and_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/of_people_and_money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warning: This is not my usual geeky-tech rambling about Org or Emacs. This is a somewhat NSFW post about my life. If you&amp;rsquo;re not into that and you&amp;rsquo;re here for the geeky stuff, I&amp;rsquo;d skip this if I were you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was reaching my 30s, I hit a jackpot. I secured a deal for a rent-controlled apartment in Morningside Heights in Manhattan. I had a job that didn&amp;rsquo;t quite pay the bills, even for that, so I drove almost 900 miles to Milwaukee, Wisconsin to fetch a friend whom I convinced to live with me in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apartment had three bedrooms, a living room, a dining area, a small kitchen (which I loved a lot) and a shower. It was packed with old furniture and dusty chachkies because its owner was about 80 years old. He asked me to wire rent money to his account every month, left me with a key, and left for Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve met, dated, and enjoyed many women during that period. I had professional dominatrix taking photos naked on my dinner table (I had to help them put on corsets), and I had a high school girl who I was afraid was underage (she wasn&amp;rsquo;t) take a shower with me. I had a woman come over to have sex with both me and my friend-turned-roommate, and another who had an orgasm telling me I&amp;rsquo;m gay while penetrating me with her fingers. All remarkable, all faded out of my life as quickly as they came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years later, in a different apartment, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to keep paying the rent. For the first time in decade, I had to move in with my mother, who moved to Manhattan by then. My mother&amp;rsquo;s apartment had only one bedroom, a long hallway, and a living room. The kitchen was a corner carved out of the hallway and had strong fluorescent lights. I remember this because the lights and the noise of dishes woke me up every morning when my mother started making coffee a few inches away from the sofa on which I slept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve dated almost no one during that time. As a matter of fact, I can remember only two. That&amp;rsquo;s because when I moved (with my mother) to another apartment, the relationships I started forming on top of the sofa with these two moved with it.  I graduated from the sofa to the bedroom. My mother, coincidentally, found a boyfriend in Pennsylvania and was away or most of the week. I noticed how slowly, with a stable job, better clothes, and the aforementioned status upgrade, I started dating more people again. Not as many - there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much time and less energy - but it was a steady rising slope. The new people I&amp;rsquo;ve dated came and went. The job, also, quickly transformed into a new career. The two partners and the sofa remained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny how you think all you want is to be able to keep fucking everyone (figuratively and literally) but what you actually want is companionship. It&amp;rsquo;s something we as a society keep shoving into everyone&amp;rsquo;s throat, yet somehow, doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to stay in anyone&amp;rsquo;s skull. Yet, it&amp;rsquo;s the fear of being alone, completely alone, that we often afraid the most. I know because I&amp;rsquo;m an as introvert as they come, but even I have to admit that my life is a hollow shade of gray without the color these two relationships brought to my life. These connections shape us, make us who we are as adults, and eventually, these connections are also what is remembered when we are gone. there&amp;rsquo;s nothing as painful as losing such a connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t make a relationship out of thin air. That&amp;rsquo;s because a relationship is forged from common experiences that you often try to avoid. Embarrassing little moments. Painful memories. The terrifying realization that at some point (you can&amp;rsquo;t be sure when) caring about that person is more important than caring for yourself. Then, the peace that comes with accepting this realization. You can&amp;rsquo;t find this sort of experience on Tinder, even if you pay their premium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never wanted to end up on my mother&amp;rsquo;s sofa, and to be honest, I never wanted to end up in relationships with both of my partners. But just like the sofa, shit happens. This is who I am now, and who they are, and how we came to be. My partners, who I affectionately call patches, live with me now. We often enjoy a good movie sitting on that sofa, which is with us still.  I&amp;rsquo;m older, I&amp;rsquo;m scarred, I have way less patience than I used to have, and I like it all just the way it is, good and bad, sofa or no sofa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Windows Managment</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/emacs-windows-managment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/emacs-windows-managment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In his 5th Emacs podcast, &lt;a href=&#34;https://emacscast.org/episode%5F5/&#34;&gt;Rakhim&lt;/a&gt; discusses the difficulties of windows management in Emacs. I agree with him. Emacs&amp;rsquo; Windows are a pain. It was probably one of the longest pet peeves I had with the program, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until this podcast that I realized that I&amp;rsquo;m much better off than I used to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t use any extension that manages windows (unless you consider Ivy&amp;rsquo;s switch buffer, which he uses too. &lt;a href=&#34;https://oremacs.com/swiper/&#34;&gt;Ivy&lt;/a&gt; is awesome). My method is based on bits and pieces I picked up. Here are a couple of lines from my settings.org, which I use to make Emacs&amp;rsquo; windows work better for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, for my ultra-wide screen at home, it helps to enlarge the default frame size. After a few tests, I found this size satisfying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-emacs-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;emacs-lisp&#34;&gt;(setq default-frame-alist &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;((width &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;90&lt;/span&gt;) (height &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;) (menu-bar-lines &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;)))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, we need to turn on the mouse vertical mouse divider. This will allow us to use the mouse to drag and adjust windows in our frame vertically as well. I actually don&amp;rsquo;t use this as much anymore (the reason is coming up) but this is a basic feature that should be on by default, in my opinion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-emacs-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;emacs-lisp&#34;&gt;(window-divider-mode &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;+1&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another basic feature, which I now use everywhere, is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html%5Fnode/emacs/Visual-Line-Mode.html&#34;&gt;visual line mode&lt;/a&gt;. If you write more than you code on Emacs (which is true in my case) this mode just makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-emacs-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;emacs-lisp&#34;&gt;(global-visual-line-mode &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;+1&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those are all good and nice, but here&amp;rsquo;s the biggest tip which I stumbled upon a few months back, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://ergoemacs.org/emacs/emacs%5Feffective%5Fwindows%5Fmanagement.html&#34;&gt;Ergoemacs&lt;/a&gt;: just don&amp;rsquo;t use windows. Use frames. Seriously, it&amp;rsquo;s that simple. There are probably many Emacs experts out there with their windows functions and extensions and what not, but let&amp;rsquo;s not reinvent the wheel here. If there&amp;rsquo;s one thing a GUI is good for is to manage windows (or frames in Emacs). They are very easy to move with the mouse, they snap to each other, easy to resize. Besides, Emacs itself splits the frames to Windows often enough. I find that I use C-0 and C-1 very often to get rid of windows I don&amp;rsquo;t need, and I can have them back quickly by switching back to the buffer with Ivy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things that used to drive my bananas when I started using Org was how the agenda and its habit to kill my windows setup. One of the most helpful lines in my settings.org is the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-emacs-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;emacs-lisp&#34;&gt;(setq org-agenda-window-setup (quote other-frame))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This saved me from going insane. Since I start up my agenda every time I start up my Emacs, this shortcut also effectively creates the other frame for me to work with until I exit Emacs. From there, I can just use the Agenda frame itself to switch to another buffer if I want to. Agenda is also the only place where I do use windows often - when I tab into one of my headers there. I tab into a task, view it, make changes if I want, save, and C-0 to return to full agenda view. It&amp;rsquo;s so fast it&amp;rsquo;s just my muscle memory now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Org Update</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/org-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/org-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I blogged about my Org activities. Overall, not a lot has changed from my latest setup. Setting up a new site on GitHub with Hugo kept me fairly busy, away from hacking away at Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/OrgUpdate_1.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lighter-agenda-no-sub-tasks&#34;&gt;Lighter Agenda: No Sub-Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, looking at my agenda sometimes less is more. I don’t rush to include every single detail in my agenda anymore, especially at work, becuase it’s redundant. We have a ticketing system that we &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to use, and the details are constantly updated by different team members. Because of that, updating technical details for myself again under each heading is not that appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I do still include notes. Just differently. I start notes with an inactive timestamp and describe where I left off. In other words, exactly what the subtask used to do. So I don’t bother with many sub-tasks anymore. The benefit of one heading is better visual organization. I get a nice Logbook which includes all the time I spent on the project, my notes are more streamlined and easy to find. It also clears the agenda from the clutter of subtasks that sometimes don’t make sense to me anymore because I forgot the big picture already. I also grew more comfortable with changing the header wordings of the task to better reflect what is the big picture I just mentioned. Since I keep short notes of where I left off with the most recent one at the top, it’s easy to see what’s going on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/OrgUpdate_2.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I would even copy-paste from the ticket straight into Org just to remind myself what was done; other times I include references to other people and cases; yet other times, if I have to vent about something, there’s a link to my journal (more on that later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fun sidenote: Orgzly, my companion Andoird App, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orgzly.com/changelog&#34;&gt;now has the ability&lt;/a&gt; to start with Org headings collapsed. This means that when I’m on the go, I can open specifically the task on hand and view my notes which I often update just before I get up to do something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little test here. And here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;keeping-track-of-time-without-going-nuts&#34;&gt;Keeping Track Of Time Without Going Nuts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Logbook contains estimated times. I almost never get to close a clock on a task once I started, because I almost never get the chance to keep working on one thing before I am called away, or have to do a prerequisite. Other times, I simply forget to start the clock. I estimate how much time I worked on something when I’m back at my desk. Now, since I don’t bother with sub-tasks and separate clocking times for these, it means I need to expend my agenda to view my logs (l in agenda view). This allows me to see the time I spent working on a certain task, even though it is marked as done later, sometimes even days (or weeks) later. This way I know when the whole task was finished, and I can see when (and for how long) I was working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of that said, most of my tasks don&amp;rsquo;t get logged with a clock. That’s because many of them are simple tasks or just interruptions when I am asked a question or something similar. I should overall though get in the habit of logging tasks in retro-respect to see where my time went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another area I stopped worrying as much about are which org files in my archive my headers go to when I refile. This was a mouthful so let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My system is based on a weekly review. Every week has its own .org file. In the past, filenames used to specify a date range like &lt;code&gt;08102018_15102018.org&lt;/code&gt;, for example. This caused me complications because I seldom had the chance to summarize and finish my week Sunday and start a clean slate Monday. Many times I wanted to conclude an .org file on a Friday after work or didn’t get the chance to do so until Monday or even Tuesday. Besides, this whole week range thing is redundant because you can always list files by dates anyway (to see when it was last modified).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, since I started using my journal again, which is based on weeks rather than months, it made more sense to name the files after the number of the weeks. For instance, this week is w41.org, last week was w40.org, etc. My journal tells me what week I’m on if I ever need to reflect, the file name is very clear and obvious and there’s no room for confusion. My weekly summaries will always be based on their respective &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;number&amp;gt;.org&lt;/code&gt;, even if I summarize a month later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, I refiled events and tasks depending on what week they were to take place. If I was planning a vacation four weeks in advance, for example, I would open a new file for that week and place the event there. This lead to all kinds of problems when I worked on projects that stretched over more than just a weekly period. Let’s say I take a vacation from Friday to Monday of next week. Now what, which file do I choose? At the time, I opted for the completion date. But, this too wasn’t simple. Because certain projects (especially at work) could last even months, or re-surface from the past. That would mean I would have to move them to the appropriate week and think about what “done” really means. One day thinking about it out loud, I just started laughing at myself: “dude,” I said, as I like to refer anyone for some reason, “what are you doing? Org takes care of all of that for you automatically! That’s what’s the Agenda is for!” Who cares if I placed a project in week 20 or week 30, I don’t ever search it that way or know where it comes from anyway, I just see it on the agenda or search for it with the agenda anyway &lt;code&gt;(C-a s)&lt;/code&gt;. That’s what it’s for. So I stopped caring about that, and events now naturally fall into the week I created them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-journal-revisited&#34;&gt;The Journal Revisited&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t use the journal as much as I used to when I had it earlier this year. I find that I use it capture experiences and emotions more than technical notes. For the later, I now have an org file called “wiki” which I keep organized as it grows further. The journal is good to keep moods and mental “patterns” I can look into on my weekly review. For this, I also use tags. This is a good exercise that allows me to recognize mental “traps” I get into more often than not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journal works nicely with my weekly reviews, which are essentially weekly videos I make reading back from my agenda and journal. With time, these became more of a personal “summary of summaries” where I highlight my week tasks and review, usually for a 10-minute segment or so. I keep these in a well-compressed mp4 format on an SD card (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ffmpeg.org/&#34;&gt;FFMPEG&lt;/a&gt; is awesome for that) and I can easily use one SSD for an entire year and still have additional room. I am now starting to name the videos based on the same weekly theme that I use for my weekly agenda files and journal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - what takes so long?</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/hugo-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blog/hugo-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following me online for the last month or so (especially on reddit) you&amp;rsquo;d know I&amp;rsquo;ve been engaged in shifting away from WordPress and into the world &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d imagine the people of in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/&#34;&gt;r/emacs&lt;/a&gt; would raise an eyebrow at the term &amp;ldquo;world of Hugo.&amp;rdquo; After all, Hugo is a relatively simple program, not a deep rabbit-hole like Emacs. Yet, it&amp;rsquo;s Hugo that got me overwhelemed, not so much Emacs. What? Really?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, it has to do with background and expectations. As a non-programmer (as in, someone who never wrote anything a bit more complicated then a few lines of shell script) Emacs was a mountain. Standing at the bottom, I gazed at the cloud shrowing its peek and told myself &amp;ldquo;well, you gotta take a first step somewhere&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; so I did. For me, that was Org-mode. As a matter of fact, at the time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know much about Emacs and how deep it can get. All I knew was that Org was cool, and I&amp;rsquo;m interested in learning more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple of months, I got a bit more comfortable with Emacs and my level of doing things with it. I am still miles away from the top, and I&amp;rsquo;m fine with that. I got Emacs to do most of what I want it to do for me at this point, which is writing these posts, my journal entries, and of course my agenda and tasks both at work and at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo, on the other hand, was meant to replace WordPress. As a person who used WordPress on and off a couple of years, I expected more or less the same thing. You know, going to my webiste online somewhere, log in with a username and password, navigate the GUI and post stuff, add plugins&amp;hellip; As such, I didn&amp;rsquo;t care for a change that much. WordPress was working more or less OK, so why change to something similar and learn things all over again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get frequent alerts that my website is down from my webhost, but I got used to shrug these off. I got it as a cheap deal, and for about $6 a month or so hosting, what do you expect? People in the Emacs reddit mentioned they see more spam from my site&amp;rsquo;s URL instead of my posts, but again, with 1 person complaining out of 10 or so, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a big deal. After all, SSL and https is for professional website that can afford it, and I am just an amatuer-ish blogger. Perhaps the biggest hurdle was Github: I knew people who use Hugo usually use Github to publish their blog, but they were all programmers. Me, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about Github or git. That was for coders, people who write scripts for a living. This is not me. I am not a porgrammer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what changed that perspective. Perhaps it was a random tutorial I saw about Git which made me realize it&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; crazy complicated. Perhaps it was the fact that someone advised me not to link to my website again if I don&amp;rsquo;t have https. Maybe it was just my inner geek, itching for a change, and WordPress was getting too familiar and too boring. Whatever it was, I took the bait, and I started doing all of it at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I watched some Lynda videos about git and read a few posts. Then, I learned more about Hugo. After that, it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/&#34;&gt;ox-hugo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lsquo;s turn (because I gotta write my posts from inside Emacs), and then it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://magit.vc/&#34;&gt;Magit&lt;/a&gt; (because I gotta use git from inside Emacs). I think I went through everything in a matter of about a month. I learned too much too fast. But that&amp;rsquo;s how I roll. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I do that to myself, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how it makes sense to go from &amp;ldquo;git is for coders&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;ALL THE THINGS,&amp;rdquo; but I do anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this attitude has terrible consequences. You learn everything on a very shallow level, which means the first tiny bump in the road sends you launching out of control. You get frustrated and you try again, just to hit another bump. Turns out, if I &lt;em&gt;learn everything&lt;/em&gt; I also expect to &lt;em&gt;know everything&lt;/em&gt; out of myself, which is of course nonsense. But not everything is futile. Knowing the big picture in advance is not a bad idea. Learning a couple of things at once make you realize how they work together, and helps you develop a mindset that is more skilled at solving specific problems. Later, when you go look at the official documents, certain things already make sense to you even though you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen them before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be it as it may, it&amp;rsquo;s not easy. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend this method to anyone. it&amp;rsquo;s doing damage control instead of learning. However, manuals never made sese to me. In the rare occessions where I do have the patience to read through the introduction, I&amp;rsquo;d forget what I wanted to do (or how to do it) by the time I get the real stuff. Besides, manuals are usually written by the people who made the program; as such, they are written from the inside, for insiders. Certain terms and syntax make aboslutely no sense to newcomers, who find that they struggle with basic terms that the veterans spit out as if they were born into it. Indeed, if there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that I kept running into when learning Emacs is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to bother with its documentation. As helpful as it is, and as much as everyone loves to say all the help you ever want is C-h v (or a or whatever) away, it was not true for me. It is much, much easier to Google something up and find a blog post (or a YouTube video) that explains it to you in plain English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m much further ahead than where I was when I started my Hugo ordeal. I have sucessfully launched a couple of testing websites on and off Github. I have whined, complained, and whined again to anyone who would listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here we are with Hugo. I use git, and well, the site is on Github. This post was written with ox-hugo. I used Magit, but because there are so many issues I&amp;rsquo;m running into, I decided to make a decision not to use it for at least another month. It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to hold myself back, for sure. On one hand, since I&amp;rsquo;ve done WordPress for so long, I&amp;rsquo;m aching to go back to my old website where I don&amp;rsquo;t have problems learning how to create a new static page (that doesn&amp;rsquo;t show on the front page of this blog), or how exactly images work with these posts, or how can I automate the long process of saving a post and updating my Hugo website compared to the simple &amp;ldquo;click to publish&amp;rdquo;  in WordPress. I&amp;rsquo;m sure some of you are aching to tell me just how to do some of these things. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and speaking of helpful people: a big thank you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kaushalmodi&#34;&gt;Kaushal Modi&lt;/a&gt;, who kept answering my endless questions, who was there through my frustration, anywhere I went. This guy is passionate and compassionate about what he does.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - what takes so long?</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blogging/hugo-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/blogging/hugo-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve bseen following me online for the last month or so (especially on reddit) you&amp;rsquo;d know I&amp;rsquo;ve been engaged in shifting away from WordPress and into the world &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d imagine the people of in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/&#34;&gt;r/emacs&lt;/a&gt; would raise an eyebrow at the term &amp;ldquo;world of Hugo.&amp;rdquo; After all, Hugo is a relatively simple program, not a deep rabbit-hole like Emacs. Yet, it&amp;rsquo;s Hugo that got me overwhelemed, not so much Emacs. What? Really?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, it has to do with background and expectations. As a non-programmer (as in, someone who never wrote anything a bit more complicated then a few lines of shell script) Emacs was a mountain. Standing at the bottom, I gazed at the cloud shrowing its peek and told myself &amp;ldquo;well, you gotta take a first step somewhere&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; so I did. For me, that was Org-mode. As a matter of fact, at the time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know much about Emacs and how deep it can get. All I knew was that Org was cool, and I&amp;rsquo;m interested in learning more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple of months, I got a bit more comfortable with Emacs and my level of doing things with it. I am still miles away from the top, and I&amp;rsquo;m fine with that. I got Emacs to do most of what I want it to do for me at this point, which is writing these posts, my journal entries, and of course my agenda and tasks both at work and at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo, on the other hand, was meant to replace WordPress. As a person who used WordPress on and off a couple of years, I expected more or less the same thing. You know, going to my webiste online somewhere, log in with a username and password, navigate the GUI and post stuff, add plugins&amp;hellip; As such, I didn&amp;rsquo;t care for a change that much. WordPress was working more or less OK, so why change to something similar and learn things all over again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get frequent alerts that my website is down from my webhost, but I got used to shrug these off. I got it as a cheap deal, and for about $6 a month or so hosting, what do you expect? People in the Emacs reddit mentioned they see more spam from my site&amp;rsquo;s URL instead of my posts, but again, with 1 person complaining out of 10 or so, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a big deal. After all, SSL and https is for professional website that can afford it, and I am just an amatuer-ish blogger. Perhaps the biggest hurdle was Github: I knew people who use Hugo usually use Github to publish their blog, but they were all programmers. Me, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about Github or git. That was for coders, people who write scripts for a living. This is not me. I am not a porgrammer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what changed that perspective. Perhaps it was a random tutorial I saw about Git which made me realize it&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; crazy complicated. Perhaps it was the fact that someone advised me not to link to my website again if I don&amp;rsquo;t have https. Maybe it was just my inner geek, itching for a change, and WordPress was getting too familiar and too boring. Whatever it was, I took the bait, and I started doing all of it at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I watched some Lynda videos about git and read a few posts. Then, I learned more about Hugo. After that, it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/&#34;&gt;ox-hugo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lsquo;s turn (because I gotta write my posts from inside Emacs), and then it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://magit.vc/&#34;&gt;Magit&lt;/a&gt; (because I gotta use git from inside Emacs). I think I went through everything in a matter of about a month. I learned too much too fast. But that&amp;rsquo;s how I roll. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I do that to myself, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how it makes sense to go from &amp;ldquo;git is for coders&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;ALL THE THINGS,&amp;rdquo; but I do anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this attitude has terrible consequences. You learn everything on a very shallow level, which means the first tiny bump in the road sends you launching out of control. You get frustrated and you try again, just to hit another bump. Turns out, if I &lt;em&gt;learn everything&lt;/em&gt; I also expect to &lt;em&gt;know everything&lt;/em&gt; out of myself, which is of course nonsense. But not everything is futile. Knowing the big picture in advance is not a bad idea. Learning a couple of things at once make you realize how they work together, and helps you develop a mindset that is more skilled at solving specific problems. Later, when you go look at the official documents, certain things already make sense to you even though you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen them before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be it as it may, it&amp;rsquo;s not easy. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend this method to anyone. it&amp;rsquo;s doing damage control instead of learning. However, manuals never made sese to me. In the rare occessions where I do have the patience to read through the introduction, I&amp;rsquo;d forget what I wanted to do (or how to do it) by the time I get the real stuff. Besides, manuals are usually written by the people who made the program; as such, they are written from the inside, for insiders. Certain terms and syntax make aboslutely no sense to newcomers, who find that they struggle with basic terms that the veterans spit out as if they were born into it. Indeed, if there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that I kept running into when learning Emacs is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to bother with its documentation. As helpful as it is, and as much as everyone loves to say all the help you ever want is C-h v (or a or whatever) away, it was not true for me. It is much, much easier to Google something up and find a blog post (or a YouTube video) that explains it to you in plain English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m much further ahead than where I was when I started my Hugo ordeal. I have sucessfully launched a couple of testing websites on and off Github. I have whined, complained, and whined again to anyone who would listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here we are with Hugo. I use git, and well, the site is on Github. This post was written with ox-hugo. I used Magit, but because there are so many issues I&amp;rsquo;m running into, I decided to make a decision not to use it for at least another month. It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to hold myself back, for sure. On one hand, since I&amp;rsquo;ve done WordPress for so long, I&amp;rsquo;m aching to go back to my old website where I don&amp;rsquo;t have problems learning how to create a new static page (that doesn&amp;rsquo;t show on the front page of this blog), or how exactly images work with these posts, or how can I automate the long process of saving a post and updating my Hugo website compared to the simple &amp;ldquo;click to publish&amp;rdquo;  in WordPress. I&amp;rsquo;m sure some of you are aching to tell me just how to do some of these things. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and speaking of helpful people: a big thank you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kaushalmodi&#34;&gt;Kaushal Modi&lt;/a&gt;, who kept answering my endless questions, who was there through my frustration, anywhere I went. This guy is passionate and compassionate about what he does.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
