<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>privacy on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in privacy on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>privacy</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/2020-10-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/2020-10-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started researching privacy more seriously, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I was looking at is the face of a forlorn, desolate path that seems to go nowhere. I picked it up as a challenge, and within a few days, it became clear that privacy is, unfortunately, a journey of hard sacrifices to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked for help on Reddit&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/privacy/&#34;&gt;privacy community&lt;/a&gt; and I was blocked from posting because my freshly-created account specifically for this purpose was too suspicious. It was just one stop of many I&amp;rsquo;ve made in the last two months. Article after article from Medium to Lifehacker was filled with begginer tips like &amp;ldquo;use VPN,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;search with Duck Duck Go.&amp;rdquo; As I kept digging deeper, looking for more specifics and advanced techniques, the more it seemed that the internet I use every day suddenly had an end. A wall.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/2020-10-26.gif&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything on the screen had a dictated sense of purpose. I was supposed to follow the &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; answers laid in front of me: buy a visa gift card with your credit card; submit your phone number to get a discount; surrender your verified email address to chat with an agent. Not a single website gave additional options. Everywhere I looked, I had to give up a piece of my privacy or to lie and hope for the best. I chose the latter option whenever I could. The feeling that I&amp;rsquo;m doing something wrong intensified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s the loneliness. I haven&amp;rsquo;t logged into Facebook for years, living with most of my friends and past co-workers behind. I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped using Twitter last year, and with it, I stopped following trends and celebrities in my industry. Most recently, I stopped using Instagram and lost touch with those who liked my photos, a window to the outside world especially during the pandemic. On the other hand, getting in touch with me became more difficult since I insist on less popular apps that no one wants to download. When I try to explain why, it often feels like I&amp;rsquo;m speaking a different language even with those close to me the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems to be the price for privacy. I am almost at a breaking point and I&amp;rsquo;ve only started. I understand now why there so little &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; information about true privacy: Those who stay out of the familiar platforms live in the shadows by default. It&amp;rsquo;s not that they try to hide, they just do what they can do to not to sell their lives away, which means they can&amp;rsquo;t reach us or we them. You can&amp;rsquo;t Google them up, friend them on Facebook, Follow them on Twitter&amp;hellip; So they don&amp;rsquo;t exist to us, automatically-suspected criminal of the dark web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much of what we do, what we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;, is not even ours to share but instead borrowed, hosted somewhere unknown to us, supplied only if we sign an agreement to give it up. And we don&amp;rsquo;t care to know. After all, when was the last time you read Facebook&amp;rsquo;s TOS? Twitter&amp;rsquo;s? Gmail&amp;rsquo;s? Apple&amp;rsquo;s? Instagram&amp;rsquo;s?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I could tell you this is all just a cheap Matrix ripoff. I wish I could go see a therapist who&amp;rsquo;d assure me I&amp;rsquo;m exaggerating. The problem is is that I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; better. I can&amp;rsquo;t unlearn what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, unread what I&amp;rsquo;ve read. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;m figuring out how to bend the rules just enough to be more than a sheepish user.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Ease of Use vs Indepence</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200218/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200218/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems like hating on Google (or Apple, or Amazon, or whatever tech giant) is the hip thing to do these days. I want to raise a couple of points to argue otherwise, and explain how I try to find balance in a monopoly-driven world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been running Linux full time at home &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191208/&#34;&gt;since last December&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;m not looking back. I love the level of control I have, the lack of nagging updates with the potential of breaking everything, the transparency in the application I use through the command line, and the overall productivity I get out of it. With the exception of a few very specific applications, I miss nothing from the Windows days&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I can manage my life without Google. Not yet, not anytime soon, and I think that even if I had the choice, I won&amp;rsquo;t really want to. The same is true for Amazon: it&amp;rsquo;s a giant online retailer that chews away on mom-and-pop shops, draining local business dry while more college folks move in and older ethnic groups move out. Sounds sinister, but I&amp;rsquo;m not in a rush to stop using Amazon. As a matter of fact, since I moved to this neighborhood, I started using it even more and I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m going to stop any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could say I&amp;rsquo;m part of the problem and I won&amp;rsquo;t disagree with you. I rather use Google maps instead of relying on hand-written instructions. I rather order something online and have it in my hands two days later than to spend half an hour in a messy pharmacy, look for a product they don&amp;rsquo;t carry, and buy a replacement for two bucks more just because I live in New York City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no lack of smartphones out there that are not made by Google, but there&amp;rsquo;s only one phone that&amp;rsquo;s good enough &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; cheap&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; enough &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; has consistent security patches &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; is not one of those 6.5 inches monsters that I can&amp;rsquo;t use comfortably. There are few Linux phones available in different stages of development, mostly expensive prototypes that cannot compete with the apps on Google&amp;rsquo;s Play store. I&amp;rsquo;d be one of the first ones to jump ship when it will make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same argument goes for other platforms I use, such as Instagram. There are free other independent options, but they don&amp;rsquo;t come close to the exposure Instagram provides. Medium is another example: the exposure goes far beyond what Duck Duck Go brings up when tech folks look something related to this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what can be done? What&amp;rsquo;s the fine line between Usability and Idealism? There are many people asking this question these days. I don&amp;rsquo;t really have a good answer, besides that I take things personally: the more of myself I invest in a certain thing, the more immersive it should be and the higher quality (to my standards) it needs to be. This is not a die-hard principle, but a guideline that seems to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take this website, for example. It&amp;rsquo;s a personal blog. Having it on a platform like Hugo-Go and be able to mess with its internal parts is important. Having it integrating directly with org-mode, which I use every day for my most personal things, makes sense. Another simple example is my coffee. My coffee morning ritual is highly personal, involving my espresso machine and froth. This means I enjoy taking the time to identify a local roaster who date-stamps each pound of espresso beans I get. I know where his shop is because I was there. I even know his dog&amp;rsquo;s name.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200218_1.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; is the kind of thing I want to imagine when I drink my coffee at home in the morning. It&amp;rsquo;s not the same when I drink the coffee at work, or at any other huge chain-stores. Nothing can recreate what this coffee and the picture I took above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are areas that require improvement. Again, take my photos. They are very personal, yet, I give them away to Facebook and Amazon by hosting them on Instagram because of the exposure I need. I give up the quality and the personal connection for a service (in this case, reaching other people). When there&amp;rsquo;s a conflict like this, I promote my own platform over the public one. In this example, only photos that are a month old will show up on Instagram; the resolution is already horrible, so if someone wants to see the real thing, they&amp;rsquo;d have to come to my website, and so on. Medium and this website have a similar relationship: only old posts that are worth larger exposure the second time around get pushed to Medium, definitely not all of them. I feel this is a compromise I can live with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same can be said about my MacOS days. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Macs for personal usage and I keep using them at work. I have a Windows virtual box for when I need to work from home or need to use a Windows program. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the Google Pixel &lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt; line, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the Google Pixel flagship line, which seems to be expensive just because iPhones are expensive. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From LastPass to KeePass</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/lastpass-to-keepass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/lastpass-to-keepass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using LastPass for the last 5 years and been happy with it. I recommended it to friends, family, and co-workers. I tried to sell it through its convenience: once set up, LastPass auto-fills user and password fields, and can even log you into a website directly. LastPass also creates complicated passwords automatically and is available on every major browser, iPhones and Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it seems like even LastPass&amp;rsquo;s time has come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we know, Convenience usually comes at the price of security. LastPass auto-fill is quick and effective but also makes it very easy for someone else to grab your laptop, find your bank website in your history, and log int with your saved credentials.  To resolve this issue, LastPass has a couple of built-in options such as logging you out after a certain amount of time or logging off when the browser is closed. There features need to be activated on each new installation of LastPass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So LastPass was an obvious choice for my mom&amp;rsquo;s new chromebook. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d set her up with a new account and share passwords with her directly. I wanted her to learn to trust the app and starts creating new secure passwords instead of using the same two or three she&amp;rsquo;s been using for years. But instead, I discovered a problem.  there were problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The option to log off automatically if chrome is closed was ignored. I&amp;rsquo;ve checked and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Lastpass/comments/aozro2/lastpass%5Fauto%5Flogout%5Fdoesnt%5Fwork%5Fout%5Fon/&#34;&gt;asked other users on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, but all I got is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lastpass.com/support.php?cmd=showfaq&amp;amp;id=3846&#34;&gt;generic troubleshooting advice&lt;/a&gt; to make sure Chrome completely exists for the auto logoff to work. Exiting Chrome is possible on Windows, Mac, and Linux (for which this guide was written) but, as it turned out, is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; possible on a Chromebook. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.google.com/chromebook/answer/6309225?hl=en&#34;&gt;summoned the ChromeOS task manager&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;code&gt;shift+esc&lt;/code&gt; or more recently &lt;code&gt;search+esc&lt;/code&gt; (this is different than the Chrome browser&amp;rsquo;s task manager, which is accessible from inside Chrome) and saw that Chrome was still running even after I exited the app. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t force chrome to quit either: The button to do so was grayed out when I had Chrome highlighted on the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That meant that the only thing protecting someone from accessing all your passwords is your Google Password with lockscreen enabled. Perhaps i&amp;rsquo;m paranoid, but for me, that&amp;rsquo;s not nearly enough. I disabled the extension and asked myself these two questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it worth using LastPass over Chrome&amp;rsquo;s built in password manger?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is LastPass really a good option to securely save passwords?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The the first answer is &amp;ldquo;not really.&amp;rdquo; If you&amp;rsquo;re a LastPass power user, who have the application on your phone and use a family plan (which allows you to share passwords), then yes, LastPass gives you more features. However, Chrome&amp;rsquo;s Password Manager now allows you to create secure passwords and sync them with your Google Profile, which means you will have access to those anywhere you log in including your Phone. Since on a Chromebook your security is already handled by Google, there&amp;rsquo;s not much sense to start a new account with LastPass, which basically does the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second question is harder to answer. LastPass is a company that makes its business to secure passwords all day every day, and they have a great product. They are, overall, pretty transparent with their security breaches when they happen and apply patches and fixes very fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, LastPass&#39; browser extension is also its weakest point. To be fair, the same can be said for &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; password manager that has an extension built into the browser. Various vulnerabilities have been listed before and &lt;a href=&#34;https://lastpass.com/support.php?cmd=showfaq&amp;amp;id=11012&#34;&gt;some were listed by LastPass&lt;/a&gt; themselves. If you&amp;rsquo;re really concerned about the security of your passwords, you should not use a browser extension. However,if I am hard-pressed between choosing Chrome&amp;rsquo;s built in password solution and a third party&amp;rsquo;s solution that is built into Chrome, I will go with Chrome&amp;rsquo;s built-in solution because it&amp;rsquo;s native to the application and hence (hopefully) more secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But. The real answer here is that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use a browser extension &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;. And that&amp;rsquo;s what I do these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite solution is to use good ol&#39; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KeePass&#34;&gt;KeyPass&lt;/a&gt;, which has been around for about 15 years. I like KeyPass for a couple of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a standalone program with  a simple GUI and flexibility. It works and looks better than LastPass&amp;rsquo;s more complicated controls and does not relay on cookies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only person with my passwords is me, which makes me sleep better at night. This has been my general trend since I started using Linux. It&amp;rsquo;s not about privacy and less about security, a proud feeling of owning my on data, something I feel we don&amp;rsquo;t do enough these days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KeyPass is old, open sourced, free, and probably not going anywhere. I&amp;rsquo;d like to say the same thing about LastPass, but companies such as these are constantly get eaten by greedy corporation that inject them with crap like social network integration and ads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With it&amp;rsquo;s combination of using key files and different ciphers (at least via plugins), it feels solid and secure. Not that LastPass security is not good enough. It should also be mentioned that LastPass has two-factor authentication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because KeyPass doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a browser extension (at least not out of the box), I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.semicomplete.com/projects/xdotool/&#34;&gt;xdotool&lt;/a&gt; to auto-type passwords into websites&#39; text fields. The workflow: I click the user field on a website, Alt+Tab back to KeyPass, hit the auto-type shortcut, and watch KeyPass putting in my credentials as if I&amp;rsquo;m typing them from memory. Because I can customize the auto-input macro (KeyPass2 and up), eventually this makes it even more reliable than LastPass&#39; auto-fill feature, which sometimes doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well with fancy animated menus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LastPass is another tool I didn&amp;rsquo;t think about replacing when I transitioned into Linux, and for a long time, I kept using it in Linux as well. When I switched away from Chrome and stopped being logged into Google all the time, Chrome&amp;rsquo;s extensions stayed behind. Like many other products (Gmail, Google Docs, Dropbox&amp;hellip;) I&amp;rsquo;m slowly but surely finding good open source options which are often better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Removing Company Software</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/remove-company-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/remove-company-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When someone asks what we install on their personal devices (BYOD laptops), I usually give them the abridged version. People rarely care about details. Every now and then though, someone is a bit concerned and asks for more information. Stuff like why do we need software that tells us details about their hardware, how do we use it, and of course, if we can view their personal data. My answer to that last question is &amp;ldquo;we can if we want to.&amp;rdquo; It bothers me this question comes only from so few individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, A client gave me her under-performing BYOD laptop for general cleanup before switching it back for strictly personal use. She knew about the different bits of software we install because she asked me when she first brought it in. She was curious and worried about her privacy and she got the full story from me. I have no doubt that the conversation was motivating enough for her to come back for a cleanup &amp;ndash; and for the right reasons. I dare hope that she sought me out specifically to clean her laptop because she trusted me a bit more after that conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many people leave us with their personal laptop without ever bothering checking in with us to make sure our software is removed? A few of them will take the time to wipe their laptops, but so many more, the majority for sure, will never bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among our most intrusive software is an Anti Virus client that dials home to our management environment and an inventory management software that gives us full details about the hardware and software installed on the device. We also effectively have root privileges on BYOD devices, basically a backdoor on their system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing unique about what we do. The same practices are followed by virtually every respectful IT company that deals with BYODs. Nothing we do have sinister intentions, and I trust everyone on my team not to abuse root privileges on BYOD devices which are often one of the most personal things a person owns. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean our clients should just trust us blindly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Removing Company Software</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/remove_company_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/remove_company_software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When someone asks what we install on their personal devices (BYOD laptops), I usually give them the abridged version. People rarely care about details. Every now and then though, someone is a bit concerned and asks for more information. Stuff like why do we need software that tells us details about their hardware, how do we use it, and of course, if we can view their personal data. My answer to that last question is &amp;ldquo;we can if we want to.&amp;rdquo; It bothers me this question comes only from so few individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, A client gave me her under-performing BYOD laptop for general cleanup before switching it back for strictly personal use. She knew about the different bits of software we install because she asked me when she first brought it in. She was curious and worried about her privacy and she got the full story from me. I have no doubt that the conversation was motivating enough for her to come back for a cleanup &amp;ndash; and for the right reasons. I dare hope that she sought me out specifically to clean her laptop because she trusted me a bit more after that conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many people leave us with their personal laptop without ever bothering checking in with us to make sure our software is removed? A few of them will take the time to wipe their laptops, but so many more, the majority for sure, will never bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among our most intrusive software is an Anti Virus client that dials home to our management environment and an inventory management software that gives us full details about the hardware and software installed on the device. We also effectively have root privileges on BYOD devices, basically a backdoor on their system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing unique about what we do. The same practices are followed by virtually every respectful IT company that deals with BYODs. Nothing we do have sinister intentions, and I trust everyone on my team not to abuse root privileges on BYOD devices which are often one of the most personal things a person owns. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean our clients should just trust us blindly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
