<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>emacs on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in emacs on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic SSH Security</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/basic-ssh-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/basic-ssh-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They say a picture is worth a thousand words:&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/basic-ssh-security.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is my SSH server&amp;rsquo;s log, and this looks like a good time to talk about basic ssh server security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Emacs and Chutzpah</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/of-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Says &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jamierubin.net/2019/06/13/writing-in-the-digital-age-an-introduction/#comments&#34;&gt;Jamie T. Rubin&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;As a writer, I naturally want to spend my time writing. More and more I see tools getting in the way of writing. If that wasn’t the case, why do so many tools now add a “focus” or “distraction-free” mode? What choices can I make to simplify my writing ecosystem?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My answer to that, considering the theme of this blog and how I&amp;rsquo;m writing it,  is obvious. But the question is going deeper than that, and so should be the answer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Org Capture Templates - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-template-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-template-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took a long unplanned break from writing about my Templates because of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/blogging/css-updates-1/&#34;&gt;CSS changes&lt;/a&gt; I worked on and the complications with Magit. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say these are now behind me, and that I gained another grain of confidence using Magit and knowing git, but this is a post for yet another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the last two templates are rather short, I&amp;rsquo;m putting them both here together. Here we go:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Org Capture Templates - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-template-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-template-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was happy to see part one of this series generated interest on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/orgmode/comments/agxe8n/my%5Forgmode%5Ftemplates%5Fpart%5Fone%5Fany%5Finterest%5Fin%5Fmore/&#34;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;. One of the things I love about Org-mode (and Emacs) is this passion among its user and the thirst to learn more from each other. I believe one of the major reasons for that is Org-mode&amp;rsquo;s complexity: there are so many options, it &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be personalized by its users&amp;rsquo; needs. Org-mode is esaily the most personal tool I&amp;rsquo;ve used in a while. Every time I read something Org-mode related somewhere else it&amp;rsquo;s as if I&amp;rsquo;m invited over for a discussion over a cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Org Capture Templates - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-template-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/org-capture-template-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.social/@emsenn&#34;&gt;emsenn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.social/@emsenn/101387457090836368&#34;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; Org-mode users for their day-to-day capture templates in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.technology&#34;&gt;technology Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; (which you should join and follow if you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet). I was happy to reply and figured it would be intesting to dig into my capture templates. I started writing this post explaining all of my templates, but then realized I&amp;rsquo;m starting to edit out details because the post is getting too long. So instead, I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain each template at a time. Hopefully you find this interesting!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Windows</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/emacs-windows-managment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/emacs-windows-managment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In his 5th Emacs podcast, &lt;a href=&#34;https://emacscast.org/episode%5F5/&#34;&gt;Rakhim&lt;/a&gt; discusses the difficulties of windows management in Emacs. I agree with him. Emacs&amp;rsquo; Windows are a pain. It was probably one of the longest pet peeves I had with the program, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until this podcast that I realized that I&amp;rsquo;m much better off than I used to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libre and Clothes</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/libre-and-clothes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/libre-and-clothes/</guid>
      <description>When I write, I live in Emacs (with the awesome Solorized theme) inside Org-Mode.
With time, I found that Org has already made me more effienet writer and note taker. I write notes in every meeting now, rather it&amp;rsquo;s my &amp;ldquo;turn&amp;rdquo; or not. I write notes as I work, about every solution and every problem I&amp;rsquo;m facing. I write first thing in the morning, usually about org-related thoughts I had as I wake up, over a cup of Sumatra cofee (little almond milk, one pack of sugar).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>