<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blogging on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/blogging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blogging on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring CSS</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/2020-07-14/</link>
      <pubDate>16160-07-07</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/2020-07-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a popular saying in IT: if you receive no comments about a project you just finished, you know you&amp;rsquo;ve done your job right. The latest commit to TAONAW is one of the biggest I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done, but I hope you&amp;rsquo;d barely notice anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the issues I wanted to fix in TAONAW was the mobile layout. The original theme, &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/hyde/&#34;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt;, comes with a narrow theme variant aimed at smartphones and tablets. On TAONAW, it was always a broken mess of inherited CSS rules coming from the wide (desktop screens) variant, which was what I always focused on. The narrow theme became even worse after I had my logo made. The logo covered the sidebar almost completely, making navigating the site on smartphones practically impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve toyed with my CSS here and there, but I knew I need to go deep to fix the narrow theme. The different CSS tricks and hacks I used made the site work through workarounds, but overall, it was still a mess. This week I finally got some time off for serious refactoring&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you narrow the browser&amp;rsquo;s window now (go ahead, do it) it will switch to &amp;ldquo;smartphone&amp;rdquo; mode when you reach 800 pixels wide. I tested the site on both my iPhone and Android and the site looks as intended on both&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The logo, which now fits better on the wide version next to the title, also sits well at the lower right corner on narrow screens. Shrink the screen more and the logo will slide left to accomodate (eventually it will overlap the text of the navigation bar, but I don&amp;rsquo;t believe there&amp;rsquo;s a screen &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; narrow intended for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CSS (in the hyde.css file) code now exhibits common code for both themes at the top, and then under it, the wide version followed by the narrow version. For example, The title font for the site is the same for both themes, so it will be defined at the top; however, the font is a different size on the wide version (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3schools.com/CSSref/css%5Funits.asp&#34;&gt;4em&lt;/a&gt;) than it is on the narrow version (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3schools.com/CSSref/css%5Funits.asp&#34;&gt;3em&lt;/a&gt;). This is one refactoring example of many. I also took out large chunks of unnecessary code that came with the original theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many examples I can point out and expand on, but I won&amp;rsquo;t get into these right now. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, the site and the theme is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jarss/TAONAW&#34;&gt;availble to all on github&lt;/a&gt;, where it&amp;rsquo;s been since day one. For me, the biggest satisfaction was learning all the new CSS &amp;ldquo;stuff&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;rdquo; and having an organized CSS I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with to keep fixing and adjusting the site in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually reserved for &amp;ldquo;serious code,&amp;rdquo; after working a couple of hours on CSS, I think the term describes well what I&amp;rsquo;ve done here. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like other projects of similar size, you only see additional issues after you&amp;rsquo;re done. A few tweaks to the narrow theme still need to be done, but now it will be much easier to get to them. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think of it, CSS is immensely useful. It can be used to present anything (through a form of an HTML page) rather it&amp;rsquo;s my wiki built-in Emacs org-mode or a document following a theme turned into PDF. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Update 2020-02</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200301/</link>
      <pubDate>9090-03-03</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200301/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I ironed out a couple of CSS issues that popped up since I updated Hugo and implemented a few navigation and new page. Why and how&amp;hellip; Coming up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;posts-fonts-read-more&#34;&gt;Posts Fonts, Read More&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Merriweather&#34;&gt;Merriweahter&lt;/a&gt;. This font looks better when smaller, which is what I was after. Overall font size was decreased and space between lines increased. This was done to improve how the site looks and to resolve the footnote notation issue, where the footnote indicator pushes the line further up than the rest. The &amp;ldquo;Read More&amp;rdquo; link was changed to clear, better looking down arrow, supported by &lt;a href=&#34;https://fontawesome.com/&#34;&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes-changes&#34;&gt;Footnotes Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Footnotes indicators are now smaller and colored in dark red (same as title) to increase visibility despite the smaller size. The footnote back link arrows aws decreased in size and colored red as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sidebar-changes&#34;&gt;Sidebar Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leading text (&amp;ldquo;a blog by Josh Rollins: Tech, Life, and the Stuff in Between&amp;rdquo;) has been removed: the text just restates the obvious function of the site. A new page was added (&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/taonaw/&#34;&gt;TAONAW&lt;/a&gt;), a link to it and to the about page about me were added now that there&amp;rsquo;s more room. Popular Topics count increased to 5 (only topics that repeat more than 5 times show now, the rest are uner &amp;ldquo;All Topics&amp;rdquo;). The font for these sections was changed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Righteous&#34;&gt;Righteous&lt;/a&gt;, same as the title font.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Update</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191229/</link>
      <pubDate>29290-12-12</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191229/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/2019-12-29_09-24.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a habit chaining in org-mode for this blog which shows me I&amp;rsquo;m passed due on updating. 4 days, to be exact. I&amp;rsquo;m rushing to update with this little post as I&amp;rsquo;m sitting here gulping coffee in my boxers before a shower I need to take&amp;hellip; so bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a post about photography for over a week. It proved to be challenging to put together because every time I put it back on my screen, there are updates and more things I want to talk about. Over the past month, there were a few good points I discussed with different people which I wanted to include, and I just don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have the time, which is the excuse I hate the most. Usually, it just means you need a slightly different angle to think of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve been reconsidering and I&amp;rsquo;d like to work on a video again, recording some of my thoughts. After all, part of getting the camera was recording videos and getting better at these &amp;ndash; not to mention that I can use visual examples. So I hope to get to that even tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I just wanted to update and tell you all I&amp;rsquo;m still here, still alive and kicking, just behind. Thanks for sticking around!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Updates Posts</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/blog-updates-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>14140-10-10</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/blog-updates-posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I wrote the &lt;a href=&#34;http://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/blog-updates-2/&#34;&gt;October Updates&lt;/a&gt; post, I came to realize that having a &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s new&amp;rdquo; kind of post regularly is a good idea. Usually, updating one thing causes me to want another change or to break something that worked. These are learning experiences that I believe could be beneficial other bloggers out there (I know they are to me). For those interested, here are some of my thoughts on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed my general plans after passing the Security+ exam on &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.tube/videos/watch/697084c3-6e9b-435c-b5e2-7647a9d9c30f&#34;&gt;my video&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike what I believe is the generic direction most folks would take at this point, like advancing their career, going further into information security, higher salary, etc., I wanted to take a step back and focus more on my website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desire comes from the recognition that studying for the exam put many other things I wanted to explore on hold due to lack of time and wanting to get this exam over with. Toward the end of my studying, I even stopped caring if I pass or not. I just wanted to be done. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have this attitude toward my interests, but this is what happens when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to push through a deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoy writing and explaining technology, so my website is usually a natural playground for constant development. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken large steps forward with Hugo and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/&#34;&gt;ox-hugo&lt;/a&gt;, which allows me to write my post directly from my favorite writing environment: org-mode. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/hugo-beginnings/&#34;&gt;Since then&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a few bits and pieces here and there, mostly to CSS and layout (I call these &amp;ldquo;cosmetics&amp;rdquo;) and some functionality with Disqus for comments and tags to categorize my posts. All of these, to one extent or another, were new or introduced a higher level of complexity that I&amp;rsquo;ve dealt with in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going back to work on my website was slow at start, but quickly became more involved when I encountered a few problems. First with simple CSS issues, later with Hugo, these issues had me looking more critically into my site, understand Hugo and its components, and remind myself how things worked. Hugo is a very powerful tool with a simple way of doing things, but it&amp;rsquo;s not always easy to get into its mindset. Like a skill that requires honing, if you don&amp;rsquo;t work at it often, you lose the sharpness of it. It&amp;rsquo;s not a matter of writing how to do things down either: this state of mind is different. It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to follow instructions blindly to get things to work, it&amp;rsquo;s another to understand &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; it works and why. To me, this is a good feeling, a certain &amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; when something clicks, a good motivation to keep on learning. It is one of the reasons why I enjoy working in IT and constantly be exposed to new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The October Update post (and those coming up in the future) is dynamic. As I work on new features, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain what I&amp;rsquo;ve done and how. I hope to get more engagement and ideas for those reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Updates: 2019-10</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/blog-updates-2/</link>
      <pubDate>12120-10-10</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/blog-updates-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been fairly active with the website this month, but most of the changes are behind the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tags-to-topics&#34;&gt;Tags to Topics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;tags&amp;rdquo; title changed to &amp;ldquo;Popular Topics&amp;rdquo;. This list now displays any topics that have been featured at least 3 times on TAONAW from the highest to lowest. A new &amp;ldquo;All Topics&amp;rdquo; link at the bottom leads to the tag page (which I need to change to &amp;ldquo;topics&amp;rdquo; now - work in progress) to view all the other topics, sorted by latest addition. I am planning to add an introduction the page later on, inspired a bit by &lt;a href=&#34;https://karl-voit.at/&#34;&gt;Karl Voit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Sections&amp;rdquo; portion of the sidebar &lt;del&gt;will be&lt;/del&gt;  was eliminated. More personal posts are now tagged as &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/life/&#34;&gt;life&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;. As a preparation to go sections-less, the tags were cleaned and condensed to reflect broader topics. Popular topics that emerge will receive their own  tags as they become more popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmetics&#34;&gt;Cosmetics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sidebar &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jarss/TAONAW/blob/master/static/css/hyde.css&#34;&gt;is now 14rem wide&lt;/a&gt; to contain the &amp;ldquo;Popular Topics&amp;rdquo; heading without a break. This caused the words &amp;ldquo;Art Of&amp;rdquo; in the red title at the sidebar to come together, something I &lt;del&gt;intend to&lt;/del&gt; changed. I learned that it&amp;rsquo;s probably smarted to increase the spaces between words in the title using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3schools.com/cssref/pr%5Ftext%5Fword-spacing.asp&#34;&gt;word-spacing&lt;/a&gt; CSS property instead of changing the width of the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post titles have a new font, &lt;a href=&#34;https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Montserrat&#34;&gt;Montserrat&lt;/a&gt;. If you don&amp;rsquo;t see this font, please let me know. This change was implemented previously, but later deleted by mistake in the CSS file. This is a Google Font that is enabled for free using the head_fonts.html in Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colors for the tags under the titles and the &amp;ldquo;Read More&amp;rdquo; links on the main page were changed to the same red as the Title&amp;rsquo;s red. Other links in the posts and remain the same&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixing-the-homepage&#34;&gt;Fixing the Homepage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My homepage, which displays a list of summaries of posts, broke after a recent Hugo update. That was because of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/news/0.58.0-relnotes/&#34;&gt;specific Hugo change in version .58&lt;/a&gt;.  This was fixed after a day of diving into Hugo, something I should probably do more often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;trimming-down-the-fat&#34;&gt;Trimming Down the fat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, there are a lot of unused files inside the builds of this website. For example, when I changed my tagging and got rid of the old tags, it turned out the old tags still have HTML files inside the site. The original theme I used to build this site is still stored intact inside the theme folders, &lt;del&gt;and I don&amp;rsquo;t really need it&lt;/del&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. There are other examples, probably one of the known side effects of having a static website that builds HTML webpages for everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearing the old files is tricky, and I ended up deleting files I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I need until I tried to publish the site again. Not a big problem since everything is backed up many times over, but something I can live without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;netifly-coming-soon&#34;&gt;Netifly - Coming Soon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Kaushal Modi, my Hugo mentor &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.technology/@kaushalmodi/102949264377765642&#34;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt;, the answer to all these annoyances is Netifly. I knew about this service previously, but this time because of a specific issue&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I had with git, I learned that Netifly bypasses the entire build Hugo creates. That is, it reads the md files directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the md files are created on the fly for me thanks to ox-hugo, it&amp;rsquo;s almost as if I have a dynamic website. I would still need to push the changes to github, but Netifly would take care of everything from there. No more old dead HTML files or forgetting to build my website before pushing to github - something I do more often than I&amp;rsquo;d like to, for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting a website to build on Netifly is pretty easy, but I&amp;rsquo;ll need to change the DNS records to point to Netifly&amp;rsquo;s servers instead of github. That&amp;rsquo;s not a hard thing to do, but there&amp;rsquo;s a chance something would break and my website will be down, and I&amp;rsquo;m running out of time as I&amp;rsquo;m writing this. I will wait on Netifly a bit longer, but this is a change that is pretty sure to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-section&#34;&gt;About Section&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve added an &lt;a href=&#34;http://joshrollinswrites.com/about/&#34;&gt;about section&lt;/a&gt; to the blog. Creating a section that uses the posts&amp;rsquo; template was a learning experience since Hugo&amp;rsquo;s default is to treat all sections&amp;rsquo; main pages (index.html pages) as a &amp;ldquo;list&amp;rdquo; template. To resolve this, I needed to use &lt;code&gt;layout: &amp;quot;single&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/front-matter/&#34;&gt;front-matter&lt;/a&gt; for the index page. In ox-hugo, this is done by adding a ~ &lt;code&gt;:EXPORT_HUGO_LAYOUT: single&lt;/code&gt; property under the header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure how to fit the link to the about section in the sidebar. For now, it&amp;rsquo;s just a linked from my name in the site&amp;rsquo;s description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was harder than it should have been&amp;hellip; these links are nested inside a class which is also nested inside a class. The right syntax in CSS is &lt;code&gt;[parent-class] [child-class] [html-tag]&lt;/code&gt; with spacing being important: three spaces, no more. However, because my CSS was messy, the rules I&amp;rsquo;ve added were re-defined again later in the CSS file; I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware I called the same elements in two different places. As it turns out, cleaning your code (CSS, bash, or whatever) is important - and so as adding comments. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I tried to publish the site to Netifly (see below) it turned out I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; need the original theme of the site. I am unsure why at this point, since all the essential files I use are stored outside of the theme&amp;rsquo;s folder. I believe this has to do with the site&amp;rsquo;s theme setting which specifies the theme&amp;rsquo;s name, which probably points to that folder. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I included the word &amp;ldquo;hugo&amp;rdquo; in my git ignore file. This was because I used to store a hugo binary in the site&amp;rsquo;s root folder, because a newer version was not available on Linux Mint, at the time. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Updates</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/css-updates-1/</link>
      <pubDate>2020-02-02</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/css-updates-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About some CSS Updates&amp;hellip; and why I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted in the last two weeks or so. (Changes are now complete!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I started making some changes for my current Hugo theme, &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/hyde/&#34;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt;. This was after I tried out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/hermit/&#34;&gt;Hermit&lt;/a&gt; theme and found out the hard way that my site is already &amp;ldquo;committed&amp;rdquo; to Hyde. Some of my customizations did not work well in Hermit and required more tweaking, while other parts of the theme didn&amp;rsquo;t look as good to me as they did on first impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead of changing a theme I started tweaking my current one and got myself lost between the branches of Git. Going in, I knew the changes I&amp;rsquo;m working on need more time than I could commit to in one sitting. Creating another branch seemed to be the way to go. Things got out of hand when I realized I never started a new branch. I was working on my master branch, which was now out of sync with the one on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find the above confusing &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s fine. The problem was that I was in the same boat as you are now, scratching my head and going &amp;ldquo;huh?&amp;rdquo; And the more I struggled, the bigger mess I&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, folks like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kaushalmodi&#34;&gt;Kaushalmodi&lt;/a&gt; exist. I don&amp;rsquo;t know where I would be without his help. Not on a Hugo site using Git, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a couple of things from him and the experience this time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://magit.vc/&#34;&gt;Magit&lt;/a&gt; can be very helpful to get back on track. That&amp;rsquo;s because it gives you sort of a road map to your project. You cay see the branches and then &lt;em&gt;go up and down the list using the arrow keys to choose the right location&lt;/em&gt;. For the first time, I saw the benefit of doing that because of the mess I was in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a whole menu of options is a question mark away, and everything has a hotkey. Magit was something I stayed away from in the past because I&amp;rsquo;m still scared of Git. After my last experience tough, I should keep using Magit for my work on this site. Magit is more effective and visual, and to me, the later is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will babble some more about my tweaks and CSS as I work on things. I will keep updates in this category (&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/blogging/&#34;&gt;Blogging&lt;/a&gt;) so you can follow up, or ignore them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;changes-now-merged--2019-02-06&#34;&gt;Changes now merged (2019-02-06)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completed some initial changes to the CSS and merged with back with my main site version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of you who understand git won&amp;rsquo;t think much of it: all I did was marge a branch. Those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t understand git won&amp;rsquo;t think of it at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me however, this is quite a big deal. I have successfully finished my first merge, in Magit none-the-less, after implementing changes on another branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;changes-implemented&#34;&gt;Changes implemented&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the complaints I got about my current layout is the width of the sidebar to the left. It takes a lot of space, and for people who like to work with small screens, this was very annoying. The other issues I found was that this theme has three layout versions (we can call them extra wide, wide, and narrow). They were also indicated in ems and rems in the CSS, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to screen width, I prefer to use pixels. So the site now has two versions: more than 800px and less than 800px. I will tweak with these some more (I think 600 as a max is better). The sidebar was tweaked to be narrower, as well as the site&amp;rsquo;s title font.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I think I will turn my attention to the navigation links themselves (under Topics) and make them more obvious with pure CSS; I have no intention of uploading fancy images. I also want to break the empty white at the right of the content in a way that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it all look so empty. We will see what happens there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything looks off to you, please let me know in the comments! Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Hugo - Full Time</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>5050-12-12</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PayPal informed me that the host of my WordPress blog is charging me for another $80 or so for the next year. The very next day, tumblr &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/231885248-Sensitive-content&#34;&gt;decided to shoot itself in the head&lt;/a&gt; (rather than the leg, if you ask me). It was good to be reminded to not trust cloud services for creative content - like my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-issues-with-my-host&#34;&gt;The Issues With my Host&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current host sucks. My WordPress blog continuously goes offline, so much so that I had to mute the alerts I got because they overwhelmed my inbox. My connection issues never got resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another major issue with that website was the lack of https (this is not my host fault, actually, it&amp;rsquo;s just yet another thing you need to buy) and the constant spam I got on the website. People would go to my link and find a totally different website trying to sell them something. That issue was not resolved either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were other technical issues, from WordPress not functioning right due to database corruptions (the host had an automatic set up process), to my domain not being resolved correctly. In the past, such issues would die out in the first month or two when I switch to a new host &amp;ndash; but not this time. This time, as soon as I got the notification of renewal from PayPal, I immediately asked for cancellation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-work-to-be-done&#34;&gt;More Work to be Done&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more work to do on this website. I am still not happy with it, and I believe my WordPress blog overall looked better still. But it is up to me to make this place better with my own set of growing skills. CSS, ox-Hugo, Go, and of course, the quality (and quantity) what I write matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also not entirely happy with the blog hosted on GitHub, which is now owned by Microsoft. It&amp;rsquo;s no difference than Tumblr being bought out by Yahoo. I need to move to an actual host with a more liberal point of view about sexual content. Unfortunately, in this world of ours, this means I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a host that is OK with Pornography. They have to include everything in one blanket statement so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to sort out in courts, in case someone gets offended. But I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go down that hole right now, there&amp;rsquo;s a whole lot of it, more than enough, on the internet right now with people freaking out about Tumblr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s the solution&amp;hellip;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe AWS (Amazon hosting service) might be it for now. I find it hard to believe they&amp;rsquo;d bother chasing me if I mention a sexual encounter or show a picture of a breast. Still, even AWS is not a safe haven. Hmmm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - what takes so long?</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/hugo-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>4040-10-10</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/hugo-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve bseen following me online for the last month or so (especially on reddit) you&amp;rsquo;d know I&amp;rsquo;ve been engaged in shifting away from WordPress and into the world &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d imagine the people of in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/&#34;&gt;r/emacs&lt;/a&gt; would raise an eyebrow at the term &amp;ldquo;world of Hugo.&amp;rdquo; After all, Hugo is a relatively simple program, not a deep rabbit-hole like Emacs. Yet, it&amp;rsquo;s Hugo that got me overwhelemed, not so much Emacs. What? Really?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, it has to do with background and expectations. As a non-programmer (as in, someone who never wrote anything a bit more complicated then a few lines of shell script) Emacs was a mountain. Standing at the bottom, I gazed at the cloud shrowing its peek and told myself &amp;ldquo;well, you gotta take a first step somewhere&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; so I did. For me, that was Org-mode. As a matter of fact, at the time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know much about Emacs and how deep it can get. All I knew was that Org was cool, and I&amp;rsquo;m interested in learning more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple of months, I got a bit more comfortable with Emacs and my level of doing things with it. I am still miles away from the top, and I&amp;rsquo;m fine with that. I got Emacs to do most of what I want it to do for me at this point, which is writing these posts, my journal entries, and of course my agenda and tasks both at work and at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo, on the other hand, was meant to replace WordPress. As a person who used WordPress on and off a couple of years, I expected more or less the same thing. You know, going to my webiste online somewhere, log in with a username and password, navigate the GUI and post stuff, add plugins&amp;hellip; As such, I didn&amp;rsquo;t care for a change that much. WordPress was working more or less OK, so why change to something similar and learn things all over again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get frequent alerts that my website is down from my webhost, but I got used to shrug these off. I got it as a cheap deal, and for about $6 a month or so hosting, what do you expect? People in the Emacs reddit mentioned they see more spam from my site&amp;rsquo;s URL instead of my posts, but again, with 1 person complaining out of 10 or so, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a big deal. After all, SSL and https is for professional website that can afford it, and I am just an amatuer-ish blogger. Perhaps the biggest hurdle was Github: I knew people who use Hugo usually use Github to publish their blog, but they were all programmers. Me, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about Github or git. That was for coders, people who write scripts for a living. This is not me. I am not a porgrammer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what changed that perspective. Perhaps it was a random tutorial I saw about Git which made me realize it&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; crazy complicated. Perhaps it was the fact that someone advised me not to link to my website again if I don&amp;rsquo;t have https. Maybe it was just my inner geek, itching for a change, and WordPress was getting too familiar and too boring. Whatever it was, I took the bait, and I started doing all of it at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I watched some Lynda videos about git and read a few posts. Then, I learned more about Hugo. After that, it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/&#34;&gt;ox-hugo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lsquo;s turn (because I gotta write my posts from inside Emacs), and then it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://magit.vc/&#34;&gt;Magit&lt;/a&gt; (because I gotta use git from inside Emacs). I think I went through everything in a matter of about a month. I learned too much too fast. But that&amp;rsquo;s how I roll. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I do that to myself, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how it makes sense to go from &amp;ldquo;git is for coders&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;ALL THE THINGS,&amp;rdquo; but I do anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this attitude has terrible consequences. You learn everything on a very shallow level, which means the first tiny bump in the road sends you launching out of control. You get frustrated and you try again, just to hit another bump. Turns out, if I &lt;em&gt;learn everything&lt;/em&gt; I also expect to &lt;em&gt;know everything&lt;/em&gt; out of myself, which is of course nonsense. But not everything is futile. Knowing the big picture in advance is not a bad idea. Learning a couple of things at once make you realize how they work together, and helps you develop a mindset that is more skilled at solving specific problems. Later, when you go look at the official documents, certain things already make sense to you even though you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen them before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be it as it may, it&amp;rsquo;s not easy. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend this method to anyone. it&amp;rsquo;s doing damage control instead of learning. However, manuals never made sese to me. In the rare occessions where I do have the patience to read through the introduction, I&amp;rsquo;d forget what I wanted to do (or how to do it) by the time I get the real stuff. Besides, manuals are usually written by the people who made the program; as such, they are written from the inside, for insiders. Certain terms and syntax make aboslutely no sense to newcomers, who find that they struggle with basic terms that the veterans spit out as if they were born into it. Indeed, if there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that I kept running into when learning Emacs is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to bother with its documentation. As helpful as it is, and as much as everyone loves to say all the help you ever want is C-h v (or a or whatever) away, it was not true for me. It is much, much easier to Google something up and find a blog post (or a YouTube video) that explains it to you in plain English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m much further ahead than where I was when I started my Hugo ordeal. I have sucessfully launched a couple of testing websites on and off Github. I have whined, complained, and whined again to anyone who would listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here we are with Hugo. I use git, and well, the site is on Github. This post was written with ox-hugo. I used Magit, but because there are so many issues I&amp;rsquo;m running into, I decided to make a decision not to use it for at least another month. It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to hold myself back, for sure. On one hand, since I&amp;rsquo;ve done WordPress for so long, I&amp;rsquo;m aching to go back to my old website where I don&amp;rsquo;t have problems learning how to create a new static page (that doesn&amp;rsquo;t show on the front page of this blog), or how exactly images work with these posts, or how can I automate the long process of saving a post and updating my Hugo website compared to the simple &amp;ldquo;click to publish&amp;rdquo;  in WordPress. I&amp;rsquo;m sure some of you are aching to tell me just how to do some of these things. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and speaking of helpful people: a big thank you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kaushalmodi&#34;&gt;Kaushal Modi&lt;/a&gt;, who kept answering my endless questions, who was there through my frustration, anywhere I went. This guy is passionate and compassionate about what he does.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
