<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Ease of Use vs Indepence</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200218/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200218/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems like hating on Google (or Apple, or Amazon, or whatever tech giant) is the hip thing to do these days. I want to raise a couple of points to argue otherwise, and explain how I try to find balance in a monopoly-driven world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The joy of Taking Photos</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200201/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200201/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been enjoying taking photos since October and decided to start recording videos, expanding the way I publish content. As it turns out, recording, editing, and storing videos is not as simple as I thought. The outcome has been holding back on discussing one of my biggest passions these days. I want to change that today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Journaling</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/of-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/of-journaling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve kept a journal (though infrequently) since my early 20s. A thick notebook with a table of contents on its first two pages made of a long list of dates. At the time, life was too chaotic to keep the habit uninterrupted. I&#39;m not sure at what point I converted to digital form, but I flirted with digital journaling for years before it became my primary method of keeping a journal&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What has Been Going on</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always dislike it when I read a post explaining why there&#39;s been a break in posting. It&#39;s usually a sign that the next post will be the last if it will happen at all, and it&#39;s always some excuse about being busy, life getting in the way, etc. etc. So I guess now it&#39;s my turn to write one of these posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Emotional Exhaustions</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/about_burnouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/about_burnouts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past week has been a good example of emotional exhaustion. Because influences overall productivity, relationships, and health (both mental and physical) I&#39;d like to discuss it here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Wisdom</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/desktop-wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/desktop-wisdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I asked my coworkers the following question:
&amp;ldquo;What is the one truth, in a sentence, you&#39;ve learned from being in a help desk position&amp;rdquo;? Here are the answers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>