<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Desk</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200622/</link>
      <pubDate>28280-06-06</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200622/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At first, I only noticed an increase in back pains. Then there was general restlessness that didn&amp;rsquo;t allow me to concentrate on long-term projects at work. There was a nagging feeling of &amp;ldquo;I miss something&amp;rdquo; coming from my body, not so much my brain. And then, one day at the office during my on-site duty, I pulled up my screen and keyboard to its standing position and it hit me: &lt;em&gt;I need to stand&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/standing-desk.jpeg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, a standing desk was a gimmick I contributed to yoga-types folks and others who had back or posture issues&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. When a co-worker left us for another place, I adopted his Ergotron Workfit because it had two keyboard trays which I needed (I work with a Mac and a Windows workstation at the same time) and I thought standing up would be a nice &amp;ldquo;perk&amp;rdquo; since I often just enjoy walking around or talk to people while standing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I didn&amp;rsquo;t know is that shifting my weight helped me concentrate and became a big part of my morning ritual. The habit of standing up in the morning when I get to the office was so hard-wired that even my manager said at one point he can&amp;rsquo;t talk to me before I pull up my desk to standing position and prepare my oatmeal cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-research&#34;&gt;The Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research was fun. A full standing desk was out of the question because of its price and the fact that I already had a nice IKEA desk that fit my NYC-size room nicely. I knew I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a standing desk converter, a fancy term for a keyboard-mouse-screen elevator. Indeed, I first aimed for cheap options from Amazon because I didn&amp;rsquo;t think of a converter to be more than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My go-to website to get information for quality products when there are several options offered is New York Time&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/&#34;&gt;Wirecutter&lt;/a&gt;. While it tends to lean more toward expensive things in general (it feels like sometimes they do it just so they have a &amp;ldquo;budget option&amp;rdquo; to add to the review) it is a good place to get a general idea. Their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-standing-desk-converters/&#34;&gt;best standing desk converters&lt;/a&gt; review was helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, $400 seemed like a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of money for something I could just use a bunch of boxes for, so after reading the full article (you need to keep scrolling past the &amp;ldquo;The Research&amp;rdquo; part) I carefully did some &lt;del&gt;Goolging&lt;/del&gt; Duck-duck-going and stumble unto &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.workwhilewalking.com/&#34;&gt;Work While Standing&lt;/a&gt;. This website seemed like a shallow review site full of ads at start, but as I read more into their reviews I saw that wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case. Their &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.workwhilewalking.com/standing-desk-converter-reviews&#34;&gt;What is a Standing Desk Converter?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; introduction was very informative and showed me what each type of converter does, what it&amp;rsquo;s good for, and why sit-stand desks tend to be more expensive &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information on both sites helped me realize a sit-stand converter is a three-in-one solution for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My ultra-wide monitor&amp;rsquo;s&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; stand that came with it was a piece of junk. It barely supported the weight of the monitor, and I was already searching for a better stand that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t allow it to wiggle and wobble at every slight movement, including typing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized that, as Wirecutter noted, the screen does need to be higher up when you stand than when you sit down (try it - you&amp;rsquo;ll see that when you stand there&amp;rsquo;s more space between your eyes and your typing hands). This has been an issue that has been bothering me for some time in the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My narrow IKEA desk and room setup meant that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want a desk that would push toward me as I raise it. I also didn&amp;rsquo;t like how the Z-shape legs of the other converters looked like on the desk, blocking off the area under the desk in its upper position like a cage. I wanted something cleaner looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from there, it was easy to conclude that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ergodesktop.com/product-types/single-monitor-solutions&#34;&gt;Kangaroo pro model from Ergo Desktop&lt;/a&gt; was right for me: it included the extra feature that allowed the screen to move independently from the tray, but at the same time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t need the Elite series which included an electric motor for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final tune-in was the measurements: turns out that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ergodesktop.com/kangaroo-pro-junior&#34;&gt;Kangaroo Pro Junior&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lsquo;s depth was the perfect fit for my desk; the bigger Pro would be too wide, with its tray pushing out toward my chest and covering the drawers of my desk. The desk had a clean, industrial look to it that I liked. I also found a coupon online just before I placed my purchase, reducing the cost of the desk by $20. Shipping was free of charge. Nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-up-and-some-hacking&#34;&gt;Set Up and Some Hacking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Junior Pro came in a large, flat, heavy box. Kind of like a flat TV screen. Because I don&amp;rsquo;t trust USPS to ship anything to my home address (that&amp;rsquo;s a long story) I shipped it to my office instead and took it home from there. I&amp;rsquo;d say I&amp;rsquo;m in a rather OK shape and I handled the box OK, but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend carrying the box a long-distance or up the stairs without help. It was just heavy enough to be a bit much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assembly was easy enough. There weren&amp;rsquo;t many parts, and the instructions were clearly printed in full colors (you can also view the PDF on their website). The only tough part was the monitor: because of its size, it was difficult to hold it with one hand while adjusting the stand so the screw holes fit just right. This is also when I ran into more problems with my screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01B9IDLAW/ref=ppx%5Fyo%5Fdt%5Fb%5Fsearch%5Fasin%5Ftitle?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34;&gt;ultra-wide monitor&lt;/a&gt; has its VERSA screw holes a bit lower than they should be. The Kangaroo&amp;rsquo;s screen-tilt lock doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide much friction as is, and it was not possible to lock the screen at a straight angle. It kept tilting downwards, hanging on the adjustable tilt screw. Another issue was the screen&amp;rsquo;s HDMI socket location, straight in the back, where it hits the metal shaft of the stand. This is a known issue with the monitor judging from the complaints on the Amazon page, where people ran into this issue while trying to mount the monitor against a wall. In short: this is a problem with my monitor, not the new desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fixed the problem temporally by placing Styrofoam between the screen&amp;rsquo;s mounting stem, which was sticking out a bit, and the metal shaft of the screen raiser. I contacted Ergo directly about my issue and got a reply the next day: they were shipping me another screw which was supposed to replace the tilt break. After playing around with it I found that it was better to use the screw they sent as a stopper, which fit in one of the grooves of the metal shaft, than a replacement for the break as they suggested. This locks the screen tilt in one position, but I&amp;rsquo;m fairly comfortable with how it stands now and I don&amp;rsquo;t need it to move. The result is a wobbly-less typing environment both for standing and sitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-few-more-words&#34;&gt;A few More Words&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting a standing desk converter is easily the biggest upgrade for my work environment in recent years. At start I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend so much money on something that seemed to be a &amp;ldquo;perk,&amp;rdquo; but the quality of the product, the way it makes the whole room look, and the inviting feeling I get every morning when I stand at it with my fresh cup of coffee are priceless. Still, this is a highly personal choice. I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend this standing desk solution for everyone: too much depends on individual quirks, measurements, budget, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, This post wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be complete without praising org-mode again. A picture is worth a thousand words, so here, have a look:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/standing-desk-research.jpeg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re only seeing half of it since my thoughts (under the closed headers) are just too long to fit here. org-mode made it not only easy to write down details as I was browsing and reading but also kept me organized with my thoughts and prevented me from going back in loops over conclusions I&amp;rsquo;ve already made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting irony, I realize: I am one of these folks myself. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s because sit-stand converters effectively include a stand for the screen. Other converters are essentially just a raised tray on which you also put the screen with the keyboard and mouse; with sit-stands, the screen mounts to the back. Better models include independent raising mechanism. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably another post in itself, an ultra-wide monitor is another must-have in my setup today. It is not as heavy and messy as having two monitors while providing much-needed work space, not to mention good gaming experience (which is horrible on a dual screens in my opinion). &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D.D.T.C Day 55</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200511/</link>
      <pubDate>16160-05-05</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200511/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Distancing Due to COVID19, Day 55. What are the effects?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One that comes to mind immediately is updating this blog. It was left untouched for a month (my last post has been growing mold for a couple of weeks, originally written in April). Other DDTC effects include: working from home and providing support to users remotely, lack of exercise, and &amp;ldquo;artificial depression,&amp;rdquo; as I call it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, distancing started on March 17, after my partner was exposed to a potentially positive COVID19 carrier. After two weeks of socially distancing, my office was already closed with my team working from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work for a medical center, which means the office has to remain open. We started a one-person-a-day rotation while the rest of us work from home. It was weird to come back to an empty office when it was my turn to be there, but perhaps weirder is the fact that by now, this has become somewhat normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote work forced us the gain more experience with different remote-support tools. Connecting to the office computers with VPN and is second nature for us, but it&amp;rsquo;s not that obvious to users who suddenly need all kinds of &amp;ldquo;required software&amp;rdquo; that they didn&amp;rsquo;t give a second thought to in the past. Even more challenging is the gray line of &amp;ldquo;owning&amp;rdquo; a user&amp;rsquo;s computer once you connect to it to troubleshoot. Most of the users just want their problem dealt with, with little concern about what you&amp;rsquo;re doing on their personal machine after they give you remote access to keyboard and mouse.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everything is work and technology (even though it seems so right now). If you ask me what&amp;rsquo;s the thing I miss the most right now, I&amp;rsquo;d say the gym. My exercise routine, somewhat trivial before DDTC, has become a concern. Going to the gym used to be a 2 to 3 mornings a week routine. Walking up and downstairs at work to show up in different offices, clinics and labs, used to compliment my exercise as well as walks to the park with my camera. Now, with the majority of these activities almost extinct, I feel sluggish and otherwise &amp;ldquo;rusty&amp;rdquo;. I can and am still taking walks, but in NYC, these often mean an inconvenient zigzag around people coming in front of you and half-circling groups of teens who still, for god-knows-what-reason (besides being teenagers I guess), insist on yapping loudly with mask-less mouths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never been big on travel, but forcing myself to stay home as much as possible in a NYC-size apartment has a toll. I can&amp;rsquo;t explain exactly what it is besides that everything feels like it has more weight. Something about not being exposed enough to other things, bad or good, outside of this immediate second skin, has made me emotionally numb. I eat less, I sleep more. These symptoms remind me of another state I&amp;rsquo;m pretty familiar with: depression. The more I stay in, the more sluggish I am. I call this &amp;ldquo;artificial&amp;rdquo; depression because I feel it&amp;rsquo;s manufactured, not naturally occurring out of the blue as depression spells can be. The reasons are well known, and as a result, like many artificial things, it has a certain taste &amp;ldquo;natural&amp;rdquo; depression does not have. Knowing that I&amp;rsquo;m choosing to do this to myself for the &amp;ldquo;better good&amp;rdquo; seems to lost importance as time passes. You start wondering, what is the better good anyway? Better good to who? For what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest cure seems to be to leave the house and, if possible, run around the little nearby park. The running sheds always the numbness and allows me to feel more positive. I&amp;rsquo;ve also turned to personal tech projects to keep the mind sharp and things interesting&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s see what I can come up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lines are pretty clear when the device is owned by the organization, but there&amp;rsquo;s a whole post to write about the gray lines of how much is &amp;ldquo;owned&amp;rdquo; by the tech when connecting to a user&amp;rsquo;s personal device. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to write here as well. For one, I returned to use Windows as my primary OS and use Linux in a VM. This is mostly (again) because of games, but also because of work requirements from home. Other projects include more scripting and automation, and re-thinking my backup system. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying Sane While Social Distancing</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200329/</link>
      <pubDate>29290-03-03</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200329/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good morning from New York City, the new epicenter of COVID-19. This morning, I want to share a few tips that helped me cope with social distancing, keep mostly calm, and otherwise remain productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m lucky I don&amp;rsquo;t live alone. I share an apartment with my two partners, and we interact on a daily basis. There&amp;rsquo;s something about making coffee in the morning for more people, or cleaning the dishes more often because you know others need them too. I enjoy being useful to others, if you can&amp;rsquo;t tell from this blog. Conversations face to face help, and if you&amp;rsquo;re one of the fortunate people to have someone living with you, be it family, significant others or roommates, use that. Even only for a couple of minutes in different periods throughout the day. If you&amp;rsquo;re by yourself, try to schedule a video conference with friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we all socially-distancing ourselves, this is actually a good time to meet new people virtually. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed streams on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/&#34;&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt; (you can find people from all over the world, last week I talked to a few folks in Italy, for example) and more people were interested to start a conversation on different dating apps. After all, there&amp;rsquo;s no where to go. Interacting with new people as well with those you know, even virtually, really helps to soften to blow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something everyone can try to do is to enforce a routine. One of the things that keep my morning energy going is to go through a series of little objectives repeating each morning. I clean the Mr Coffee and prepare coffee. While it&amp;rsquo;s brewing, I&amp;rsquo;m checking the sink for dishes and the dishwasher for clean ones. I take out the trash. Then I go to my room and do a short series of exercises for about 15 minutes while catching on news (usually NYT, sometimes NPR). I then sit at my computer with my mug of coffee and either learn more on the situation, write in my blog, or check on my emails and work. I don&amp;rsquo;t always do all of my habits, and I often &amp;ldquo;break the chain,&amp;rdquo; but I know that if I keep it up, for as long as I do, my mood remains positive and I tend to be more productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of exercise, it deserves it&amp;rsquo;s own paragraph. Gyms are close, but now is actually a good opportunity to exercise more. There are many sources online that will teach you different stretches, yoga, Pilates. There are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qWy%5FaOlB45Y&#34;&gt;YouTube videos&lt;/a&gt;, quick programs from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/05/09/the-scientific-7-minute-workout/&#34;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt; and media outlets, tips from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www1.nyc.gov/site/doh/health/health-topics/physical-activity.page&#34;&gt;nyc.gov&lt;/a&gt; (these are geared for older adults, but these will do nicely if you&amp;rsquo;re younger, just ramp up the difficulty). Walking outdoors, though becoming a more controversial topic recently, is still generally recommended. As long as you can maintain your distance (which is the key issue), jogging outside recharges your mental batteries and burn fat. Just pick up a street that is not too busy, and run &lt;em&gt;slowly&lt;/em&gt;, which should allow you to get around people. Be generous to others and if you see a narrow fit ahead, slow down and allow people to pass. cross the street if you see a group of folks talking without masks on, which unfortunately still happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an amateur photographer, going outside is a crucial activity. These days I&amp;rsquo;m lucky to have found a hobby that is mostly solitary anyway, and usually keeps me away from people. The spring is slowly coming, and this means you can encounter different flowers and birds. Here&amp;rsquo;s a picture I took last week in Fort Tryon, while maintaining much more than 6-feet distance from other people:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200329.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I essentially work for a hospital, I still support our users&amp;rsquo; machines. 80% of the work is remote, though we&amp;rsquo;re still required to come to the office and show physical presence on a rotating basis in case IT support is needed on site, which in our case can mean hospital equipment. Working remotely is an interesting challenge in itself, and when I&amp;rsquo;m not working, I&amp;rsquo;m playing video games to keep the mind busy and relief stress. There are amazing free deals on all major gaming stores - Steam, Epic, GOG, Humble Bundle. And if you just have a laptop, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, there are quite a few games that will work fine there too and keep your mind busy. I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.klei.com/games/oxygen-not-included&#34;&gt;Oxygen Not Included&lt;/a&gt; if you like management style gaming that require thinking, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.darkwoodgame.com/&#34;&gt;Darkwood&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re into horror, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stardewvalley.net/&#34;&gt;Stardew Valley&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re into something peaceful and relaxing, &lt;a href=&#34;https://thimbleweedpark.com/&#34;&gt;Thimbleweed Park&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re into old-school point and click quests. All of these are under $30 and offer hours of fun. Other big AAA titles are also inviting right now if you have fellow friend gamers. I recently started playing &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.ubi.com/us/the-division-2/&#34;&gt;Division 2&lt;/a&gt; with my co-workers, online. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some helpful things that keep me going. Writing this post and hopefully using it to interact with more people is another good way to be productive and social during these times. What are some of your tips?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Ease of Use vs Indepence</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200218/</link>
      <pubDate>29290-02-02</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200218/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems like hating on Google (or Apple, or Amazon, or whatever tech giant) is the hip thing to do these days. I want to raise a couple of points to argue otherwise, and explain how I try to find balance in a monopoly-driven world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been running Linux full time at home &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191208/&#34;&gt;since last December&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;m not looking back. I love the level of control I have, the lack of nagging updates with the potential of breaking everything, the transparency in the application I use through the command line, and the overall productivity I get out of it. With the exception of a few very specific applications, I miss nothing from the Windows days&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I can manage my life without Google. Not yet, not anytime soon, and I think that even if I had the choice, I won&amp;rsquo;t really want to. The same is true for Amazon: it&amp;rsquo;s a giant online retailer that chews away on mom-and-pop shops, draining local business dry while more college folks move in and older ethnic groups move out. Sounds sinister, but I&amp;rsquo;m not in a rush to stop using Amazon. As a matter of fact, since I moved to this neighborhood, I started using it even more and I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m going to stop any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could say I&amp;rsquo;m part of the problem and I won&amp;rsquo;t disagree with you. I rather use Google maps instead of relying on hand-written instructions. I rather order something online and have it in my hands two days later than to spend half an hour in a messy pharmacy, look for a product they don&amp;rsquo;t carry, and buy a replacement for two bucks more just because I live in New York City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no lack of smartphones out there that are not made by Google, but there&amp;rsquo;s only one phone that&amp;rsquo;s good enough &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; cheap&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; enough &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; has consistent security patches &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; is not one of those 6.5 inches monsters that I can&amp;rsquo;t use comfortably. There are few Linux phones available in different stages of development, mostly expensive prototypes that cannot compete with the apps on Google&amp;rsquo;s Play store. I&amp;rsquo;d be one of the first ones to jump ship when it will make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same argument goes for other platforms I use, such as Instagram. There are free other independent options, but they don&amp;rsquo;t come close to the exposure Instagram provides. Medium is another example: the exposure goes far beyond what Duck Duck Go brings up when tech folks look something related to this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what can be done? What&amp;rsquo;s the fine line between Usability and Idealism? There are many people asking this question these days. I don&amp;rsquo;t really have a good answer, besides that I take things personally: the more of myself I invest in a certain thing, the more immersive it should be and the higher quality (to my standards) it needs to be. This is not a die-hard principle, but a guideline that seems to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take this website, for example. It&amp;rsquo;s a personal blog. Having it on a platform like Hugo-Go and be able to mess with its internal parts is important. Having it integrating directly with org-mode, which I use every day for my most personal things, makes sense. Another simple example is my coffee. My coffee morning ritual is highly personal, involving my espresso machine and froth. This means I enjoy taking the time to identify a local roaster who date-stamps each pound of espresso beans I get. I know where his shop is because I was there. I even know his dog&amp;rsquo;s name.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200218_1.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; is the kind of thing I want to imagine when I drink my coffee at home in the morning. It&amp;rsquo;s not the same when I drink the coffee at work, or at any other huge chain-stores. Nothing can recreate what this coffee and the picture I took above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are areas that require improvement. Again, take my photos. They are very personal, yet, I give them away to Facebook and Amazon by hosting them on Instagram because of the exposure I need. I give up the quality and the personal connection for a service (in this case, reaching other people). When there&amp;rsquo;s a conflict like this, I promote my own platform over the public one. In this example, only photos that are a month old will show up on Instagram; the resolution is already horrible, so if someone wants to see the real thing, they&amp;rsquo;d have to come to my website, and so on. Medium and this website have a similar relationship: only old posts that are worth larger exposure the second time around get pushed to Medium, definitely not all of them. I feel this is a compromise I can live with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same can be said about my MacOS days. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Macs for personal usage and I keep using them at work. I have a Windows virtual box for when I need to work from home or need to use a Windows program. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the Google Pixel &lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt; line, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the Google Pixel flagship line, which seems to be expensive just because iPhones are expensive. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The joy of Taking Photos</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200201/</link>
      <pubDate>4040-02-02</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200201/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying taking photos since October and decided to start recording videos, expanding the way I publish content. As it turns out, recording, editing, and storing videos is not as simple as I thought. The outcome has been holding back on discussing one of my biggest passions these days. I want to change that today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/my-new-sonya6000/&#34;&gt;discussed my camera&lt;/a&gt; before my trip earlier this year. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve learned more about photography enjoyed seeing my skill improving. Here&amp;rsquo;s one of the first photos I took to demonstrate this:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200201_1.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above image is an experiment in trying to focus on an object with a 16mm lens. I was trying to see if I can get the blurry effect with the stock lenses, and I succeeded, though I basically almost had to have the fruits in the picture touch the lens to get it. The composition in this image was done a few weeks later (it&amp;rsquo;s all about cropping).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the elements of photography as an art form is seeing things that are not really there. It requires creativity I admire in other photos. My own take:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200201_2.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figure of the hand in this photo was almost missed when I was focusing on the water drops after the rain. It captured the mood of the day perfectly: gloom and melancholy. It was taken much more recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often go to a park nearby to relax and enjoy a bit of nature in the midst of the busy city. Animals are a constant sight, and as I improved the flow in my movements and became somewhat less clumsy, I stopped scaring the little ones off. First, there were squirrels:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200201_3.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, as I became more still, birds stopped flying away as I took my time changing my lenses:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200201_4.jpg&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both the above cases, I took plenty of photos and selected these two. I find that squirrels are fairly easy to snap. They&amp;rsquo;re not really afraid of humans and can actually be &lt;a href=&#34;https://gothamist.com/news/nyc-park-visitors-warned-about-hangry-squirrels-out-for-blood&#34;&gt;quite intimidating&lt;/a&gt;. Birds, on the other hand, are a different story. They are everywhere, and you have to be perfectly still for a while for them to come closer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot in photography that is both different and similar to the work I do every day. In a way, it&amp;rsquo;s highly technical with much to learn about lighting and composition elements. In another way, it takes me out to explore, often to long walks of several hours, alone with nature and with my thoughts. I have to take my time and slow down on these walks to take good photos and I appreciate many things from different angles as I re-evaluate them in a different light, quite literally. The technical and the art mix in a way that fits well into my current lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The images you see here are all on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/jrss12/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, which is why they have such a bad quality. I do have the larger, high quality versions with me of course and recently started printing some of them to keep around my home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of you may scuff about Instagram. Why use Facebook&amp;rsquo;s commercial platform on a site that stands for free software? The answer is reach, discovery.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixelfed.social/&#34;&gt;Other options&lt;/a&gt; exist, but they are nowhere close with their use-base and have a limitation on how many images can be stored. I do hope to find a better solution as I take more photos and grow in skill and content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re a regular reader of this site!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Journaling</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/of-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>29290-08-08</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/of-journaling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve kept a journal (though infrequently) since my early 20s. A thick notebook with a table of contents on its first two pages made of a long list of dates. At the time, life was too chaotic to keep the habit uninterrupted. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure at what point I converted to digital form, but I flirted with digital journaling for years before it became my primary method of keeping a journal&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the old paper journals are the ones that survived and moved homes with me (for the most part) while the digital ones are lost somewhere in the cloud.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve tried many different applications, more than I can remember. My thoughts are spread across Google, Microsoft Evernote and Apple products, some defunct and cannot be restored. My journal today, in org-mode, is resistant to that - at least, that&amp;rsquo;s my hope. I enjoy keeping a journal here, on the same platform I use for blogging and organizing my day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to a written notebook, a digital journal offers a couple of big benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can read my notes: my handwriting is horrible. English and Latin letters are not what I grew up writing (my early journals in my native language are not exactly neat either). This used to be a problem: Combined with spelling mistakes I&amp;rsquo;ve had early on, my writing was often a serious deciphering challenge. Digital text obviously fixes this issue.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I Can write more: I have more room to write and I don&amp;rsquo;t struggle with turning the notebook around to fit sentences into corners. My hand gets tired writing for long period of times, especially if I get excited or angry and press harder on the paper. I can also type faster than writing by hand and fit much more content in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organization and storage: this is a bit of a contradiction since I said earlier I lost my old digital journals. This is now fixed though. Digital notes are more organized (I save mine by week number in a year, more about this coming up). As for safe storage, my journal is now backed up in several locations and can be restored if needed. The same is not true for my physical journals which can get damaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But&amp;hellip; I do I miss journaling on paper sometimes. Paper journals are 100% personal. The choice of a notebook, the way it ages and shows daily usage, the handwriting, cards/stickies/photos shoved and glued between its pages &amp;ndash; things you can touch and smell &amp;ndash; these are irreplaceable in a digital format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For their birthday, I got my partner (who loves scribbling down their thoughts) a pack of limited-edition &lt;a href=&#34;https://fieldnotesbrand.com/limited-editions&#34;&gt;Field Notes&lt;/a&gt; with a couple of Parker pens. I was skeptical of the small size of these things at first, but my partner&amp;rsquo;s thrilled with these. They write vertically and horizontally (and other ways which make sense only to them); they add tables to organize their planning for vacations; the fact that you need a magnifying glass to see some of their side notes makes the whole thing look even better somehow. It&amp;rsquo;s a small package of pure personality, and it reflects my partner perfectly. I, on the other hand, used graph-paper notebooks for my journals for as long as I can remember because it just made sense. I used to align pictures with the blue guidelines when I pasted them in back in my paper-journaling days. These journals reflected my personality just the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I miss having something personal and &lt;em&gt;un&lt;/em&gt;-technological in my life, especially as an IT professional. There are many ways I can explore un-technology, but I just like writing. Sometimes I just miss the feeling of the pen, and I have the itch to just sketch something quickly, without opening a dedicated program or having a specific goal in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how my journal looks like today:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/2019-08-29.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was preparing this post (which took forever for other reasons&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) I went through several of my former posts. The overall &amp;ldquo;feel&amp;rdquo; of the journal is very welcoming. In org-mode each entry is folded neatly into its day, which is folded into its week number, which in turn is folded into its year. The whole journal, easily the largest file among my personal text files, looks like 10 lines of text when it&amp;rsquo;s first opened. You can see this effect above, where the entry on Monday is on a fourth level (you can&amp;rsquo;t see the year in the picture, which is the first level).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend org-mode to journaling newbies or for those unfamiliar with Emacs already; it&amp;rsquo;s like going to a culinary school to learn how to make a simple salad. There are far simpler software for this purpose, and if you want to pick on the habit of journaling in general, I would recommend a notebook first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, a person who uses org-mode on a day-to-day basis to keep track of tasks and writing this blog, this is a no-brainer. It looks fantastic and functions even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I cringe at the thought that my most personal notes are buried somewhere deep in a company&amp;rsquo;s server. Back then, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know better. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many writing applications come with spell-checking options which can be highly distracting. This is a habit that I believe started with Word&amp;rsquo;s red zigzag. It forces you to stop your train of thought and focus on the mistakes highlighted in angry red. Emacs doesn&amp;rsquo;t have this problem. Spell-checking takes place only after I highlight a segment of my text and ask for to spellcheck. Having spellchecking separate from the writing process is important! I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize how disturbing this can be before transitioning to org-mode. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These being mostly lack of sleep, insomnia of some sort. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What has Been Going on</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/updates/</link>
      <pubDate>3030-04-04</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always dislike it when I read a post explaining why there&amp;rsquo;s been a break in posting. It&amp;rsquo;s usually a sign that the next post will be the last if it will happen at all, and it&amp;rsquo;s always some excuse about being busy, life getting in the way, etc. etc. So I guess now it&amp;rsquo;s my turn to write one of these posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been away for a week, traveling overseas to see family. The trip in itself was fine and not as eventful as I anticipated (which is a good thing). When I got back, I immediately bought two things: a HOTAS for Elite Dangerous, and a good headset with a DAC to experience music better. I am almost done writing a post about the later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mornings, which were once completely empty and dedicated to writing, now share time with going to the gym. As it turns out, it&amp;rsquo;s much easier to keep a gym routine in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emacs and Org mode - not much changed there, as a matter of fact. I tried the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/myuhe/org-gcal.el&#34;&gt;Gcal&lt;/a&gt; for Emacs and ended up disappointed after I figured out how to set it up. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orgzly.com/&#34;&gt;Orgzly&lt;/a&gt;, on the other hand, keeps evolving and becomes a must-have tool for all org-mode users with Android devices in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit to talk about and expand on. I hope to get back on track soon with a new post. In the meantime, feel free to say hello or read my older posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Emotional Exhaustions</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/about_burnouts/</link>
      <pubDate>9090-03-03</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/about_burnouts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past week has been a good example of emotional exhaustion. Because influences overall productivity, relationships, and health (both mental and physical) I&amp;rsquo;d like to discuss it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;defining-what-it-is&#34;&gt;Defining What it is&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this post looking for a good definition for a burnout, which is what I thought I was experiencing. Turns out, I was wrong. Like other terms that describe a relative and immeasurable state of emotions, burnout is a definition of a situation that gets overused and eventually dismissed as a dramatic conversation emphasis. After a short research, I found the following definition from &lt;a href=&#34;http://dictionary.sensagent.com/&#34;&gt;Sensagent&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most well-studied measurement of burnout in the literature is the Maslach Burnout Inventory. Maslach and her colleague Jackson first identified the construct &amp;ldquo;burnout&amp;rdquo; in the 1970s, and developed a measure that weighs the effects of emotional exhaustion and reduced sense of personal accomplishment. This indicator has become the standard tool for measuring burnout in research on the syndrome. The Maslach Burnout Inventory uses a three dimensional description of exhaustion, cynicism, and inefficacy. Some researchers and practitioners have argued for an &amp;ldquo;exhaustion only&amp;rdquo; model that sees that symptom as the hallmark of burnout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This definition and the link above led me to more research which focused on additional causes of burnouts, most notably depression and a sense of lack of accomplishment and/or purpose. Because I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with these emotional states as well, I recognized these feelings were &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; present this week. I felt very tired and drained, but I did not feel sad or lacking a purpose. As a matter of fact, I felt focused (to the point of overdoing things, part of the reason for exhaustion) and very productive at work. I was pleased with my achievements this week and my interactions with colleagues were better than usual.
I then settled on this definition, from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotional%5Fexhaustion&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emotional exhaustion is a chronic state of physical and emotional depletion that results from excessive job demands and continuous stress. It describes a feeling of being emotionally overextended and exhausted by one&amp;rsquo;s work. It is manifested by both physical fatigue and a sense of feeling psychologically and emotionally &amp;ldquo;drained&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can conclude that emotional exhaustion is a symptom or a part of a burnout. Exhaustion &lt;em&gt;can lead&lt;/em&gt; to a burnout, which has the additional effects that were earlier discussed (like a sense of lack of purpose, cynicism, depression, etc.) This is important because it serves as a way to contain the problem so other areas that do not require examination at this point are left out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-discussing-exhaustion-is-important&#34;&gt;Why Discussing Exhaustion is Important&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending certain activities require energy while others &amp;ldquo;charge&amp;rdquo; such energy. As a mostly introverted person who values quiet and privacy, social interactions require that I spend energy. Several activities on my personal calendar, such as attending a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dungeons%5F&amp;amp;%5FDragons&#34;&gt;DnD&lt;/a&gt; session with friends, requires I spend a relatively high level of mental energy. Other activities, like working out at the gym, requires a different kind of mental energy and a level of physical energy. In sate of emotional exhaustion, both are depleted and prevent me from doing these activities. In turn, giving up on something that is highly important to me (going to the gym) leads to a feeling of guilt and self-blame which is another step toward overall burnout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make a long story short, exhaustion means you&amp;rsquo;re doing less overall and could lead to further physical and mental problems that in turn mean you&amp;rsquo;re even less productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;causes&#34;&gt;Causes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we can talk about &amp;ldquo;fixing&amp;rdquo; exhaustion, we should probably discuss what is the source of the problem. In my case, the source of emotional exhaustion is work. This is very common, and again, may be overused and overstated. Therefore, I turn to concrete symptoms. A simple series of yes/no questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have I worked extra time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I have additional responsibilities at work than usual?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I feel physically tired, to the point of napping or going to sleep extra early?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there increasing need to be left alone and rest (recharging)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the week that passed, the answer for all of the above is yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixing-the-issue&#34;&gt;Fixing the Issue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; your car when you run out of gas? How do you &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; your phone when the battery is drained? The answer is indeed obvious. The problem is that recharging is not always an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be the weekend (finally) but there are other responsibilities and plans that are waiting since you did not have time to deal with these during the week. For me, it is also very possible to fall back on habits that waste time rather than recharge or recharge efficiently. that are not necessarily as recharging as they are just a cause of exhaustion. For example, playing video games until very late at night might feel like recharging, when in reality what is really needed is sleep and a physical/mental break from the computer screen. In turn, this also requires energy (discipline) which I may already be lacking because of the exhaustion. What do we do then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divide activities into time segments: Instead of just ignoring the world and watching 5 episodes of a TV show, break it to watch only one before getting up, walking around a bit, evaluating things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize true recharging activities: like sleep. Recognize that I need to be in bed at a certain time and finish with other activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use friends / significant others: if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky to live in with people who care about you, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to reach out for a point of reference and have them help you and prevent you from sinking into something else completely. Have some tea time together. Talk. Cuddle. Take a walk with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vent productively - find a way to let out your feelings in a way that feels productive and is worth your time. In my case, this post is that particular item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-and-prevention&#34;&gt;Conclusion and Prevention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, emotional exhaustion happens or can be triggered because of an environmental element that is not tied to your own habits. It is important to recognize that prevention is not as important as having a way to cope and work out of a situation when it does happen. Being prepared and having a plan to work with when needed is the most important thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prevention may comes second but is also important. it&amp;rsquo;s important to know what&amp;rsquo;s coming and plan for it. This is one reason why I love &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Org-mode&#34;&gt;Org-mode&lt;/a&gt;. Having a good tool is part of the job, using it is the other. For me, a good routine is to remote into my VM at work before I come in, turn on Org-mode, and sync my personal tasks. I then work from home looking at my day and evaluate what needs to be done. While this changes during the day, knowing what&amp;rsquo;s coming gives me a top-down view of what a successful day should look like. In turn, this prevents a sense of lack-of-purpose and directly prevents me from sliding into burnout, as mentioned earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important prevention technique that I rediscovered is to disconnect several times during the workday. For me, a minimal break of 10 minutes is needed to &amp;ldquo;reset&amp;rdquo; and be able get out of the &amp;ldquo;tunnel vision&amp;rdquo; that I sometimes get while working. I work in a large enough environment that allows me to take walks inside the buildings regardless of the weather. I use the time to find a quiet corner and look outside and daydream a bit. In addition. the power of napping has amazing benefits. It&amp;rsquo;s not always possible to find a spot to nap, but if I do, a quick dose of even 5 minutes around 15:00 (this is usually when the &amp;ldquo;crash&amp;rdquo; comes) can be immensely helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it&amp;rsquo;s important to leave some empty time on your calendar. Some folks pencil in every possible day with activities, including the weekend. I know, for instance, that using my Saturday for activities with partners and family means I won&amp;rsquo;t have Saturday to myself, so I give myself time Sunday. This is a luxury not many adults can afford, especially those with a family, But for me this is thankfully not an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always important to look back and reflect on emotional events that take place to learn from them and improve for the next time - good or bad. We are all learning creatures, and we can always &amp;ldquo;self-upgrade&amp;rdquo;. Personally, writing this post already helped me quite a bit. I hope this would help someone else reading it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Wisdom</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/desktop-wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>24240-10-10</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/desktop-wisdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I asked my coworkers the following question:
&amp;ldquo;What is the one truth, in a sentence, you&amp;rsquo;ve learned from being in a help desk position&amp;rdquo;? Here are the answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris (age:25, years in the job:3)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;There are a lot, and I mean a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt;, stupid people in the world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick (age:28, years in the job:10)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;You got to have a lot of patience&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave (age:63, years in the job:30)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re only as good as the last person you&amp;rsquo;ve helped&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myself (years in the job:3)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;If it was really to &amp;lsquo;just work&amp;rsquo;, we&amp;rsquo;d be out of a job&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at the nature of the job and the experience each one of us had, these facts make a lot of sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris is the youngest, very bright, and after money. He&amp;rsquo;s tired of users forgetting to check the power cable or not knowing how to reset their computers before calling. Nick is a chill guy who never seems to get upset. He is used to the boss demanding things and he exercises every day, which definitely help to take out aggravations. Dave has seen it all in this job and been through a couple of management changes. His other favorite sentence is &amp;ldquo;tomorrow is another day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
