<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>android on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in android on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Impressions of The Pixel 4a</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/2020-08-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/2020-08-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve received my new Pixel 4a a Friday before last and after a week I can say this with confidence: this is the best smartphone Google ever made. I also hope it will be the last phone I buy from Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to read more about the Pixel4a, There are plenty reviews on the web, both written and videos (here&amp;rsquo;s a recent in-depth one &lt;a href=&#34;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2020/08/google-pixel-4a-review-the-simple-basic-reasonable-google-phone/&#34;&gt;arstechnica&lt;/a&gt;, and a quick visual one from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wAuiV0B-Yvw&#34;&gt;the Verge&lt;/a&gt;). Instead, here I&amp;rsquo;m going to focus on why I find this phone so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware-the-phone&#34;&gt;Hardware: The Phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start from the obvious: the price. At $350, Google is back where I think it has always been best: supplying top tech at a price that doesn&amp;rsquo;t twists people arms. At hard times like this, with folks losing their jobs, this is a welcome change from the $800 plust flagships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pixel 4a is not a statement of class like the iPhone, and it&amp;rsquo;s far from delivering the latest and greatest. That&amp;rsquo;s fine, because you don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; the latest and greatest, you just need a damn smartphone. The iPhone 8 Plus, which I have for work, still sells for about $500 today&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 8 Plus has always been too big and too heavy for me, yet somehow the screen on it is &lt;em&gt;smaller&lt;/em&gt; than the one on the Pixel 4a. This makes a big difference for me. The Pixel doesn&amp;rsquo;t fall out of my hand when I pick it up like the iPhone 8 plus does. I can reach the corners of the screen without doing crazy hands acrobatics. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t stick out of my pocket for everyone on the street to see. It fits nicely into my pouch when I go for a run. These may look like insignificant details, but the overall experience is liberating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a bonus, the pixel comes with an earphone jack. I can carry my flac files with me on the phone and listen to my higher-end earphones at the office now, especially since the phone has twice the space than my old Pixel2. The Bluetooth headphones are good for meetings and streaming music, but if I want to get lost in some good stuff, I need an audio cable&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s also nice to plug in my good set and charge my phone at the same time when I&amp;rsquo;m at my computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/2020-08-28.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;


&lt;figcaption&gt;iPhone 8 Plus and Pixel 4a side by side&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;And That&amp;rsquo;s it. Yes, I know the Pixel 4a is all about the camera, the better battery life, lack of better water resistance, Android sucks/rules, whatever. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter to me. One more thing. While I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly care about looks, the Pixel &lt;em&gt;looks&lt;/em&gt; good. The edge-to-edge screen without bezels, the crisp image, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.google.com/us/product/pixel%5F4a%5Ffabric%5Fcase&#34;&gt;fabric cases&lt;/a&gt; to match, it puts the iPhone in perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-software--android&#34;&gt;The software (Android)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android 10 is part of what makes the pixel 4a so great. I used to marvel at Google&amp;rsquo;s utilitarian vanilla Android and scoffed at anything that wasn&amp;rsquo;t pure android experience. Now, after a couple of years in IT working with Android, iOS, macOS, Windows, and of course Linux, I&amp;rsquo;m moving forward. Or perhaps (depends on your view) backward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href=&#34;https://grapheneos.org/&#34;&gt;GrapheneOS&lt;/a&gt;. A mobile OS that is meant to strip the Pixel out of what makes it Google. One of a kind mobile OS, built on top of Android, meant for privacy and security geeks who want a smartphone that doesn&amp;rsquo;t call back to the mothership. I want to wipe this phone clean and see if I can live without Google on me all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m cheating. I still have my iPhone. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that all the apps that need to &amp;ldquo;spy&amp;rdquo; on me can be on my work phone. Bank app? I don&amp;rsquo;t mind if my job, which pays my salary, sees my bank statements. Google Maps? If I travel, I can&amp;rsquo;t leave work completely behind anyway. Phone calls? I barely call people anymore and most of my contacts are on iPhone, so I don&amp;rsquo;t mind using Facetime. Everything truly personal however will live on the Pixel: my org notes in Orgzly, my contacts on Signal&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, my media, passwords, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, this is mostly a challenge I want to take. I still have my old Pixel 2, and I&amp;rsquo;m planning to use it first as a &amp;ldquo;demo&amp;rdquo; version to see how this works out - or fails. By the time I&amp;rsquo;m done I believe GrapheneOS will already have a working Pixel 4a version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Well, why not? This blog is called the art of not asking why, after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This price came up for a refurbished iPhone 8+ on Apple&amp;rsquo;s website. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, I find that I don&amp;rsquo;t need my amplifier when I connect directly to the jack. With the USB-C dangle, which looks horrible and prevents me from charging the phone at the same time (so it slowly runs out of juice), I need to use an AMP as well. So imaging this: heavy audio cable from the headset, into the adapter, into the AMP, into the phone. I want to say there&amp;rsquo;s a slight difference in sound quality without the amp, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have a professional-grade headset to detect that sort of thing. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be tricky since Signal is not exactly open source, &lt;del&gt;but I&amp;rsquo;m aware there&amp;rsquo;s a way to install the APK anyway&lt;/del&gt;. Actually, Signal puts out their APK directly on the website. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
