<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>email on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/email/</link>
    <description>Recent content in email on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/email/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Managing Email in Emacs is not for me</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/mu4e-not-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>22220-05-05</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/mu4e-not-for-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had &lt;a href=&#34;https://irreal.org/blog/?p=8004&#34;&gt;irreal&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/bfsck6/mu4e%5Ffor%5Fdummies/&#34;&gt;mu4e for dummies&lt;/a&gt; on my todo list for a week before I decided to give it up. At first, I thought it was because setting the time and following through the guide was too much of a &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; in my head to tackle, so I broke it down. Then, as I looked at the individual components, I realized it&amp;rsquo;s more complicated then technicalities alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Org-mode has resolved an old problem for me I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I have. Or, more precisely, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know it was a problem because it was too big to grasp. It was the issue of identities and online accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emails are a good way to explain this issue. I currently have four active email accounts: my main Gmail one which is used for professional needs, financials, keeping in touch with family, etc. Then I have another Gmail account, which in the past was more specific for other endeavors such as creative writing and close friends. This became a more personal account which is now associated with my calendar. A third active account is my work email, in Outlook, which is probably the main account I&amp;rsquo;d like to use within Org-mode. I also have an account with proton mail, which I try to utilize more often with my GitHub and other techy things I do as I try to break away from the Google hold over my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re probably starting to see the issue here, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really have to do with Emacs or mu4e.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t instead to have four active email accounts, but this is how it is. While it&amp;rsquo;s possible that others have no more than two email accounts which might fall into nice buckets of &amp;ldquo;personal&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;work,&amp;rdquo; for me, these buckets happen within Org-mode. This is why it&amp;rsquo;s such a critical part of my organization. Life is chaos. My job bleeds into my personal life. My technological passions bleed into work. I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; the barrier between emails and calendar for my Org-agenda, which contains &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; I want to do. Once I decide to put something on my agenda, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter anymore where it came from. What matters is that it gets done. That&amp;rsquo;s all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
