<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on The Art of Not Asking Why</title>
    <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on The Art of Not Asking Why</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshrollinswrites.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My XCFE Experiment Works Out</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/2020-09-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/2020-09-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;KDE&amp;rsquo;s Plasma desktop environment has been my go-to on whatever Linux distro I use: Xubuntu, openSUSE, Manjaro, and now Debian. As I keep favoring terminal and Emacs over GUI, Plasma desktop is becoming more of a habit than necessity. I decided to dump KDE altogether and give XCFE another try with a new laptop build. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I have to say after a couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open any &amp;ldquo;Linux porn&amp;rdquo; (hey, I didn&amp;rsquo;t come up with the concept) reddit or hashtag on twitter, and you&amp;rsquo;ll realize two things: all the cool kids use KDE, and all the cool kids try to make their Linux laptop look as close to a Mac as possible. I&amp;rsquo;m more of a grumpy IT guy than a cool kid, so I never bought into this camp to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I got Debian working on an XPS 13 I had laying around&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, It only took a day with KDE to have me go &amp;ldquo;Oh yeah, I wanted to try XCFE&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; and dump the whole thing. These were my main grudges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KDE Wallet, a tool that&amp;rsquo;s supposed to help with credentials, was the only way to save my WiFi password. When disabled, I had to re-type my wifi password every time I reactivated the laptop (from hibernation as well). There are different tips online, like deactivation wallet (fails) or give all users permissions to the WiFi in the adapter&amp;rsquo;s GUI setting (also fails). I just hate that no one asked me if and how I want to save my passwords, this feels too much like a Microsoft trick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t need KDE Wallet, I use KeepPassXC. But you know what else I don&amp;rsquo;t need? KMail, Akregator, Konversation, KTorrent, Konqueror, Kontact,  and the list goes on. Some of these apps are easy to remove, some&amp;hellip; not so much. But why do I need to uninstall anything? I understand these are good apps, I understand they are helpful and give you that &amp;ldquo;streamline fluid experience&amp;rdquo; or whatever sexy words you want to use, I don&amp;rsquo;t care. No thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is definitely a pet-peeve: time format. KDE&amp;rsquo;s time management system is coded with Qt&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; which doesn&amp;rsquo;t follow the standard time flags you&amp;rsquo;d use elsewhere. I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in the US for most of my life at this point, but I&amp;rsquo;ll never get used to the ridiculous time recording system here. I record dates in a yyyy-mm-dd format, and I use a 24-hours digital clock. It makes sense, It always has, and it always will. The fact that I can&amp;rsquo;t change that simple thing and have a different time format while keeping my locale inside the US is driving me crazy. The only way to (kind of) fix this is to dive deep into KDE&amp;rsquo;s individual settings for the lock screen, then the splash screen, and then into the different widgets, and change them all. Because this is the locale, it can mess things up for apt and other installations, so I just learned to live with a thorn at my side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With XCFE there&amp;rsquo;s barely any software I don&amp;rsquo;t need. I still need to uninstall the Libre Office suite, but that&amp;rsquo;s about it. The wifi works without me needing to enter the passphrase every single time, and time is showing in a sane manner by default. I already have a 24 hour clock with a yyyy-mm-dd date &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a week number (my preferred time unit to measure projects and progress) on my top panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lower panel is where you&amp;rsquo;ll find the only feature I happily &amp;ldquo;stole&amp;rdquo; from macOS: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ricotz/plank&#34;&gt;Plank&lt;/a&gt;, which imitates macOS&amp;rsquo;s genie-affect when hovering over the app icons at the lower panel, with active apps having a bright dot under them. I find that it makes more sense to use Plank on a small screen, where the otherwise normal panel will make the icons to small to see clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XCFE comes with options that still allow me to customize its appearance the way I want it to be. Right now I have a dark central theme with my window manager that does away with XCFE outdated original version at the top right, a half-transparent panel at the top that gives only minimal information, and even a little owl icon for the launcher, just for kicks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/2020-09-23.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;


&lt;figcaption&gt;My XCFE environemnt&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everything is perfect of course, and I still need to implement a few tweaks. Some of the system icons, for example, cannot be replaced by the themes I downloaded and look even more out of place now next to the modern looking ones. KDE had a pretty simple way to have the Caps Lock key work as control, which is one of the first thing I do on any machine I use Emacs on, but it&amp;rsquo;s not as easy on XCFE. The language indicator at the panel doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work, or not work right, and I can&amp;rsquo;t use it to switch languages (keyboard shortcut works though). These are things I will need too look into to fix or get used to, but overall I think XCFE looks fine on the laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy. Debian doesn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;like&amp;rdquo; proprietary firmware, like the kind that is needed for the XPS&amp;rsquo;s NIC, which means you don&amp;rsquo;t get wifi out of the box, you have to work for it. There was another issue with grub getting lost somewhere in the boot partitions which required re-installation from a live USB, two things that would probably discourage users from using Debian and run back to Ubuntu. Most users who choose Debian though are slow and patient folks who enjoy learning how things work and spend time on IRC channels, which ended up working in my favor. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not an expert on this, but I looked into changing the lock screen and login time formats and it requires tweaking configuration files deep inside KDE&amp;rsquo;s folders. This never worked fully: I was able to get the lock screen time or the logon screen time corrected, but never both. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Linux on VM</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200522/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200522/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the majority of work happening from home, I decided to go back to Windows. I was stubborn at start, and continue to host a Windows VM inside Linux, but eventually I acknowledged that I&amp;rsquo;ll a smoother workflow the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, Linux has always been good in vmware&amp;rsquo;s virtual machine. At work, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with my SUSE VM for three years to have org-mode next to me. In a VM, the setup process always seems to be smoother than native. A VM also offers snapshots (this is a feature that comes with the non-free workstation option, but can be done indirectly on the free version by simply saving a copy of the VM files)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before we go further, how could I ignore my &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/too-many-notifications/&#34;&gt;strong feelings&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191208/&#34;&gt;against Windows&lt;/a&gt;? The short answer is that I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I still dislike all the things I mentioned in Windows. Its still has a pushy, buggy, and undependable update procedure. It still keeps throwing at me a bunch of &amp;ldquo;click me!&amp;rdquo; notifications that often draw float on top of the system tray and block it&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fix the updates, I spent an afternoon going through the different &lt;a href=&#34;https://seowsource.com/disable-automatic-updates-using-group-policy-windows-10/&#34;&gt;group policies&lt;/a&gt; and disabling what I could to prevent Windows from messing up my computer without warning. For the notifications, I disabled whatever auto-start applications I could and uninstalled a bunch of junk. I spend my productive time (like writing this post) on the right virtual-desktop full screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VMware is one of Windows&#39; blessings&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I set up a fresh installation of pure Debian with KDE, something I wanted to try before because of Debian&amp;rsquo;s stability. Instead of chasing the bleed edge distros I built Emacs and Hugo to get the latest versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some more things my VM offers me I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get from running Linux nativity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping my IP address on the host while using VPN on the guest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mounting SMBs for windows managed and shared NTSF drives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bitlocker &amp;amp; Powershell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AAA Games that won&amp;rsquo;t run on Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work essentials: VPN, Remote support software, RDP, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know that 90% of the things I listed can be made to work with Linux or have a replacement. I could have another VM inside Linux for VPN, for example, or I could try Lutris and Wine (not to mention Steam is running excellent on Linux) for gaming. But it usually requires extra tweaking, and in the end you end up having to contaminate your productivity environment with games and Chromium, which only work to 80%-90% of their potential anyway. I know because that&amp;rsquo;s what kept happening to me. I wanted to use Firefox, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to bring all my work-related links from Chrome and my Google profile, so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t access those without restarting. I also had to restart every time I wanted to play &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom%5FClancy%27s%5FThe%5FDivision%5F2&#34;&gt;Division 2&lt;/a&gt; with my co-workers. This, in turn, was cutting me off from my other friends on Signal and assessing my org-agenda. In the past, I used a laptop and &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching-to-manjaro/&#34;&gt;a KVM switch&lt;/a&gt;, but the laptop doesn&amp;rsquo;t have nearly as much power for ffmpeg tasks and certain things like my gaming keyboard where problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for work, it takes place on a Windows 10 machine which requires a &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; RDP client, Bitlocker, and other applications that run only on Windows. Yes, there are workarounds, but these involved more questions than I care to answer. I don&amp;rsquo;t like nor need extra attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I work at home now, I have my Windows VM roughly occupying a third of my ultra-wide screen, with my work-related websites or remoted-machine to the right. Additional office software that is needed for work is running directly on Windows, next to games and other distractions, where it belongs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will things stay this way? Who knows. Knowing how I am, I&amp;rsquo;ll get bored 3 months down the line and switch back to some new distro. But that&amp;rsquo;s how I roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When placed at the bottom, the Windows taskbar has more annoyances. I have it set on auto-hide, but when a program requires my attention, it will not go away and often block an important part of the screen. Another issue is confusion between the VM&amp;rsquo;s Linux taskbar and Windows, on top of each other. To fix this, I find that it&amp;rsquo;s better to move the Taskbar out of the way to the right edge of the screen. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VMware has Fusion for Mac and a Linux version as well. I only have limited experience on an underpowered Mac, where Fusion is impossibly slow, and its Linux version leaves much to be desired, so on Linux I dumped it in favor of Virtuabox. It seems to operate best on Windows. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mounting an SMB Share on Linux</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200518/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200518/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mounting SMB shares to Linux machines (or VMs) is an important skill for anyone using Linux. It can be quite confusing, especially for newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide assumes that you have two machines, Windows and Linux, on the same network and same subnet. It also assumes you&amp;rsquo;ve already shared the SMB folder with the right security properties: if you need help with this, &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/4092694/windows-10-file-sharing-over-a-network&#34;&gt;look here&lt;/a&gt; for starters or find other helpful articles like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techbout.com/share-files-folders-windows-10-44386/&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me start by throwing the &lt;em&gt;mount&lt;/em&gt; command at you and then explain what it does. Here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nil&#34; data-lang=&#34;nil&#34;&gt;sudo mount -t cifs -o user=[your Windows user] //[path/to/smb/mountpoint/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We start with &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; because mounting requires root permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mount&lt;/code&gt; is the command to mount a drive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-t&lt;/code&gt; to tell mount that next we&amp;rsquo;re specifying a &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt; of filesystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cifs&lt;/code&gt; is our filesystem&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-o&lt;/code&gt; to tell mount that next we&amp;rsquo;re specifying an &lt;em&gt;option&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;user&lt;/code&gt; is our option, the user is our Windows system user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;next we specify the smb host and the path to the folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;last, the mounting point, the folder on Linux where we&amp;rsquo;ll be viewing the files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nil&#34; data-lang=&#34;nil&#34;&gt;sudo mount -t cifs -o user=seriousam //192.169.1.12 /media/sserious/space
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notice the two things highlighted above: the Windows user (seriousam in our case), which we can find out simply by going to &lt;code&gt;C:\User&lt;/code&gt; in Windows, and the host, which is identified by its private IP address. Depending on how you have your Linux machine set up, I find that it&amp;rsquo;s safer to use an IP address (and use your router&amp;rsquo;s DHCP settings to always give your machines the same IP address so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t change) than the using the machine&amp;rsquo;s host name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mounting this way comes with two annoyances. First, because you have to mount as root (using sudo), only root will have read/write permissions to the folder. You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to download files and save them to the SMB folder without sudo-ing, for example. Second, you will have to mount the share each time you log in and enter the password for your Windows user (the mount command has an &amp;ldquo;password&amp;rdquo; option, so you could type it as part of the mount syntax if you&amp;rsquo;d like).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The better and more acceptable solution is to mount your SMBs in your &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fstab&#34;&gt;fstab&lt;/a&gt;. This is where Linux goes to find out what hard drives and partitions you got going among other things (like SMBs) and how to mount them. It might look scary, and for a good reason: mess up your main filesystem SSD, and Linux won&amp;rsquo;t know where to boot from&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To edit fstab you&amp;rsquo;ll need sudo like all things that are system-wide and are not in your user folder: &lt;code&gt;emacs /etc/fstab&lt;/code&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (or use nano, or VIM, or what have you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fstab starts with a nice commentary about how to get your UUIDs, which is very important if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to mount a physical disk. the first line of code specifies your main Linux file system&amp;rsquo;s UUID and then under it most likely your swap partition. Remember I told you how you can fail to boot if you mess with your fstab? Stay away from these lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start a new line under the last with a comment that will help you figure out what you were doing in the future, and then specify the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nil&#34; data-lang=&#34;nil&#34;&gt;//[host ip address/share-folder] [/path/to/mount/point] cifs credentials=/home/sserious/.smbcredentials,uid=1000,gid=1000 0 2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;OK. This looks a bit like the mount command, but what&amp;rsquo;s with all the extra stuff?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//host ip address/share-folder&lt;/code&gt; this we already know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/path/to/mount/point&lt;/code&gt; this we also already know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cifs&lt;/code&gt; the filesystem. Notice how we don&amp;rsquo;t specify a &lt;code&gt;-t&lt;/code&gt; for type here, because this part belongs to the mount command which is different than fstab. Take a look (don&amp;rsquo;t touch!) at the Linux disks about: probably ext4 and swap, which might look familiar back from when you installed Linux and defined your partitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;credentials=/home/sserious/.smbcredentials&lt;/code&gt; uh oh. What&amp;rsquo;s this? fstab needs credentials to mount the share, this we know from the mount command. Since we want fstab to have everything it needs and won&amp;rsquo;t stop us during boot about some lack of access to SMB, we want to automate this process. In this particular case, the credentials are written in a file, .smbcredentials&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I will specify what goes in it below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;uid=1000,gid=1000&lt;/code&gt; Remember how we had the problem that the SMB share was mounted by root, which meant no other users can save unto it? This line sets permissions to your &amp;ldquo;regular&amp;rdquo; user which most likely has user id of 1000 and group id of 1000. Run &lt;code&gt;id -u&lt;/code&gt; to get your user id and &lt;code&gt;id -g&lt;/code&gt; to get your group id.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;0 2&lt;/code&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m still not 100% clear on these. The first number, which can be 0 or 1, is for dump, the second is for fsck, which can be set to 0, 1, or 2. Dump is a way Linux backs up file, or used to back up files. It is not really used anymore (you&amp;rsquo;ll noticed your main filesystem has a 0 as well) and fsck is the order which Linux will check the disks. Your filesystem has to be 1 (and it is by default) and everything else can be 2. We actually don&amp;rsquo;t really need it for SMB because the disk is located somewhere else, it&amp;rsquo;s a matter of logging in, not checking the files, so we could put 0 there also so it won&amp;rsquo;t be checked at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The .smbcredentials from step 4 looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nil&#34; data-lang=&#34;nil&#34;&gt;username=seriousam
password=password123
domain=.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. You now have all you need to mount the SMB share. Make sure you save fstab, restart, and see if you have access to your SMB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simple and short explanation is that CIFS is basically SMB. But this is not exactly true. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Server%5FMessage%5FBlock#SMB%5F/%5FCIFS%5F/%5FSMB1&#34;&gt;CIFS is a blend of SMB&lt;/a&gt;. SMB improved with the years, and today we&amp;rsquo;re beyond SMB 3.0 which is developed by Microsoft for Windows, while Linux keeps CIFS which was &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; improved with the years and the kernel, so it is, in a way, a blend of modern SMB of its own and not the original CIFS from the 80s. Confused? Me too. I&amp;rsquo;m sure someone who knows more about this could comment and explain. For now, for practicality&amp;rsquo;s sake, we can pretend SMB = CIFS. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution to this, by the way, is to boot up with a live-USB just like you do when you first install Linux, mount the hard drive of the Linux partition you messed up, find the fstab, and fix it &amp;ndash; not that I know anything about messing it up! No sir&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t I just say we need sudo? Why yes. In Emacs you do that by using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/tramp/#Using-su%5F002c-sudo-and-sg&#34;&gt;TRAMP&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;giving out a user name and password in plaintext in a file sounds like a terrible idea. However, since you encrypt your entire hard drive (which you better do) or your VM, the assumption is that if someone went around your hard drive encryption and found your user namhe and password to log into Linux, you&amp;rsquo;re f-ed anyway. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Software</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200428/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200428/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What do Emacs, SSH, FTP, IRC and ffmpeg have in common?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; programs&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that stood the test of time and are still in active usage today. Yes, ffmpeg is maybe not as &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; as Emacs, with its base back in the 1970, and you could argue IRC is barely used next to the giants of social media today, but that doesn’t mean they&amp;rsquo;re not usable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, not only usable, but often better off than modern software that gravitates more and more toward the cloud. My argument here is not that these old tools should replace the existing popular gaints of today and tomororw. Actually, the fact that they &lt;em&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt;, the fact that they are &amp;ldquo;frozen&amp;rdquo; in time and only work for geeks, is a big part of the benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet%5FRelay%5FChat&#34;&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, or internet relay chat. Using IRC requires some know-how of commands like &lt;code&gt;/join&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;/nick&lt;/code&gt; and even &lt;code&gt;/whois&lt;/code&gt; that today&amp;rsquo;s users would know nothing about. Modern application such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.com/help/articles/201259356-Use-built-in-slash-commands&#34;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; and the like have similar commands, but these are artificial like plastic plants: a head nod to the past with often the same functionality a mouse click can achieve in GUI. Most users without technical background won&amp;rsquo;t even know these. IRC does not have a CEO behind it; it does not have a single software which is at the mercy of patches and version numbers; it does not have to abide to the whims of its shareholders and change its TOS every couple of months to another confusing legal document no one reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could pick up a Linux administration book from 2007, and most of it will still be true today. Administrators, or those who think like admins, tend to prefer the proven and stable, not the new-and-flashy. The level of granular control, the options, the out-of-the box availability, the lack of storage space that is required, and of course the no payment associated, add to the stability and familiarity to a package that is hard to defeat. I could use 3 different Linux distros, a Mac and a Windows PC, and I will still trust ffmpeg to work on my video compression and editing more than I would any Adobe product. It&amp;rsquo;s just that there are far better solutions that I found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could argue it&amp;rsquo;s all a matter of taste, and I&amp;rsquo;d say sure, everything is. I find comfort in the terminal, in typing in commands which show me what I&amp;rsquo;m about to do, and how. I know that I could type in the same command 5 years from now, even 50, and expect the same thing to happen - if the machine these programs reside in is alive. In turn, this attitude pushes me to learn more of how things work. At first, a regular user might not understand why I spend 2 hours learning how to script something that takes them 3 clicks to accomplish; but later, when the GUI clicking needs to be repeated for 50 or a 100 items, or when they need a new setup which comes with a new workflow, they&amp;rsquo;d understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;: Technically, IRC, ssh and ftp are procols, not software; but the idea I&amp;rsquo;m driving at is age, stability and usage. ffmpeg is a collection of software and Emacs &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a software (in a way, perhaps a collection of packages in itself as well), and the same point can be applied to both of these as well. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Tools for the job: Duplicati</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200212/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200212/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve kept postponing since &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191208/&#34;&gt;switching to Linux on my desktop&lt;/a&gt; has been my backup system. I wrote a script on my raspberry pi to create an encrypted tar achieves of my org files twice a day transfer them over to Hedwig (my desktop), which will then find their way into an online backup provider. Now that I switched to Linux, that system stopped working, and I&amp;rsquo;ve kept postponing the critical need for an online backup too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a happy &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.backblaze.com/&#34;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; customer for about half a year, and I used their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.backblaze.com/cloud-backup.html&#34;&gt;full computer backup plan&lt;/a&gt; on Windows for a flat fee of $60 a year. With Linux though, this plan was no longer an option. It seemed Backblaze was telling me &amp;ldquo;hey man, now that you&amp;rsquo;re using Linux full time, it&amp;rsquo;s time to wear the big boy&amp;rsquo;s hat and stop using our training wheels. Get serious, or go back to Windows.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backblaze&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/cloud-storage.html&#34;&gt;B2 Backup&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most affordable (if not &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; most affordable) deals I&amp;rsquo;ve found. I had to create a script that would most likely run with &lt;a href=&#34;http://duplicity.nongnu.org/&#34;&gt;Duplicity&lt;/a&gt;, a trusted Linux tool that&amp;rsquo;s been around for a while. After a massive project at work finally ended, I had the time to sit down and try to make it work. I started running into issues though: it seemed like authentication with B2 was rejected due to some known issue, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find too much information about fixing it. What I did found though, as I was looking through various help documentations, is a lesser-known FOSS tool: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duplicati.com/&#34;&gt;Duplicati&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can tell by the game of words here that Duplicity and Duplicati are related: &amp;ldquo;The Duplicati project was inspired by Duplicity and had similar functionality until 2008,&amp;rdquo; its team says in the manual, and the philosophy is the same: a free encryption-supported tool for backups. It&amp;rsquo;s not directly available in official depositories (maybe in rolling releases?) due to its beta status, but it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duplicati.com/download&#34;&gt;easy enough to download for Debian-based distros&lt;/a&gt; (this is another example of why &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200108/&#34;&gt;switching to Kubuntu&lt;/a&gt; was a good idea for me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duplicity&amp;rsquo;s GUI is easy enough to understand, almost to the point that their &lt;a href=&#34;https://duplicati.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;&gt;manual&lt;/a&gt; or excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duplicati.com/articles/Getting-Started/&#34;&gt;getting started guide&lt;/a&gt; are not needed. As it turns out, connection settings for Backblaze&amp;rsquo;s B2 backups come built-in, as well as many other options like Amazon&amp;rsquo;s S3 or box.com. As a matter of fact, the GUI was so simple and intuitive I quickly created different backups for that required different intervals:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/20200212_1.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these created, I was looking a my backups differently. No longer one large archive of all my system files, photos, media and org files, but a separate, &lt;em&gt;purposeful&lt;/em&gt; and specific jobs for different kind of needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200201/&#34;&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt; do not need to be backed-up every day. That&amp;rsquo;s because I take new photos perhaps once a week (sometimes less unfortunately). My org files are the opposite case: I work with them daily both at work and at home, and the differences are large enough for two daily backups: midday while I&amp;rsquo;m at work, making progress on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200123/&#34;&gt;various projects&lt;/a&gt;, and one late at night, after I&amp;rsquo;ve recorded my day in the journal and additional events on the agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duplicati also comes with &lt;a href=&#34;https://duplicati.readthedocs.io/en/latest/04-using-duplicati-from-the-command-line/&#34;&gt;command-line options&lt;/a&gt; which can be used to automate similar process on different machines (I can upload my photos from my desktop, and then duplicate the process for a similar backup on my raspberry pi, for example) or to save in case you need it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s too early to tell, but Duplicati&#39; approach to backups with its ability to work with b2 out of the box is making the long-trusted &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bit-team/backintime&#34;&gt;back-in-time&lt;/a&gt; obsolete: there&amp;rsquo;s no need to backup to my external with one program and upload to b2 with another; duplicati is perfectly fine backing up what I need to my external as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backblaze is an excellent service/tool in itself. For &amp;ldquo;regular&amp;rdquo; home users, they have a simple desktop tool (Mac or Windows) that backs up everything important on the computer (main hard drive and system files) by default, but easy enough to work with if you want to be more granular about your approach, including password-protected encryption. They are aggressively affordable, even more so than Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Glacier. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Kubuntu over openSuSE</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200108/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20200108/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191208/&#34;&gt;After giving openSuSE a try&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to switch to Kubuntu. So far it&amp;rsquo;s been a month or so since the switch, and everything I want works to the point that I havne&amp;rsquo;t booted into Windows once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran into several issues with openSuSE and finally decided to call it quits when Company of Heroes 2, one of the few games I play, refused to work. When I contacted Linux support for it, the answer I got was along the lines &amp;ldquo;sorry, we don&amp;rsquo;t support this version of Linux.&amp;rdquo; My new Desktop Linux setup is not geared toward hardcore gaming is it was first intended when I built it, but I still want to spend some time gaming here and there. There were other issues, of course, mostly the need to download a specifically tailored software for something I needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Kubuntu installed, I looked into installing windows on a VM. I ended up choosing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads&#34;&gt;Oracle&amp;rsquo;s Virtual Box&lt;/a&gt; for its better integration with the Linux Kernel (latest version) and indeed, it runs pretty well. Windows now is in a confined frame used for occasional downloads and remoting to computers at work - this completely satisfies any need I need out of Windows at this point. After a bit of a hardware upgrade which hopefully will happen soon, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even need to turn off the VM when I&amp;rsquo;m done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VM caused several &amp;ldquo;hijacking&amp;rdquo; issues of my keyboard and mouse, so I disconnected my &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching-to-manjaro/&#34;&gt;KVM swtich&lt;/a&gt; and stored it away. Having a powerful desktop means my laptop is no longer in use unless I travel or need a backup. It still runs Manjaro and I think I will keep it this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like my Linux setup is mostly complete at this point. My desktop (&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191208/&#34;&gt;which I call Hedwig&lt;/a&gt;) is used for writing or productivity, photography and gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Long Goodbye to Windows</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191208/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/20191208/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The idea of switching &amp;ldquo;Completely&amp;rdquo; Linux has been in my head since I wrote
about &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/too-many-notifications/&#34;&gt;having too many notifications&lt;/a&gt; thrown at me whenever I log into Windows&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait. Isn&amp;rsquo;t this entire blog written from Linux? Haven&amp;rsquo;t I already switched to work from Linux? Almost 100% of the posts here concern Emacs, org-mode and Linux. &amp;ldquo;What do you mean&amp;rdquo;, you&amp;rsquo;d ask me, &amp;ldquo;switch completely? Haven&amp;rsquo;t you already?&amp;rdquo; Yes. Kind of. Not really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me back off a second, and tell you about Hedwig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hedwig, for those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know, is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magical%5Fcreatures%5Fin%5FHarry%5FPotter#Hedwig&#34;&gt;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo;s owl&lt;/a&gt;. In the movie series, it is a large snowy owl that delivers Harry his mail. It is an obedient, yet confused owl. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a mess, but you learn to like its character and weirdness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/ox-hugo/snow_owl.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;above: a snowy owl, straight from the books&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My electronic devices (phone, laptop, and desktop) are usually named after the owls from Harry Potter. The Raspberry Pi which syncs all my org-mode files is called Hogwarts; the desktop is Hedwig, the phone is &lt;a href=&#34;https://harrypotter.fandom.com/wiki/Pigwidgeon&#34;&gt;Pigwidgeon (pig)&lt;/a&gt;, the laptop is &lt;a href=&#34;https://harrypotter.fandom.com/wiki/Hermes&#34;&gt;Hermes&lt;/a&gt;. I am not sure when I came up with this naming scheme, but my liking to owls and Harry Potter clicked some time ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; Hedwig, my Desktop is a large (full tower, soon to be full ATX) machine. It is somewhat &amp;ldquo;confused&amp;rdquo; about certain things, like the time (I replaced a CMOS battery a couple of times), the state of Windows updates (aren&amp;rsquo;t we all), and in general, its identity. Hedwig&amp;rsquo;s been through Windows, Linux (various distros), and even a full Hackintosh at one point. It&amp;rsquo;s the first computer I built completely from ordered parts, the case, motherboard, PSU, CPU, GPU (all the Us), optical and hard drives. This happened about 6 years ago, before I switched careers to IT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of December, Hedwig is again a duel-boot machine: Windows and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenSUSE&#34;&gt;openSUSE&lt;/a&gt; Linux. I decided to switch to openSUSE from Manjaro (which I use on my laptop) because I&amp;rsquo;ve been using openSUSE at work on my VM and it has been rock-solid; I also grown to like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YaST&#34;&gt;YaST&lt;/a&gt; which helps when I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how to change a setting from the command line. The idea is to eventually throw Windows out completely, and interact with it only in a VM on a full Linux machine. This is something I tried to tackle in the past but failed to do in the days before Emacs and Steam on Linux. Now, with my few favorite games available through Steam&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and Emacs leaving Windows and Office tools in the dust when it comes to file manipulations and writing, I think I will stay committed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I am writing these lines on my laptop. Hedwig&amp;rsquo;s fresh Hugo installation, which I use for this blog, is not working yet. This is just one example of many: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jonls/redshift/releases&#34;&gt;Redshift&lt;/a&gt;, Linux&amp;rsquo;s trusted version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://justgetflux.com/&#34;&gt;f.lux&lt;/a&gt; (or nightshift, if you speak Apple), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.veracrypt.fr/en/Home.html&#34;&gt;veracrypt&lt;/a&gt;, which is a cross-platform encryption solution I use daily, and various codecs required to watch videos and compress videos&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with ffmpeg all require special configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve grown accustomed to these kinds of workarounds (Manjaro had it&amp;rsquo;s own) on Linux. As much as I love the productivity and stability it brings with it, configuring a machine to work in Linux the way I want it to is never a quick process. In contrast, when I had to restore Hedwig to Windows in the past, all it took was signing into my Microsoft account; withing a minute, all my configurations including the wallpaper was in place. But that&amp;rsquo;s the price you pay for having Microsoft (or Google, or Apple) having a probe up your behind and knowing everything you do. This eerie feeling of &amp;ldquo;we know what&amp;rsquo;s good for you&amp;rdquo; is built into every OS, and exists outside of the technology word alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything fits into nice neat boxes, and so do you, so shut up and move along, I feel they tell me. Even though I find that I have less and less patience for folks who invents &amp;ldquo;new ways&amp;rdquo; and think &amp;ldquo;originally&amp;rdquo; these days, I also have less patience toward those who tell &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; to stick to the common ways of doing things. If we are all special none of us is unique, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I find that overall there&amp;rsquo;s little difference in my workflow from Manjaro in openSUSE. Most of my more per-machine tweaks happen in KDE, my preferred desktop environment, and Emacs&amp;rsquo;s file paths which I still can&amp;rsquo;t get to be the same when encrypting (would it kill someone to have the same mounting point for veracrypt in each distro?) Overall, I hope to stick to one distro so I can simply install from a pre-configured backup whenever I need to move to a new computer or a new VM. Using one (or two, one for work and one for home) init files for Emacs would also be great instead of having 5 slightly-different versions floating around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But. While this sounds ideal, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;ll ever happen. That&amp;rsquo;s because I find that I &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; the little differences in how each machine looks and feels. A small XPS running Tumbleweed, openSUSE&amp;rsquo;s rolling release, with white-on-black theme, neon-colored panel with Late and a top panel for system notifications to imitate a Mac like all the cool kids fits, while Hedwig is far more &amp;ldquo;responsible&amp;rdquo; with SUSE&amp;rsquo;s Leap and a traditional black-on-white theme. I need at least a bit of personality on each machine. That&amp;rsquo;s the bit the creative non-conforming dude inside the IT guy in me. Or perhaps I&amp;rsquo;m just nuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in case you&amp;rsquo;re interested, these four games are currently &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YaST&#34;&gt;Cities Skylines&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/231430/Company%5Fof%5FHeroes%5F2/&#34;&gt;Company of Heroes 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/search/?term=oxygen+not+inc&#34;&gt;Oxygen not Included&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/262060/Darkest%5FDungeon/&#34;&gt;Darkest Dungeon&lt;/a&gt;. Over time (and age, I suppose) I discovered I&amp;rsquo;m less interested in FPSs and more interested in detailed-oriented games. I all-heatedly recommend you take a good long look at Oxygen not Included, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this blog regularly - it&amp;rsquo;s perfect for problem-solvers who are looking to sync into a fun, cute, but very thought-provoking kind of game. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/ffmpeg/comments/e79qv8/maxium%5Fmp4%5Fcompression%5Fonly%5Fin%5Fopensuse/&#34;&gt;I found out&lt;/a&gt;, openSUSE doesn&amp;rsquo;t come with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.videolan.org/developers/x264.html&#34;&gt;libx264&lt;/a&gt;, a codec used to compress videos into mp4 formats. It is so common-place in other distros and programs many (me included) don&amp;rsquo;t even know it exists and does a fantastic job. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Many Notifications</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/too-many-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/too-many-notifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fan noise that came from my Windows machine finally got on my nerves, so I turned off my PC. I turned it on the next day, not thinking much about anything, my coffee at hand. As soon as I logged in I was greeted with windows opening on me notifying me on updates, of new games sales, of emails&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;click me! No! Click me!&amp;rdquo; Yeeeesh. I put my coffee down and shut down my Windows PC off again. How did I get to this point again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows allows all kinds of apps to be launched at login (autostart) and throw notifications at you without asking for permission. Because my Windows PC is used for gaming, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epic%5FGames%5FStore&#34;&gt;Epic store&lt;/a&gt; announces free new games, and Steam&amp;rsquo;s client keeps updating every few days for whatever reason. NVIDIA&amp;rsquo;s updated includes bloatware, wrapping new driver updates with news bulletins I care very little of. Windows itself informs me every time an update is waiting for me to restart, which I do as soon as possible because I don&amp;rsquo;t trust the system to wait for me as it claims to do: if it decides it&amp;rsquo;s time to update then it&amp;rsquo;s time to update, then it&amp;rsquo;s time to update, and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing I can do about it. Even Chrome browser launches automatically with &lt;a href=&#34;https://emby.media/&#34;&gt;Emby&lt;/a&gt;, and with it all the notifications built into Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not new to this and I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised, yet, somehow, this behavior keeps sneaking up on me bit by bit until it&amp;rsquo;s suddenly too much. While Windows is notorious for this kind of behavior, things in Linuxland are also getting out of hand. In particular, Firefox and &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.kde.org/KDEConnect&#34;&gt;KDE-Connect&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take WhatsApp for example, which I have to use to communicate with 95% of my friends and family&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s open in Firefox, where it&amp;rsquo;s quick and convenient to type messages while my phone is charging, so Firefox informs me of new messages coming in. My phone, connected by KDE-Connect, also sends notifications. And if I ignore these because I&amp;rsquo;m busy, my Fitbit ionic vibrates on my wrist with yet a third attempt to grab my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all seems annoying and unnecessary as I write this, but during the last two weeks, it was vital. My dad was in the hospital undergoing surgery, and my family members across-seas were talking to each other in a chat room. I wanted to be involved, but not to the point where WhatsApp will show on my browser at work since my privacy (and that of my family) is important to me. Because running around a lot is a normal part of my job I don&amp;rsquo;t always sense the phone vibrating in my pocket. The watch was the best option to be notified. The big hoopla is mostly over now, and it&amp;rsquo;s time to tune it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another good example is email. I moved personal emails (family and friends) to Protonmail about a year ago: I wanted to give Google a little bit less info to work with and encrypting communications with important people give me a warm fuzzy feeling. My main money/health/adult-stuff email though is still Gmail, while Outlook has autonomy at the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently use Thunderbird for my Gmail, and I find that the &lt;em&gt;lack&lt;/em&gt; of notifications is potentially a problem: if one of my apps happily subscribed me again automatically, I want PayPal to inform me I was just charged. The occasional newsletter from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bandcamp&#34;&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; is something worth skimming for good new music &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/upgrading-audio-game/&#34;&gt;I re-learned to appreciate&lt;/a&gt;. However, I get no notifications unless Thunderbird is running. This is good because the thought of being notified of &lt;em&gt;every single email&lt;/em&gt; makes me want to puke, but it&amp;rsquo;s all or nothing kind of deal which is not that great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I need to get in there and tailor my notifications to my specific needs, but who has the time to do that &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; keep things under control? I know I don&amp;rsquo;t. I&amp;rsquo;m on the verge of contaminating my peaceful Linux environment with notification and information overload I don&amp;rsquo;t want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution for now seems to be in Gmail. I haven&amp;rsquo;t tweaked my filters and labels there in a long time. It should be easy enough to either tame Gmail what&amp;rsquo;s important or at least create an automatic workflow and then worry only about specific labels - these can translate into folders in Thunderbird, and from there, be notified &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; for that folder. I can see this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least in Linux information overload is &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; choice, not some operating system&amp;rsquo;s default behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In communications apps there&amp;rsquo;s not much of a choice: you use what your friends and family use, and that&amp;rsquo;s it. You can sing the praises of Signal or what-have-you as much as you&amp;rsquo;d like, but you&amp;rsquo;d end up talking to yourself. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do They Use a Mac?</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/why-admins-use-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/why-admins-use-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Macs are evil. Macs are expensive pieces of toy hardware, which is often not up to par with what&amp;rsquo;s offered on the market (my personal biggest annoyances are the keyboards and the touchpad). Everything you do on a Mac you can do on Linux better&amp;hellip; and so on. If that&amp;rsquo;s true, why are so many professionals in IT environments (which are otherwise Windows-based) use Macs? I want to see if my perspective changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, Macs are consistent. Apple provides reliable, top-of-the-line support to keep things more or less the same for people with decade-long workflows. This is impossible to do on Windows. Many Linux distros offer similar long-term consistency (I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenSUSE&#34;&gt;openSUSE&lt;/a&gt;), but support is harder to come by. With Linux, many times you&amp;rsquo;re left scratching your head alone for days, even weeks and months. As a person with limited time, I have learned to appreciate consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macs also tend to be as simple or as complicated as you need them to be. For example, you could use Emacs on a Mac through homebrew or chocolate and &amp;ldquo;complicate&amp;rdquo; your workflow with Emacs to your heart content; on the other hand, if you&amp;rsquo;re fine with &lt;a href=&#34;https://todoist.com/&#34;&gt;Todoist&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus&#34;&gt;Ominifocus&lt;/a&gt;, this is one headache less for you. These apps are a pleasure to use on an iPhone too, which brings me to the next point&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhones, love them or hate them, have been a seamless extension to Macs since 2007. I believe every tech Mac user also has an iPhone unless they specifically need an Android phone for development or something similar. Every app I use on my work iPhone is polished, relatively easy to use, and works as expected. I can&amp;rsquo;t say the same on Android apps, especially in my case where I sometimes use FOSS apps, which don&amp;rsquo;t come from the Google store. There&amp;rsquo;s also a big point against Google their consistency of supporting apps. Once you&amp;rsquo;re in Apple&amp;rsquo;s echo system, switching to anything else is painful and costly productivity speaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s still also the Apple brand. People save up to buy a new computer and it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a Mac, because it&amp;rsquo;s a Mac. It is still widely known to be a good computer (if not the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo;), and it comes bundled with support to match. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard many complaints from Mac users about their devices over the years, but they almost always turn around and buy another one when the time comes. That&amp;rsquo;s because they don&amp;rsquo;t do their research (not necessarily out of laziness) and Macs always come up as the default option. While other brands slowly climb up there (and Apple arguably loses credibility), it will take years before any other brands will enjoy the same reputation as Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux as a personal choice for years, I came to realize the &lt;em&gt;reasons&lt;/em&gt; for this have changed. At start, it was mostly out of sheer curiosity and Microsoft-forced-updates trauma. Every computer I installed Linux on had a different distro and different flavored desktop. As time passed, I started enjoying the consistency and efficiency of running processes through the command line. If I wanted, I could find these two easily within macOS, but there&amp;rsquo;s another form of consistency at place here. I can potentially take any old computer and install Linux on it and have it run exactly the way I&amp;rsquo;m used to, be it next year or 20 years from now. I can&amp;rsquo;t say the same thing about Macs (and definitely never about Windows). As I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward, I believe I will keep preferring Linux machines, and if forced, will feel &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo; on a Mac. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty safe to say though that I&amp;rsquo;ll probably never use Windows again as a personal productivity machine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Updates: June</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/quick-updates-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/quick-updates-june/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though I don&amp;rsquo;t have any means of tracking how many readers I have on this blog, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel a little bit responsible for my audience. This is an attempt to see how a quick &amp;ldquo;here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s up&amp;rdquo; post while the blog is otherwise idle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, a few quick updates about what&amp;rsquo;s coming up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discovered I can use .org files as templates for capture. This opens the possibilities to create highly complex templates, like checklists with several headers, accessible from capture. It took me a year(!) to finally figure out even though it&amp;rsquo;s dead simple. I want to discuss why this took so long, and how Org-manual could use more visual examples. I also want to discuss how I use these checklists at work, and why they&amp;rsquo;re useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of the above, I am also changing my workflow in org-mode, or precisely, how I&amp;rsquo;m using my files. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to scale back from my &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/agenda-multiple-files/&#34;&gt;multi-file approach&lt;/a&gt; and use only two or three major files, and I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of testing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike Elgan writes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.computerworld.com/article/3405559/google-needs-to-pull-itself-together.html&#34;&gt;about Google products that should be merged&lt;/a&gt;, and it made me remember how I used to have the same issues until I switched over to Linux and Emacs. People who use Linux have it better in terms of productivity. I want to discuss why.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Manjaro</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching-to-manjaro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/switching-to-manjaro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux as my daily driver for the last three years. I work with Windows on a daily basis and I support Mac issues all the time, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I will ever go back to using either one for my personal data. As a matter of fact, it&amp;rsquo;s Linux which made an appearance at work: without my VM and Org-mode, I would probably be drowning under hips of emails, meeting invites, support tickets, and the constant in-person walk-ins into our work environment. I throw everything I get at Org-mode to keep on top of the couple of tasks I try to tackle each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was always clear to me that I have things a bit backward. Linux Mint, which I use all the time, is trapped in a VM in a Windows-host which I only use for Games and entertainment (yes, I know you can play games on Linux. Trust me when I tell you I tried, and it&amp;rsquo;s not there yet. Not for me, anyway). I&amp;rsquo;ve had an old &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dell%5FLatitude&#34;&gt;Dell Latitude 6430u&lt;/a&gt; laying around for a while as a backup and for travel. Big and bulky, it had Ubuntu installed, with much to be desired in the battery-power retention department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week ago, due to various issues with Microsoft Windows patching at work, I decided it&amp;rsquo;s time to try and leave Windows behind again and let Linux run free. It took me a while to realize that one of my big setbacks have been that I wanted to keep my work setup. I love my mechanical keyboard and the crisp, ultra-wide screen. I enjoy working at my desk behind a closed door, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/upgrading-audio-game&#34;&gt;enjoying my music&lt;/a&gt;. Once I realized the main setback, the solution came easily: a KVM switch. After quick research, I found this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B078LY741V/ref=ppx%5Fyo%5Fdt%5Fb%5Fasin%5Ftitle%5Fo06%5Fs00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34;&gt;TESmart 4K HDMI KVM Switch USB2.0 Port&lt;/a&gt;. So far, it works wonderfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was setting the laptop up, another unexpected change took place: I gave up on Linux Mint and decided to try Manjaro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say &amp;ldquo;gave up&amp;rdquo; because installing Linux Mint was never easy. For as long as I remember, on desktops and laptops, I always had difficulties booting Mint after install. It would install just fine, but when restarted, I ended up staring at a grub shell and couldn&amp;rsquo;t go further. I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted difference things, starting from switching between Legacy and UEFI boot to using &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/Boot-Repair&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s boot repair tool&lt;/a&gt;, but nothing really worked. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent hours on IRC trying to get help and I grew tired of describing the same process again and again in various forums trying to figure out what went wrong. This is why my laptop had Ubuntu to begin with, instead of Mint which was always my preferred distro. I never liked Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;feel,&amp;rdquo; and that Amazon symbol at the middle of my dock (yes, I know you can turn it off), was sticking out at me like a rusty for-profit nail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to install Linux Mint on my laptop again and ran into the same boot issue. I asked for help on the forums again and told myself I should wait until I get the help I need and solve this issue once and for all. But I&amp;rsquo;ve been hearing good things about Manjaro, and my fingers were itching, so I threw it all to hell and decided to go for it. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first obvious good thing about Manjaro is that it worked without any issue after install, just like Ubuntu. No headaches, no asking for help, no forums, no nothing. The second major good thing, turns out, is that I chose the &lt;a href=&#34;https://manjaro.org/download/kde/&#34;&gt;Plasma KDE version&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mint has always been Cinnamon (which is a version of GNOME) for me. While Mint offers Plasma as well, I never tried it on Mint. I did test Plasma briefly with &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubuntu.org/&#34;&gt;Kubuntu&lt;/a&gt; at one point, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t impressed. Manjaro, on the other hand, seems to be amazing with it. Many of the the things I&amp;rsquo;m quickly learning to love in Manjaro (but not all) are Plasma-related, such as KDE connect (syncs notifications and texts with my phone), &amp;ldquo;hot corners&amp;rdquo; (one of the things I liked about macOS), Yakuake for quick pull-down terminal needs, and in general, the sleek modern design of the dark theme. It just &lt;em&gt;looks /good&lt;/em&gt;. So far, any application that existed on Mint (which is based on Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s repositories) can work on Manjaro through its vast user/community libraries. Oddly enough, because Manjaro does not require additional repositories for additional software to be installed, the overall installation process for &amp;ldquo;Ubuntu/Mint applications&amp;rdquo; is even &lt;em&gt;smoother&lt;/em&gt; than it was on Mint itself. Speaking of software&amp;hellip;  Manjaro has the latest version of almost everything, which means I am now running Emacs 26.2 instead of 25, the version I have on the Mint VM. I have a feeling Google Drive support will become useful for me soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still working on the setup. For one, I need to re-wire everything and hide all the cords from sight. I also want to run an Ethernet cable from the laptop (having a bulky heavy laptop has advantages&amp;hellip;) directly to the router for increased speeds and stable LAN connectivity for my SMB shares on my Windows machine, when I set them up. I also want to purchase another battery from eBay just in case. I&amp;rsquo;ve been running it without a battery connected directly to a power source. Currently, the CPU widget points at less than 25% usage (that is until I fire up Chrome&amp;hellip;) and the laptop&amp;rsquo;s lid is closed, in its &amp;ldquo;docked&amp;rdquo; state on my desk. If I want to go somewhere all I have to do is to attach the battery and disconnect it from the wires, and I have my Linux productivity setup with me ready to go in my backpack. No need for a thin sexy under-powered over-priced device here, we&amp;rsquo;re doing juuuuust fine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hub</title>
      <link>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/raspberry-pi-org-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshrollinswrites.com/help-desk-head-desk/raspberry-pi-org-hub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having a consisted, stable server for my org files has been on my mind for a while. I bought a Raspberry PI (RP) to serve as a file server to be used as a &amp;ldquo;hub&amp;rdquo; that will always be on and host these files. This is a description of the setup of what I&amp;rsquo;ve done to make this work. I hope you&amp;rsquo;d find this useful! Feel free to contact me with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buying-the-raspberry-pi-dot&#34;&gt;Buying the Raspberry Pi.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the setup I describe here, you need the RP itself, a power source, an SD card, a USB case for 2.5 inch HDD, and the HDD itself. You&amp;rsquo;ll also need an Ethernet cord for this setup. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have one, go grab yourself a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/AmazonBasics-RJ45-Cat-6-Ethernet-Patch-Cable-5-Feet-1-5-Meters/dp/B00N2VILDM/ref=lp%5F9938478011%5F1%5F1?s=pc&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1542991619&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;CAT6 cord Amazon Basics&lt;/a&gt; cable, it&amp;rsquo;s always good to have one around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the RP, you better off getting a package similar to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/CanaKit-Raspberry-Complete-Starter-Kit/dp/B01C6Q2GSY/ref=sr%5F1%5Ffkmr0%5F2?s=electronics&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1541986065&amp;amp;sr=1-2-fkmr0&amp;amp;keywords=canakit+raspberry+pi+3+b++sd+card&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;. You could probably get something slightly cheaper by getting all the parts yourself, but not by much. Better to have everything you need at once without worrying about forgetting something. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the above package with the SD card, so I had to wait a couple of days for another order to come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HDD I had laying around already, so I got &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01M08LCXW/ref=oh%5Faui%5Fdetailpage%5Fo00%5Fs00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34;&gt;this case&lt;/a&gt; for it. 8 bucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-the-rp&#34;&gt;Setting up the RP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we&amp;rsquo;re going to set up the SD card to run our RP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we jump in, a note about my setup: I have Linux in a VM inside a Windows host. As it turns out, having Windows an alt-tab away (or in my case, ctrl+alt+left arrow away) can be very useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If switch between Windows programs and Linux commands without mentioning it, that&amp;rsquo;s because this setup comes naturally to me at this point. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working this way (office and home) for almost four years, minusaa half a year of dual-booting with Linux-Mint as my daily OS. There&amp;rsquo;s a whole story here about the switch to Linux and back, but that&amp;rsquo;s for another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK! Enough chatter. Let&amp;rsquo;s get on with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org/downloads/raspbian/&#34;&gt;Raspbian&lt;/a&gt; (zip file).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Format the SD to FAT32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unzip, and write the image to the SD using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/win32diskimager/&#34;&gt;Win32 diskimager&lt;/a&gt; or Underbootin. For me, the first option is better when I deal with SD cards and my USB-SD adapter, YMMV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an empty file (no extension) on the SD root called SSH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last part is important. Creating the file (in windows, just create a new text file, rename to SSH and delete the extension) is what tells our RP to open port 22 for SSH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you insert the SD card and power the RP up. Log into your router to find the RP&amp;rsquo;s IP address.  This is why you need to Ethernet connection for. You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to access the RP with WiFi for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go ahead and SSH into the RP as pi: &lt;code&gt;ssh pi@[RP IP address here]&lt;/code&gt;. your default password is raspberry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in, you want to sudo into  RP config tool: &lt;code&gt;sudo raspi-config&lt;/code&gt;. The setup tool is straightforward enough, but I found that remoting into the pi itself with VNC (coming up) is more convenient, so the only option we really care about now is to turn VNC on:
go to interface options (option 5 in my case, in the middle), and do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save, get out, and then download &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.realvnc.com/en/connect/download/vnc/linux/&#34;&gt;RealVNC&lt;/a&gt;. I downloaded it for Linux because that&amp;rsquo;s what I use to SSH and setup my Pi. It&amp;rsquo;s also where later I will setup Syncthing (coming up), so it made sense. RealVNC is the recommended option for RPs. it&amp;rsquo;s easy to install and run, and supports VNCing with a password, which is what you need for the RP. As a bonus, it automatically creates nice thumbnails of the last logins (IP addresses) which can be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With RealVNC, go ahead and connect to the RP using the same IP address and default password. The Raspbian will jump on you right away telling you need to change your default password and a bunch of other things. and that&amp;rsquo;s all good. Follow these screens, and after updates are downloaded, &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; restart just yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might have noticed you&amp;rsquo;re working in a tiny little screen. Let&amp;rsquo;s change that quickly by going to the preferences (click on the RP icon at the top left), then Raspberry Pi Configurations. Under resolution, choose something that works well for you. for my ultra wide screen, 1920x1080 was good enough to work in. Now you can restart. If you changed your password (you should have!) leave RealVNC on and it will inform you the password is wrong (because you changed it). All good, log in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-note-about-passwords-and-password-generators&#34;&gt;A note about passwords and password generators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use a password manager (my favorite on Linux now is xpass, LastPass is another), I strongly recommend to copy-paste your password in plaintext somewhere first, then copy it to the RP password-change field, and click the eye icon to reveal it. &lt;em&gt;Make sure what you pasted is the same thing you think you pasted&lt;/em&gt;. In my case, I messed this up twice and had to image my SD card all over again. Yes, &lt;a href=&#34;https://howtoraspberrypi.com/recover-password-raspberry-pi/&#34;&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s a technique to reset up the password by booting into the root shell&lt;/a&gt;, but this didn&amp;rsquo;t work for me. And besides, it&amp;rsquo;s annoying and requires to physically connect a screen and keyboard to the RP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because my RP is set up for SSH with a password for now, I made a random 32 character password for it. copy-paste is not a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;encrypting-the-hdd&#34;&gt;Encrypting the HDD&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose to use a separate HDD for a couple of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can take it with me if I need to and mount to another machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have unused HDDs laying around from computer repairs. In my case, the HDD is 500GB, more than enough for text files and occasional pictures I use in Org-mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the HDD dies, I still have a functional RP with the OS on the SD card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The encryption tool of choice for me ended up being LUKS, the same thing that encrypts Linux machines at startup. Actually, my first choice was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.veracrypt.fr/en/Downloads.html&#34;&gt;VeryCrypt&lt;/a&gt;. It comes with a convenient GUI and better options to handle containers. As it turns out, there&amp;rsquo;s no updated version for ARM (which is what the RP is), and I&amp;rsquo;d have to compile from source. Possible, but not worth it for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VNC into your RP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, Install cryptsetup on the RP (apt-get). This is the LUKS suite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figure out the USB-connected drive: &lt;code&gt;sudo fdisk -l&lt;/code&gt;. this will show you where&amp;rsquo;s your hdd in /dev. In my case, it was in /dev/sda (not sda1, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Format with LUKS:  &lt;code&gt;cryptsetup luksFormat /dev/[drive]&lt;/code&gt; the default option was fine for me, but be aware that LUKS comes with many options if you so desire. When formatting, it should ask for a passphrase, so give it one. Then it should start doing its thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When done, verify your drive is encrypted with  &lt;code&gt;cryptsetup luksDump /dev/[drive]&lt;/code&gt;. You should see information about the encryption, along with the first key (LUKS can hold up to eight keys) and its hash. This means we&amp;rsquo;re all good so far.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now, create a mount point for your drive. for me, out of habit of using Mint, that was /media/pimount. So: &lt;code&gt;sudo mkdir /media/pimount&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is where things get a bit hazy since I&amp;rsquo;m writing this from memory. We need to open the encrypted drive with &lt;code&gt;cryptsetup luksOpen /dev/mapper/[drive name] [mounting point name]&lt;/code&gt;. Notice we have &lt;strong&gt;mapper&lt;/strong&gt; in the path after dev now. that&amp;rsquo;s how LUKS work. The encryption is not being done on &lt;em&gt;dev&lt;/em&gt;[drive] itself. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why (I&amp;rsquo;m sure there&amp;rsquo;s some Linux file system reason behind it), so feel free to educate me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now, we need to format the drive with the file system of our choice. In my case, ext4. I believe this can also be done for FAT32 or even NTFS if you want to access your drive from Windows, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested that. To format, you can download Gparted, which is good to have in general. However, this is easy to do with &lt;code&gt;mkfs.ext4 /dev/[name]&lt;/code&gt;. In fact, that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what Gparted would do for you anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mount the freshly formatted drive: &lt;code&gt;mount /dev/mapper/[name] /media/[name]&lt;/code&gt;  If we have &amp;ldquo;show mounted drives&amp;rdquo; option on the desktop in RP, it should show now. As a matter of fact, it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to enable this (right click on the RP desktop).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you start putting stuff on your HDD, it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to restart and practice mounting the drive again (step 6 and 8; you don&amp;rsquo;t need to format again!). Then do it again. The unmount command is umount (no n), or you can simply restart the Pi.  There&amp;rsquo;s a way to automate this using fstab, but messing your fstab could screw up your RP as it happened to me. I figured I never plan on really turning off the thing, so I will just keep doing it manually. Now, if someone happens to just grab your HDD and walk away, it will need to be mounter and decrypted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syncthing-setup&#34;&gt;Syncthing setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syncthing&#34;&gt;Syncthing&lt;/a&gt; is the best solution for all my file-syncing needs. It works without a hitch until you need to change something tiny and meaningless. Then all hell breaks loose. I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why that is, but I learned to accept it as a fact of life at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this RP weekend setup, I had to change my Syncthing setup so that the RP will become the central hub. What happened was a fruitless night of trying to figure out why Syncthing stopped syncing and  an messy Monday at work. It was such a bad setback, in fact, that I decided to create a process dubbed &amp;ldquo;downfall&amp;rdquo; for future cases just like this one when I can&amp;rsquo;t use Org-mode at work. Yes, not having Syncthing basically means I can&amp;rsquo;t use Org. But I digress&amp;hellip; The important lesson here is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t mess with Syncthing. Set it up, make sure it works, and &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t touch it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As intimidating as this sounds, Syncthing actually has a pretty simple setup process. Here&amp;rsquo;s the plan:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://joshrollinswrites.com/hub.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The different colors represent the different folders in syncthing. To me these are personal, work, utilities (this is the only folder that does not have org files), and archive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use four devices, three daily, one (laptop) once in a while. The home VM, which is my main productivity box, gets everything. So does the laptop, it&amp;rsquo;s meant to be used as my home away from home. My work VM (OpenSuse Linux) only contains work org files and the archive. On the phone, I skip media-heavy folders like DnD and some classical music flac files to save space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setup process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Syncthing on RP (apt-get).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose the first device to sync. Add the RP&amp;rsquo;s ID to its Syncthing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wait&lt;/em&gt; for RP to acknowledge the device. Approve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From the connecting device, share the folders you want to sync with the RP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wait&lt;/em&gt; for RP to acknowledge folders. Approve each, choose path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify the sync work by altering the files a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose the second device to sync&amp;hellip; repeat step 3-5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, folders that common to a couple of devices should be added first from one device (as stated above) with the RP, and then add that folder to the &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; device. Device_A &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; RP &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Device_B. This ensures you&amp;rsquo;re sharing the same folder (same folder ID) and not creating duplicates. The reason you&amp;rsquo;re doing it this way and not just sharing from one device to another is because you don&amp;rsquo;t want the other devices to see each other; they should only &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; the RP. The RP is the only device that needs to see all of them. Fewer complications means Syncthing works better and faster. Remember what I said earlier: don&amp;rsquo;t play with it, keep it simple and it will work. Complicate it, and you&amp;rsquo;ll spend hours trying to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for example, if I first sync my home VM and share the &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; folder to the RP, after I&amp;rsquo;m done and verify the sync work, I am connecting the work VM to the RP, wait until it&amp;rsquo;s recognized, and then send the work folder (which is now synced between home VM and RP) &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; the work VM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
